<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mac on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in mac on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up a New M1 Mac for Development</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</guid><description>I recently updated my 2012 Mac Mini with a 2021 M1 Mac Mini and decided to document the first time setup process. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up. What follows is all the steps in written form as a handy reference for you to copy and paste from - or future me. Surprisingly, the installation process was fairly simple now there are versions of software written for Apples new architecture.</description></item><item><title>Recovering Images from SD Cards with PhotoRec</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</guid><description>I had the horrible situation last Sunday following removing a number of pictures using an SD reader from my SD card that when I inserted it in my camera, it registered nothing upon it. My heart sunk, because this card is stuffed full of images of me and my family (along with my 1 year old son growing up) and I was unsure of which ones I’d actually backed up. After perusing the hidden files on the card, all I could discover was the files I’d most recently transferred from the card….</description></item></channel></rss>