<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Films on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/films/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Films on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/films/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Business with Developer APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis/</guid>
      <description>Those of your you who follow me on twitter will might be aware of a single day hack I attempted last week, which takes output from Lovefilm&amp;#8217;s customer history and formats it so it can easily be imported into the lovely Letterboxd. It&amp;#8217;s named Loveletterd and it seemed entirely appropriate to release it on Valentines day.
After hearing that Letterboxd had created a CSV import tool for it&amp;#8217;s community to use and as I&amp;#8217;m a Lovefilm developer, I felt like it would be a great use of my time to get to work on Loveletterd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scientist in an Adventure with Pirates</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</guid>
      <description>This is a talk I did back in May at unifieddiff about my time working as a web developer at Aardman Features. I talk quite a bit about the production process and what we take from staff in order to help them do their jobs properly. I quite enjoyed giving this talk &amp;#8211; more so than those I&amp;#8217;ve given in an academic capacity in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Something I&amp;#8217;ve thought I&amp;#8217;d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I&amp;#8217;ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I&amp;#8217;m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I&amp;#8217;ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I&amp;#8217;ve got the opportunity to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of &amp;#8220;The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain&amp;#8221;, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>