<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:21:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cookiecutter Template for Multiple Python Package Managers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I described how you can use Python and Makefiles to quickly get new projects started. In this post I explore how you can use cookiecutters more advanced Jinja templating techniques to make a cookiecutter that can be used for multiple package managers. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll be extending the existing template to build another that can be used with either Poetry or Pipenv.
Our New Cookiecutter Template As a reminder, Cookiecutter allows us to template project and directory content and structure using Jinja2 logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping Python Projects with Cookiecutter and Makefiles</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</guid>
      <description>When starting a new project, it’s easy to get caught up in the excitement of starting the shiny new thing and forget about some basics. What starts out as a script slowly evolves into an application and before long you’ll find yourself repeating common steps for every project to get it to match personal preferences. If you happen to be working within on a team, you may have many repositories that should have the same setup and inconsistencies between them can quickly lead to large amounts of lost time to get them aligned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
