<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2008/05 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2008/05 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Web Meetup #3</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to remind people that this coming week is the third Cardiff meetup for web types in wales. It&amp;#8217;s in 10 Feet Tall on Church St on Wednesday 4th June from 6.30pm. Featured speakers include Matthew Cashmore (Development Producer for BBC Future Media &amp;#038; Technology, Research and Innovation) and Tim Holmes (Course co-ordinator for the Postgraduate Diploma in Magazine Journalism and the MA International Journalism: Magazine Pathway at Cardiff University&amp;#8217;s School of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnny Lee&#39;s Innovative Uses of Common Technology</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not sure how many visitors have caught this ted talk before, but I&amp;#8217;d thought I&amp;#8217;d post it anyway. Johnny Chung Lee is amazing, turning a $40 wii remote into use an interactive whiteboard or a new way to interact with video games via head tracking. He&amp;#8217;s been at this sort of thing for ages previously putting out a $14 steadycam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare - Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</guid>
      <description>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I&amp;#8217;m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with fairdos and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don&amp;#8217;t appeal to us at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>