<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TechcrunchUK Non-Pantomime Continues</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, according to the free English dictionary there is a couple of definitions other than the traditional UK understanding of the word pantomime. For those international readers who don’t know, a pantomime is a pretty awful example of B-List celebrities acting ability in the UK in which involves them dressing up in bad costumes and acting out a fairy tale or story. In Cardiff, the big panto is Jack and the Giant Beanstalk – where Jack is played by John Barrowman (or Captain Jack from Torchwood and Dr Who).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg gets Video and Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Digg.com is sporting the ability to be able to now rate online video and podcasts. Postcast searching is in limited beta for registered users only.I just spent a while perusing some items of interest, and found a great segment of play! over on google. This just builds on the fact that Mario has the most awesome music ever.The searching of podcasts is dangerously close to an idea I’ve currently working on myself for a while now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything in Moderation</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/everything-in-moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/everything-in-moderation/</guid>
      <description>Apparently coke isn’t that good for you – a few of my friends might like to take heed of that advice. But, you can do some cool things with a lot of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Sethi has Nowhere to Blog?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>It seems, according to Ben Metcalfe, that Sam Sethi has had his typepad account disabled by Six Apart, rendering him unable to post any updates on his recent departure from TechcrunchUK. Loic Le Meur (Executive Vice President of Six Apart and General Manager of Europe, Middle East and Africa) is currently giving no information about the whole scenario upon his own blog.UPDATE: Apparently Sam Sethi’s blog is up and running, though he has to yet confirm this and post his take on the whole scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Sethi is sacked from Techcrunch UK</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</guid>
      <description>Techcrunch UK, Techcrunch’s european sister site has recently had a lot of activiity from some notes which the editor at the time, Sam Sethi made about the recent leweb3 event.This invited some comments from Six Apart’s Loic Le Meur in which he called Sam “an asshole”. Sam subsequently posted another blog about the fact that TechcrunchUK would be setting up its own events and workshops in the forthcoming year. It seems this displeased techcrunch’s Mike Arrington enough to give Sam the boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Fools - Learn to Drive!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools-learn-to-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools-learn-to-drive/</guid>
      <description>It wasn’t that long ago that I posted about coming off of my bike due to a slippery road, but this time was a bit different. Today somebody properly smacked me off of my bike! They were attempting to cut round a light-enabled junction when the lights had gone green in a different direction. As there is a small window of time only 1 or two generally make this turn, but this car decided that it should go even if it wasn’t its turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Threadless rule or not?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</guid>
      <description>Last night I perused a number of articles describing the success of my favourite t-shirt store threadless, the first of which – over at 37Signals reviews in a positive light and the second in a more negative one.Threadless is a t-shirt company with a difference, it’s a 24-7 competition allow you to become the designer. Designs are chosen by the team, and are able to be rated by the community that operates around the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got no hot friends? - Fake Your Space!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/got-no-hot-friends-fake-your-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/got-no-hot-friends-fake-your-space/</guid>
      <description>I heard about fakeyourspace via mashable today, which offers the ability to purchase your own social networking friends to leave messages and comments on communities such as myspace and facebook (the only two web pages I ever see to be open when supervising university labs). In their own words:*“If you are tired of seeing everyone else with the hottest friends and want some hotties of your own, then this is the place for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Demand Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/19/on-demand-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/19/on-demand-access/</guid>
      <description>I don’t really understand microsoft, over the last few days, their live network has been experiencing problems every time I’ve tried to logon to access my email. Who knows what my 8 emails contain which are hidden within live mail, I certainly don’t. You would think that more people would be in uproar about this – I mean what if these were payment requests, final demands or quick response business proposals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Web Applications - London 07</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</guid>
      <description>Registration is open for the Future of Web Apps conference in London 07. I’d love to go, loads of great companies/people talking (good to see Last.fm making an appearance), loads of schmoozing (if thats the appropriate word), but unfortunately absolutely jack to do with my PhD, so no funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zach Braff Makes an Appearance at Threadless</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/zach-braff-makes-an-appearance-at-threadless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/zach-braff-makes-an-appearance-at-threadless/</guid>
      <description>The amazing Zach Braff has made an appearance over at threadless to show off the t-shirt which was designed to promote his new film, “The Last Kiss”. Apparently according to the audio interview he gave, he also was going to try to wear it on scrubs at some point, with a cheeky reference to the film. It’s also featuring as part of their current $10 sale in the run up to christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Web Users Want Web Standards?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/13/do-web-users-want-web-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/13/do-web-users-want-web-standards/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking about this earlier and was trying to make an educated answer. What I would note is that it is primarily content which drives users to use sites, we can see that through all manner of feeds and low bandwidth sites across the net. Without content, theres no point in sticking up a website. You can see demonstrations of that assertion here from time to time. It’s also fairly visible through all manner of seedy content on the web as users will be quite happy to sit through the many pop-ups and poorly formatted text to get to that bunch of images which they’re after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carson Systems shows us the money</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</guid>
      <description>Carson Systems is showing the details of how dropsend stacks up in terms of monthly profit. Ryan states that at a conservative estimate by December ’07, it’ll be making $21k/mo. He also seems to be beating off a bit of bad feedback on the advertising which has/hasn’t been done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DropSend is up for sale</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>Carson Systems DropSend has recently been put up for sale by Ryan Carson. He states that currently they don’t have enough time to give it the attention it deserves, although the application is profitable with customers accumulating month by month.DropSend allows users to email huge files to one another via uploading them to dropsend and sending an email to the reciever to detail where it can be collected from. It’s quite interesting as the costs involved in its building are quite detailed within Ryans talk at a previous Future of Web Apps conference (also broken down here at 37 signals).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love useful error messages</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/i-love-useful-error-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/i-love-useful-error-messages/</guid>
      <description>I love it when I get useful error messages such as those often uttered by hotmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techno Graveyard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/03/techno-graveyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/03/techno-graveyard/</guid>
      <description>Our front room is looking a bit of a technology graveyard at the moment. Not only do we have the two archaic computers which have been there since forever, but now we also sport an unused fridge which has been replaced by one of our housemates parents (much larger) hand-me-downs.
This time last year saw the cleaning out of the Cardiff Department of Computer Science’s cupboards, with a large amount of the machines having to be “properly disposed of”, due to their burden of having huge crt monitors from yesteryear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/31/halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/31/halloween/</guid>
      <description>Does anyone else get the distinct impression that halloween is reserved for lamers? I mean, correct me if I’m wrong, it stems from a pagan festival celebrating a time at which spirits can make contact with the physical world. Is that something people really want to be celebrating?
I assume that the majority of the world goes along with the fact its just a bit of fun, a time at which kids get dressed up and collect sweets door-to-door, punishing those who don’t pay up with a bombing of baking compnents and parents play the niave fools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Tells Me Anything</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/29/nobody-tells-me-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/29/nobody-tells-me-anything/</guid>
      <description>Somebody should really remind me the evening before the clocks go back. I got up at 7.30 today and could have done with that extra hours lie-in. Oh well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 2.0 is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/23/firefox-2.0-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/23/firefox-2.0-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Firefox 2.0 is out! Wikked wikked bwaaad bwoy!Get your ass over to mozilla.org while its still hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God is a DJ</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/17/god-is-a-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/17/god-is-a-dj/</guid>
      <description>This short vid is quite clever:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash bash</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</guid>
      <description>I was quite impressed with myself the other day that I’d actually managed to write a bash script within ubuntu which served a purpose. I wanted to be able to monitor the size of files within a particular directory, and report back their size when a change was observed.
I found a program called fileschanged, which fulfilled half the problem, namely reporting back a file had changed, but I needed a greater level of detail than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ow! My arse!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</guid>
      <description>For the 3rd time I can remember ever I came off my bike this morning. I took a corner too sharply and ended up sliding across the road. So I am currently sitting here with gravel ridden hands and a really sore arse. I thought to go and check my arse when I finally arrived at uni and decided that it might be an idea to find something to stop the injury oozing all over my underwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flickr</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</guid>
      <description>After just 24 hours on flickr, someone has already added one of my pictures as one of their favourites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been following a number of so called “web 2.0″ companies in the uk recently via techcrunch.co.uk in order to explore what might be available to me when I need to start work this time next year. It’s quite interesting that actually, there is a number of companies cited around the Cardiff/Bristol/Bath areas that I’d never realised were in the UK.In Bath, there’s Carson Systems, which also host a number of web application workshops around the uk, with a Drop Send and Amigo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My final year of being a student?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</guid>
      <description>I thought I’d pose this as a question because I’m unsure if this is indeed my final year. It’s quite strange to think at the end of this thing I’m actually going to have to find some work somewhere another. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated from whomever. I’m looking for £50k/yr involving part time work from home, company car, but then I think the rest of the world is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone want to buy a car?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</guid>
      <description>I’m selling my car, which has been with me for the last 4/5 years and always been very reliable. It’s a very nice Vauxhall Corsa 1.5 TD in red, for more details, check freeads here and drop me an email either through freeads or this website if you’re interested.
I’m pretty sad to see the thing go, but as I now have no need for it due to the acquiring of my own personal chauffeur, it seems a bit uneconomical to hang on to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web is Just to Darn Big</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been suffering at the hands of the sheer size of the web recently. Just starting off at popurls yields many hours spent just browsing randomly across many, many web buzz sites. Although its all very interesting, its not particularly useful to my research, or in fact my own projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XGL, Compiz on Dapper 64 - Too much to ask?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64-too-much-to-ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64-too-much-to-ask/</guid>
      <description>I spent a large amount of time last week, after realising that I could very easy install compiz and XGL on my machine at uni, trying to install it upon my home machine. As its 64 bit, and owing to previous problems I’d experienced installing 64 bit applications (like linux for instance), I spent the best part of 2 days attempting to install both, before caving and completely giving up.I got to the stage where XGL is installed properly and seems to work ok, but the compiz gnome window manager isn’t working properly, meaning I have no borders to any panes I create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, we’ve not spoken in a while. How’s you?It seems I’ve been succumbing to a lifestyle of late that I wish I would never end up at – that of working within a “routine”. I must be getting old. The whole of last week seemed a little bit of a drain, working my ass off trying to get tiny parts of code to work properly in the day and the rest of the time being tired that I was staying up late to give myself alone time in the evenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Igniter</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been experimenting with code igniter tonight, a php mvc framework. I discovered it yesterday, not realising that such things were available for php. As its extremely lightweight and seems to speeding up things no-end already, I reckon I’ll probably be using it on some of my new slimshot projects I’m planning on working on soon. I just need to get another life somewhere so I can actually go about implementing all this stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slug&#39;s Talking Nicely</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a couple of problems getting my slug working nice under ubuntu. Firstly, although it is recognised by default and I can connect and browse via samba, when I actually came to playing my media, everything got screwed up, with Amarok trying to launch kmail…… I could copy files to ubuntu and play them properly from there, but straight off of the slug was a no go.I found the solution was to mount it under ubuntu using the command:sudo mount -t smbfs //NAS/DISK 1 /media/slug -o username=user,password=passWhere user and pass are your username and password for the slug respectively and the backslash indicates a space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to contribute</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been wanting to create a site which attracts lot of attention for ages. Not to create some profit-making venture, just to know that my voice was being listened too elsewhere and hopefully appreciated. I suppose that goes for my PhD too. It’s kind of depressing however that almost everything ever has been done, and every avenue seems blocked in both respects. How do you contribute to a world that is uninsterested in what you have to say?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Slugs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks back I discovered a slug in cash converters. Well, a usb2 external disk to nas drive converter affectionately known as the slug. Seeing as how I’ve been considering purchasing one, I figured shelling out the £25 was worth it for an experiment with installing linux on it for a bit. The D-Link nslu2 features two usb2 connection points for hooking up usb2 drives, but I didn’t really feel like sacrificing my university external box as this usually comes in quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Ubuntu? - ATI 9600 and SBLive</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu-ati-9600-and-sblive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu-ati-9600-and-sblive/</guid>
      <description>Another post about ubuntu? Where will it end?I was fairly excited from thursday evenings antics of getting things working on my machine at home, I thought I’d give it a try with my dev machine at uni. My graphics card, a 9600 (yes ATI, I know!) had been screwed since the day I’d put on Dapper, and to be honest, as I’m not using it that much for GL stuff, I wasn’t really bothered about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I speak too soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</guid>
      <description>It seems I may have spoken too soon about my linux joys with ubuntu. After performing a dist-upgrade on my previous beta version of Dapper, I discovered I’d have to go through the same problems of downloading kernel source and linux header packages for my new kernel version.I also discovered after doing this that actually there were further problems on booting Dapper straight up. Apparently the pointers to drives get screwed up somewhere in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thieves</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</guid>
      <description>You’d think that thieves would be content who’d bent my door back along to try and nick my car, realising actually I have nothing of value. Or that by monitoring my movements over a period of time, the opportune time to get into it would be when I went away to Dublin, Chicago or Singapore for weeks on end. Apparently not, in fact, they think its such a prime example of Vauxhalls lack of security that they would in fact like to come back and try to nick it by bending out the other door right when I’m here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Working</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</guid>
      <description>FInally, after a grand total of 10 months, I have a 64bit version of Ubuntu Linux working upon my home machine.This is great news, not only does it mean that I have a wonderful OS to try out for size, but that I can easily convert my subversion server code and latex source to my machine.As I’ve never mentioned it before, I’ll detail what the problem was here. First up, the graphics card didn’t have drivers which were working which meant that my X800 was pretty pathetic to be quite honest with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Irony</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I got a little annoyed about the fact that it seemed as if play had forgotten all details of my existence and telling me my email address was wrong. After sending a little letter off to them complaining yesterday evening, I realised after their response that actually I’d altered my saved email a little while before. I went ahead and placed my order of Sideways this morning which I’d expected to be fairly good due to the rave reviews I’d heard of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it take to make a good wife?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</guid>
      <description>From “How To Succeed With Women Without Really Trying” c1957
“The first wife, as opposed to the fiancee, must be practicable and serviceable. She is neither a toy, an ornament, nor a playmate. She will be your wife during the early, hard years before you can afford a staff of servants. She will serve as mother, cook, housemaid, chauffeur, nurse, and charwoman. This will allow her, if she is nimble, six or seven hours of sleep a night, ample for a sturdy girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mull</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</guid>
      <description>So my holiday in Mull more than surpassed the expectations I had for it. Beautiful scenery, solitude, our own private beach, lots of sheep and cows etc etc. In fact, you had to be fairly careful negotiating the roads of Mull for fear of taking out the 50 odd sheep that would block our journey to and from the house. That and the rocks (which we experienced through a blowout). We visited the smaller islands of Iona and Staffa, with both being beautiful but Staffa getting my vote (its full of puffins, rather than americans).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays Soon!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</guid>
      <description>Woohoo, rock on – its almost holiday season for me. Next week I’ll be off to Scotland to the Isle of Mull for a week and a bit of unadulterated relaxing. Ahh…Looking forward to it. Last years summer time in France was one of the best times I’ve had in donkeys and I hope and expect this to be too. So to those who’ll be there with me – you best make it a good’n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing domain names</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/choosing-domain-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/choosing-domain-names/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I’ve been spending many an hour pondering domain name choices for a fair trade t-shirt site I’d like to set-up, but never actually committing to one, due to the rather lacklustre responses of others on hearing my suggestions, or not finding anything suitable which conveys what I am trying to get across (a hip, trendy t-shirt place, ala threadless.com).If anyone can think of anything clever – let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My world has ended</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/my-world-has-ended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/my-world-has-ended/</guid>
      <description>Interestingly, two of my most used sites hotmail and ebay, seem to be unavailable at the moment for me to peruse in my daily late night browsing routine. Maybe ntl is doing something stupid at the moment, in fact this is most likely the problem as large amounts of images around the web are unable to be displayed for one reason or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 7 - Sentosa Island (Hopefully!)</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</guid>
      <description>So I managed to make it to the zoo yesterday, which was very exciting. More exciting though, was the night safari, where everything is minimally lit with the animals there to give a night time experience (I expect). I was a bit worried about catching buses and the like, but it was fine in the end, everything was really very well laid out, it was a doddle.
Today I’m off to visit the somewhat artificial Sentosa island – there seems to be a bit of controversy about the fact the land is all ‘reclaimed’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just returned from the conference dinner to finalise CCGRID for ’06. Tomorrow will be its last day whereupon everyone will return to their various different countries, or maybe somewhere closer for a short time on holiday. I’ve already heard of others plans to see Malaysia and Vietnam. I’ll be here until Tuesday evening to check out all that Singapore has to offer (at least I hope I will be able to).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</guid>
      <description>So, I have arrived safe and sound in Singapore. I got in yesterday and have been doing various CCGrid related things since. Yesterday evening, after a quick shower I headed off to find the conference venue and something to eat. Unfortunately I spent the best part of my time wondering round trying to find the venue! It was rather annoying as a large majority of pedestrian routes had been obstructed due to a huge amount of road works going on around the university premises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to Singapore!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</guid>
      <description>So despite having only been back in the UK for less than a week, I’m now off to Singapore, to present another paper of my work at CCGrid06. I’m slightly less nervewracked this time, but not looking forward to the ridiculous flight time (best part of 13 hours) and the time difference when I arrive (+ 7 hours). Viv tells me its a beautiful and amazingly techie place, so it sounds not at all distant from my own bedroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Five - Threadless and Whitesox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</guid>
      <description>After the workshop ended in the early hours of the afternoon today, I thought it would be kinda cool to head over and see if I could find threadless in Chicago, to stock up on some more of their awesome t shirts. After a little bit of thinking and umming and ahh-ing about whether or not I could actually find the place, I decided to make a a go of it and try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Six - Last Day in Hard Rock</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</guid>
      <description>So today marks the last day I’m put up in the Hard Rock, and my last full day here in the states. I awoke to a bill that had been slipped under my door to announce that I’d been charged for their “intimacy kit”, because I had moved it to have a look at it, and this constitutes a charge. I found this most amusing. I think I’ll make sure that there are no more automated charges made before I leave, seeing as how I’ve actually used nothing….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Four - Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Hello. Today marked the second day in the workshop I’m attending and the presentation of some of my own work and thoughts. I’ve also experienced some very useful thoughts of not only my work, but my PhD as a whole. Today is a good day for that.
Yesterday evening we attended an italian restaurant as part of the evening meals for the conference, which featured such a ridulous amount of food it was stupid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Three - Workshop Start</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</guid>
      <description>So today marked the checking in and out of hotels to move down the road in preparation for my workshop I’m attending while I’m here. Here’s some views of my hotel room looking out onto Sears, complete with the only person whom is here with me. I have to head out now, for the conference dinner etc. I shall be sure to post later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Two - Sears Tower, Hancock Observatory</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</guid>
      <description>Today, after yesterdays success, and it being fairly sunny, I decided to try and find Sears Tower (The USA’s tallest building) and come home fresh in the knowledge I had ascended it. People were all trying to put me off going as the views from Sears weren’t as good as those from the Hancock observatory, which sits on the Magnificent Mile and gives nice views of the shore of Lake Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day One</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</guid>
      <description>I have an uncanny habit of organising travel on unique dates. Last year my journey to Edinburgh for a conference was held up because it was the day before the G8 summit, when Viv and I went to Dublin, I completely forgot about the fact St Patricks day would fall around that time. My journey to Chicago it would seem is not to be blessed without this feature either. I’ll let you in on what happened in a sec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling to Chicago</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve arrived safe and sound in Chicago! I’m quite glad about that as it means I’m not dead, murdered or anything like that from what came from my whole journey…
I didn’t realise how much of a strain etc travelling could be, mainly because I’ve never come this far before (actually, I’ve never been outside of Europe). I had to set off at around 8.00am from home, catching a train to get to Gatwick for 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Go!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/05/all-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/05/all-go/</guid>
      <description>Its been a long time without me saying anything much, but lots and lots going on. The first event to note was that I had my car attempted to be broken into over here in Roath, I suppose that eventually that this was bound to happen being in a city centre and all I guess until now I’ve been lucky. They tried to get in through the passenger side door, bending it out and giving up after not getting in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ebay Experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/04/the-ebay-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/04/the-ebay-experiment/</guid>
      <description>I’m always coming up with concepts for websites, but I thought this one was worth blogging about. Basically, my idea is that you give yourself a budget of say 99p on ebay and see what kind of profit you can get from that by selling it again….on ebay… and so on until you flop and lose all your profit, or give up and bag the benefits of being able to spell and take photographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>worpdress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I noticed that worpdress.com, org and net weren’t registered, despite their similarity to the excellent blogging tool wordpress’s domain. I thought it was too good an opportunity to be missed, and registered the lot of them.After a couple of posts on the wordpress forums, and the realisation that there was no way in hell I’d ever have the time to put anything there, I decided to donate them to Matt Mullenweg, so at least they were redirecting the one or two people who might hit them to the correct wordpress site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nth Fest</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</guid>
      <description>Although I didn’t attend it, it sounds like this event held at my church at home in Somerset was an absolute blast – props to crackers for sorting it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg It</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently, through many searches to do with AJAX, Web 2.0 and the like been perusing digg.com, that fairly new web site for geeks.Basically, it’s a social booking marking site where users “digg” those sites which they find interesting, as more users digg the same pages, they get promoted up through to the main page, or higher up through the rankings within particular categories. Its a really interesting concept, quite similar to del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Pancakes!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Flipping pancakes eh? They’re crafty beggars they are..
Would you believe that in my 24 years knocking around, I’d never actually flipped a pancake until this tuesday? You could understand why I might be a little excited about that particular prospect, and a little nervous. I spent my evening with a bunch of girls, in all shapes and sizes (some tall, some short, some insanely strong) to celebrate this occasion, but when my time to shine came, it was all good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSI RS480M2-IL Motherboard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who would like to have a stable SFF machine, lest ye take heed of my advice…do not buy MSI.I bought a mATX MSI RS480M2-IL back in october, with a view to putting it in my new Antec Aria SFF case. It looked deceptively feature packed with its 939 madness and 3 x PCI and PCI-E slots. There it still currently resides sitting quietly all day until I return from work in the evening to perhaps do a little web design or listen to the 70 odd gigs of music I have stashed away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geeks gone out</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started a new blog over at webtyrant.com for all of you who visit my site and need a fix of techie-type jazz. I figured most of you didn’t, hence my placement on a different domain. You might notice a similar theme over there, so that’ll make you feel right at home even if the content doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just been informed that my paper for CCGRID06 has been accepted, which I’m very pleased about. It’s my first paper acceptance in my 14 months of being based as a PhD at Cardiff University so really its about time I got some ideas out in the open to people. It’s also based in Singapore, and I’ve never left Europe – yeah it’s two days, but I’m chuffed nonetheless.
The ironic thing is I was a bit annoyed last year at the fact CCGRID05 was in Cardiff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</guid>
      <description>Romantic rose petals and normal ones?
Probably about £6 I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</guid>
      <description>My day was brightened lots yesterday when my my PhD supervisor informed me he had a blog on the subject of grid computing. It was intended for members of our research group to contribute to and discuss things. The most amusing part was, being cutting edge and all, you’d expect it to be a bustling hive of activity. What I actually found was a site with two posts covering the last 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</guid>
      <description>and so it begins….a new website, a new era of web geeking to the max, free from the shackles of mere mortal mens minds.A place to be geeks are creative, explore and communicate…Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you, The Web Tyrant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are 100</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</guid>
      <description>This post is the official 100th post on this site! Wow, how exciting. I know that it’s marked up as #127, but these are of the ones that actually made it public here. The first one made it up back in August 03 and was rather boring. That makes an average blog per month rating of 3.4….Yeah, thats lame too. So, what can I talk about to make it all profound now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live in the Moment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</guid>
      <description>For Christmas, one of my gifts was an ace calendar providing helpful hints on worst case scenarios for each day of 2006. Todays one made me smile quite a lot – “How to survive psychological torture”. The second part of it however sounds more applicable to everyday life, work, relationships etc rather than actual torture (except for the horrors part).
Here’s the advice:
Do not worry about what comes next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Goes On</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</guid>
      <description>On the dawning of a new year, life continues much the same as it has done previously, I have lots of work to do, lots of pointless things to do and lots of people who want me to fix their computers because they heard I know a little about those sorts of things. On my quest to rid the world of all t-shirts by stocking up on them myself, I’d quite like to pick up this t-shirt to reflect how I sometimes feel about this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</guid>
      <description>I’ve not spoken in a long time on here and it seems I’m getting harassed into doing so, so I thought I’d air some stuff.
It’s the New Year! Woohoo! Christmas brought with it all the usual stuff, like parents moaning about computers and arguing about nothing. This year I only crept back for a very short time in which to see family and catch up. It seems like Yeovil is less and less like my home now, with friends moving away and all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
