<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2006/05 on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/</link><description>Recent content in 2006/05 on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Singapore Day 7 - Sentosa Island (Hopefully!)</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</guid><description>So I managed to make it to the zoo yesterday, which was very exciting. More exciting though, was the night safari, where everything is minimally lit with the animals there to give a night time experience (I expect). I was a bit worried about catching buses and the like, but it was fine in the end, everything was really very well laid out, it was a doddle.
Today I’m off to visit the somewhat artificial Sentosa island – there seems to be a bit of controversy about the fact the land is all ‘reclaimed’.</description></item><item><title>Singapore Day 3</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</guid><description>I’ve just returned from the conference dinner to finalise CCGRID for ’06. Tomorrow will be its last day whereupon everyone will return to their various different countries, or maybe somewhere closer for a short time on holiday. I’ve already heard of others plans to see Malaysia and Vietnam. I’ll be here until Tuesday evening to check out all that Singapore has to offer (at least I hope I will be able to).</description></item><item><title>Singapore Day 2</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</guid><description>So, I have arrived safe and sound in Singapore. I got in yesterday and have been doing various CCGrid related things since. Yesterday evening, after a quick shower I headed off to find the conference venue and something to eat. Unfortunately I spent the best part of my time wondering round trying to find the venue! It was rather annoying as a large majority of pedestrian routes had been obstructed due to a huge amount of road works going on around the university premises.</description></item><item><title>Off to Singapore!</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</guid><description>So despite having only been back in the UK for less than a week, I’m now off to Singapore, to present another paper of my work at CCGrid06. I’m slightly less nervewracked this time, but not looking forward to the ridiculous flight time (best part of 13 hours) and the time difference when I arrive (+ 7 hours). Viv tells me its a beautiful and amazingly techie place, so it sounds not at all distant from my own bedroom.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day Five - Threadless and Whitesox</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</guid><description>After the workshop ended in the early hours of the afternoon today, I thought it would be kinda cool to head over and see if I could find threadless in Chicago, to stock up on some more of their awesome t shirts. After a little bit of thinking and umming and ahh-ing about whether or not I could actually find the place, I decided to make a a go of it and try.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day Six - Last Day in Hard Rock</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</guid><description>So today marks the last day I’m put up in the Hard Rock, and my last full day here in the states. I awoke to a bill that had been slipped under my door to announce that I’d been charged for their “intimacy kit”, because I had moved it to have a look at it, and this constitutes a charge. I found this most amusing. I think I’ll make sure that there are no more automated charges made before I leave, seeing as how I’ve actually used nothing….</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day Four - Workshop</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</guid><description>Hello. Today marked the second day in the workshop I’m attending and the presentation of some of my own work and thoughts. I’ve also experienced some very useful thoughts of not only my work, but my PhD as a whole. Today is a good day for that.
Yesterday evening we attended an italian restaurant as part of the evening meals for the conference, which featured such a ridulous amount of food it was stupid.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day Three - Workshop Start</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</guid><description>So today marked the checking in and out of hotels to move down the road in preparation for my workshop I’m attending while I’m here. Here’s some views of my hotel room looking out onto Sears, complete with the only person whom is here with me. I have to head out now, for the conference dinner etc. I shall be sure to post later.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day Two - Sears Tower, Hancock Observatory</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</guid><description>Today, after yesterdays success, and it being fairly sunny, I decided to try and find Sears Tower (The USA’s tallest building) and come home fresh in the knowledge I had ascended it. People were all trying to put me off going as the views from Sears weren’t as good as those from the Hancock observatory, which sits on the Magnificent Mile and gives nice views of the shore of Lake Michigan.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Day One</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</guid><description>I have an uncanny habit of organising travel on unique dates. Last year my journey to Edinburgh for a conference was held up because it was the day before the G8 summit, when Viv and I went to Dublin, I completely forgot about the fact St Patricks day would fall around that time. My journey to Chicago it would seem is not to be blessed without this feature either. I’ll let you in on what happened in a sec.</description></item><item><title>Travelling to Chicago</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</guid><description>So I’ve arrived safe and sound in Chicago! I’m quite glad about that as it means I’m not dead, murdered or anything like that from what came from my whole journey…
I didn’t realise how much of a strain etc travelling could be, mainly because I’ve never come this far before (actually, I’ve never been outside of Europe). I had to set off at around 8.00am from home, catching a train to get to Gatwick for 11.</description></item></channel></rss>