<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tshirts on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/tshirts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tshirts on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/tshirts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Run a Fairtrade Business?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief retrospective of what I&amp;#8217;ve learned in the 6 years I&amp;#8217;ve been running Fair &amp;#038; Bare, a Fairtrade t-shirt company along with my wife.
If you&amp;#8217;re a new follower of mine, you heard right &amp;#8211; I run a Fairtrade t-shirt company. I&amp;#8217;ve not actively been marketing it more recently for a number of reasons, but I still have a strong belief in our original vision. That vision was that Fairtrade shirts at the time weren&amp;#8217;t being well received by the world, despite being available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair  Bare - January £10 Sale!</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</guid>
      <description>Fair &amp;#038; Bare &amp;#8211; The little shop I run (with a little help from my wife) is having a January Sale right now in celebration of entering the year 2010. Every shirt we&amp;#8217;ve made to date is just 10 squid! Hurry up people, it only runs until Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</guid>
      <description>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what&amp;#8217;s going on over at Fair &amp;#038; Bare and if you&amp;#8217;re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I&amp;#8217;ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what&amp;#8217;s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-Shirts from Fair &amp; Bare</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair--bare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair--bare/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really pleased to announce that Fair &amp;#038; Bare has just released 2 new shirts. First up is “Feel the Force” based on a slogan submission by JonnyDanger and secondly is the fantastic Esther Aarts’ “My Bike is My Castle”. 

We printed these on super-soft, Fairtrade certified, organic in-conversion cotton using fantastic waterbased inks. They also look pretty darn good. It&amp;#8217;s the net result of a ton of hard work by our printers, designers, community and the original cotton original farmers that mean that these have been able to be released.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>