<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
    <title>ianwootten.co.uk - Category: projects</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Shipping in March: Week 1</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I promised a progress update on how my attempt to get 4 projects shipped this month was going. On my first week, I decided to focus on my time tracking tool, <a href="http://hourglass.io">hourglass</a>. I’ve had this in the works for sometime and unfortunately, it’s fallen by the wayside to client work.</p>

<p>I’ve failed on my first week in getting this released to the world, but I’m far happier with how it’s working now and the value it might give to any potential user than previously. I’d had a working app and a shiny new design for it prior to last week, so first on my agenda was to bring that in and start from there. Beyond that, I bug fixed a number of known issues, followed by building out a number of reporting features which I feel are critical to have before release. It’s also allowed me to better think about the decisions I’ve made regarding implementation and whether or not it makes sense to change them at any stage soon.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, over this time I hit a major hurdle of my internet connection being killed due to scheduled maintenance. I had been sent a letter on this, but hadn’t clocked the date. I was lucky that in Cardiff we have a number of excellent co-working facilities that allow me to turn up unannounced and fled home for the sanctuary of <a href="http://foundershub.co.uk">Foundershub</a>. In the end I lost probably a couple of hours to this problem and I’m glad I made the decision early on to move before I’d lost the best part of the day.</p>

<p>I’m going to be moving on to my next project this week as planned and move back to hourglass if time allows. I feel that experiencing the variety of these projects will hopefully allow me to continue some kind of momentum. Out of all the ones I have planned, I feel that hourglass is probably one of the larger ones too.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Shipping in March</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>This month, I’ve decided to take some time out to ship projects. </p>

<p>I have a huge list of projects accumulating I’d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.</p>

<p>Currently I don’t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we’ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released. </p>

<p>That sounds easy, but I’m well aware from past experience it isn’t. I don’t want to work outside of working hours (9-5.30pm) as I know the impact it has on my family. My hope is by setting myself some achievable goals I can at least get some way to ticking off some checkboxes on this growing todo list. </p>

<p>Some of these projects are products I’ve not yet completed, projects I’ve released but need work or ideas that haven’t made it to the build stage yet. As a freelancer, I hope that some of them may even help out other people in a similar situation to me.</p>

<p>Over the coming month, I’m going to attempt to ship at least 4 projects out of the door. 1 a week for 4 weeks. I’ll be blogging about my progress here, and posting summaries of how it went at the end of each week. The end date of the 28th is also my birthday, so it would be great present to myself to have come some way to meeting my goal.</p>

<p>If you’re interested in receiving progress updates via email, signup here: <a href="http://eepurl.com/PxGe9">http://eepurl.com/PxGe9</a></p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>New T-Shirts from Fair &#038; Bare</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I&#8217;m really pleased to announce that Fair &#038; Bare has just released 2 new shirts. First up is “Feel the Force” based on a slogan submission by JonnyDanger and secondly is the fantastic Esther Aarts’ “My Bike is My Castle”. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/2/feel_the_force"><br />
<img src="http://www.fairandbare.com/images/shirts/2/1.jpg" alt="JonnyDanger - Feel the Force" /><br />
</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/3/my_bike_is_my_castle"><img src="http://www.fairandbare.com/images/shirts/3/1.jpg" alt="Esther Aarts - My Bike is My Castle" /></a></p>
<p>We printed these on super-soft, Fairtrade certified, organic in-conversion cotton using fantastic waterbased inks. They also look pretty darn good. It&#8217;s the net result of a ton of hard work by our printers, designers, community and the original cotton original farmers that mean that these have been able to be released. <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Head over to buy one (or more!)</a>.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web20</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web20</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>If anyone else like me is considering working in the uk “web 2.0″ market, and finds the posts on common job boards clogged up with all the jobs from america, the small job board I have created and posted online might be a help. You’ll find it over at: <a href="http://webtyrant.com/jobs">http://webtyrant.com/jobs</a>. It aggregates some common job boards together like 37Signals and ThinkVitamin, but removes anything but those located in the UK.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>The geeks gone out</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2006-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve started a new blog over at <a href="http://www.webtyrant.com">webtyrant.com</a> for all of you who visit my site and need a fix of techie-type jazz. I figured most of you didn’t, hence my placement on a different domain. You might notice a similar theme over there, so that’ll make you feel right at home even if the content doesn’t.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Arggh</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’m realling struggling at the moment to get a visual interface all sorted and loverly so people can literally “point-and-click”. I made the decision to do this after talks with both my supervisor and moderator and have been trying like crazy to get it sorted, its taken over a week so far! Not good.</p>

<p>My moderator also suggested that trying to find example XML schemas for CMS’s which were already out on the market at the moment for would make for good reading also.</p>

<p>I have to go see my supervisor this week anyway, will post to say how it went.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>IE</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Just realised that my cms doesn’t display properly in IE6. Might explain why it looked so dodgy at my mid-year meeting with my supervisor.</p>

<p>Got a few extra things in my project, permission system is fully functional, priorities for roles, workflow management – all of which still have bugs. Going to get down to the actual “management” part of the CMS tomorrow.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>What a waste</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>What a waste of a day that was…I hate programming. </p>

<p>I’ve spent most of the day stuck on trivial little tasks like trying to pass back multi-dimensional arrays through scripts, and interpret the results.</p>

<p>On an upside, I’ve managed to get XSL producing XHTML output and generated a working grid for the actions in the system. I also found a bug in XSL which means that it will condense textarea tags to their smallest form, and resulting in incorrect display in most web browsers.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>XML, XSL</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>After spending most of the day working upon it, I have managed to convert the whole template system in my project over to XML. I also added the beginnings of a permissions system which has no functionality yet. </p>

<p>This does need some time for me to go through the motions of Spec, Design, Implementation write-up for this over the weekend so that I can present it next week during my mid-year progress presentation with my project supervisor.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>XML, XSLT</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve spent a large portion of today converting bits of my project over to using XML with XSLT stylesheets. This solves a few issues that I’d had problems with.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Generating RSS feeds.  </li>
  <li>The masses of files for each template is now reduced to a single XSLT file, easily modified by anyone knowing what they are doing.  </li>
  <li>Better compliance with web standards (missing “‘s, closing tags all need to be corrected) means that it should be relatively XHTML compliant when tested.  </li>
  <li>Well layed out source.</li>
</ol>

<p>I haven’t completely finished moving over to this new format but will try and sort it all by the end of tommorow.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>