<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Out with the Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</guid>
      <description>If anyone is interested in puchasing my old computer, I&amp;#8217;m getting rid of it.
It features:
 Athlon 2500XP Barton CPU 512Mb 3200 DDR Memory 80Gb 7200RPM Hard Disk Sound Blaster Live Drive 5.1 with Remote Control Sony DVD-ROM LG 52x24x52 CDRW Tyan Tachyon 128Mb G9600Pro (Ati Radeon &amp;#8211; fully boxed) 350W Levicom Blue Lit Dual Fan Power Supply (fully boxed) Antec Plusview Case (with side panel)  (fully boxed) 17&amp;#8243; Hansol 710D CRT Flat Monitor Logitech Keyboard/Mouse  Boxes/driver disks included, but supplied without any operating system (unless you want Ubuntu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</guid>
      <description>I cleaned out one of the boxes of papers kicking around my room the other evening. In it, I found an old lunch pass from school (featuring a photo sporting a lovely little version of me) and lots of old encouragement sheets we used to pass around our youth group to gets lots of positive comments on ourselves. Most of these are at least 5 years old and some stretch back to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Long</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday morning, Maggie, our eldest labrador at home was taken to the vet to be put down. She&amp;#8217;d been poorly for sometime and had become unable to walk, for any reason whatsoever. Maggie was a member of our family for the past 13 years, so it&amp;#8217;s understandably a bit of a loss to us all. It&amp;#8217;s strange to think back to when we first got her, making apologies to numerous teachers for the state the new books I&amp;#8217;d been given had gotten into so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It&amp;#8217;s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I&amp;#8217;d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she&amp;#8217;d brave the border as well to make those &amp;#8220;all important&amp;#8221; first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oblivious</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;#8217;m a little less than perceptive of situations in which I&amp;#8217;m involved. Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve been clued in to a number of things which makes me think I&amp;#8217;ve been carrying freeriding on this life while I could of been part of something so much more interesting. This isn&amp;#8217;t a direct attack on anyone but myself, so don&amp;#8217;t anyone take it to heart. I think this is best shown through the forming of a type of relationship I&amp;#8217;ve been starved of for the best part of my life, one with my lovely new girlfriend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alarm Bells</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</guid>
      <description>Some of the thoughts in this post over at Barbara&amp;#8217;s really hit home with me today. I don&amp;#8217;t often take time to reflect on pointers like these but the majority of them are ringing alarm bells about some aspect of my life at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>From a sample upon the dischandler (DJ Moneyshot):
&amp;#8220;No one wants to be a failure, no one wants a life constantly filled with worry, fear and frustration. Therefore you must remember to reap that which you sow. If you sow negative thoughts, your life will be filled with negative things. If you sow positive thoughts, your life will be cheerful, successful and positive.&amp;#8221;
Not so sure how this pads out in real life&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMuppets</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;#8217;ve had not a lot of response to my situation with ebuyer of late, but this recent email I recieved from them sent me over the edge &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;d sent them 7 emails and phoned 2 times with a 40 min wait prior to recieving this.
&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-
Microsoft OEM Windows XP Professional x64 Edition &amp;#8211; 1Pk
Dear Sir / Madam,
Thank you for informing us of your missing item. When we are believed to have short shipped an</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing the Effects of Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</guid>
      <description>I went round to Living Stones last night for a bit of a lads night with Jon, Dan, Rob and Joe for music and watching Batman Begins. I took a number of Cd&amp;#8217;s for Dan and I to listen to, which basically reflected the &amp;#8220;base&amp;#8221; around which the majority of all my other music stems from. It&amp;#8217;s quite odd trying to verbalise how a particular song makes you feel, why you feel uplifted by it, how it captures a particular moment in time, thought, etc etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daft Punk</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been attending a fair few &amp;#8216;live&amp;#8217; gigs recently as oppose to the frequenting of clubs in Cardiff. The first was the fantastic R&amp;ouml;yksopp, whom I was dubious to see alone, but glad I did. Quite frankly they were as great live as I could possibly hope for and the addition of the huge inflatable tape and scrolling info about each song added to the experience.
More recently, I got to see &amp;#8220;Bowling for Soup&amp;#8221; at union on Friday, which allowed me to experience the &amp;#8216;delights&amp;#8217; of teen punk as well as some awful &amp;#8220;post-punk laptop &amp;copy;rap&amp;#8221; from Mc Lars who seemed confused as to where exactly Cardiff featured in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What colour are you?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/08/what-colour-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/08/what-colour-are-you/</guid>
      <description>I found a wicked animation by Maria Claudia Cortes describing what personalities a bunch of colours are often attributed with. I reckon I&amp;#8217;m a mixture of red and blue, my wardrobe reflects this as well. What colour are you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fools</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/06/fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/06/fools/</guid>
      <description>Whats the most annoying thing ebuyer could leave out of my order for my building a new PC? That&amp;#8217;s it &amp;#8211; the OS, so I can build my lovely little machine, but not actually use the thing until they get their act together. Nice one guys, you suck ass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD Greedy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve always bought lots of music. Those of you who&amp;#8217;ve had the privilege of viewing my collection will have seen it spans all manner of media, Tape, CD, MD, Vinyl. I&amp;#8217;ve recently been doing a lot of random browsing on ebay for CD&amp;#8217;s that have previously escaped me and possibly buying a few other items from the same seller to save on postage. My biggest one though has to be my most recent, 12 albums from the same seller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragile</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m feeling rather fragile at the moment, which is really annoying because the majority of the time I&amp;#8217;m the picture of health. It started yesterday, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d got over it only for headaches and tummy aches to return by the evening. Unfortunately, it meant I wasn&amp;#8217;t best of hosts to Hannah who stayed over on Sunday because of a stereophonics gig she was going to. I had to fix her up with Jon to go with as her mate decided to back out on her pretty late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</guid>
      <description>That last post aside heres a mildly amusing anecdote that happened to me whilst in B&amp;#038;Q a couple of weeks ago featuring a sweet old welsh lady.
Old Lady (Looking at lampshades): &amp;#8220;Is that the ACTUAL price of these!?&amp;#8221;
Me (Bewildered, wondering past end of aisle): &amp;#8220;Well, yeah, it says so on the label&amp;#8221;
Old Lady: &amp;#8220;&amp;pound;11.99! I saw &amp;#8216;em for &amp;pound;1 on Newport Road!&amp;#8221;
Me (Still bewildered, now in aisle): &amp;#8220;Oh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who hid the bloomin&#39; remote?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</guid>
      <description>I was contemplating all the stuff I generally tend to blog about. Most of the time, something rather huge has to happen for me in my week to be bothered to blog about it and then a large majority of that goes unnoticed by you, my readers (both of you), due to concerns about upsetting people, getting upset by people or not reflecting myself in the best of light. Other stuff, I just don&amp;#8217;t think is interesting at all, but I&amp;#8217;ve been told that while I think it mundane, it proves amusing to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may have noticed that I&amp;#8217;ve moved. Whats that? You didn&amp;#8217;t? Oh well, cheers then, how much of a friend are you? I never read your blog either. For those who didn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8211; take a look in the address bar, I&amp;#8217;m now at www.ianwootten.co.uk (Highly original I know!).
This week I have been mostly stressing about work, sitting at home alone, watching repeats, finding interesting links through the wonder of del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not quite the iflea, but...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</guid>
      <description>So Apple announces this week that they release their new version of iTunes, the ROKR E1 &amp;#8211; a mobile phone featuring iTunes and finally, the iPod nano &amp;#8211; a super-small, thinner version of the iPod to replace the iPod mini. Another iPod &amp;#8211; how many have there been now? There&amp;#8217;s still no move on a larger capacity front, so nowhere to house my 7000 high quality mp3&amp;#8242;s just yet &amp;#8211; except my portable fat hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Interludes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</guid>
      <description>These last couple of weeks have been fairly exciting from a musical point of view. I dj&amp;#8217;ed for both Sarah Lou and Zoe&amp;#8217;s birthday parties, which were both fantabulous, getting to hang with new and making even newer friends. My mixing on each was somewhat dodgy, but to be honest I&amp;#8217;m a bit out of practice.
Tim had been preparing for his CD launch for his band &amp;#8220;Walking Wounded&amp;#8221; all week last week, and their performance upon Thursday at Journeys showed off all their hard work (although unfortunately, I don&amp;#8217;t think the same can be said of the random geezer who decided to perform last minute inbetween them and the support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bizarre Dreams</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/25/bizarre-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/25/bizarre-dreams/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been having some really random dreams this week, the strangest part being I can actually remember them. Here&amp;#8217;s a few examples:
Sunday &amp;#8211; I had one of those ones where, you&amp;#8217;re aware you&amp;#8217;re asleep and can control whats going on, but was face down on my bed and completely overcome by something and unable to move any part of my body. When I woke up, with a bit of a start, I&amp;#8217;d only been out for a half hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trials Unicycling</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired yesterday by watching a few vids on the internet of crazy kids doing trials unicycling, so decided to go out for a ride in the evening round Roath Park. It&amp;#8217;s been a long time since I&amp;#8217;ve ridden, but it seems you don&amp;#8217;t forget. Nor do the &amp;#8216;oh I&amp;#8217;m original&amp;#8217; taunts cease, such as &amp;#8220;oi, mate, you&amp;#8217;ve lost a wheel!&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;pull a wheelie!&amp;#8221; etc etc. Anyway, it was nice to finally ride mine without fear of the horrid scratching which I usually obtain from my previous saddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Somerset</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/17/sunny-somerset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/17/sunny-somerset/</guid>
      <description>I went back home this weekend for Tim and Becca&amp;#8217;s wedding. Although the weather didn&amp;#8217;t hold out &amp;#8211; it was raining all day, the guys made the most of it and the service was fab. Music was provided by Mr Maynard and a string quartet. By far the most amusing thing was the pastor&amp;#8217;s inability to use a radio mike without whispering the whole service. So amusing sentences like &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t fall down the steps&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Mercies</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/11/small-mercies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/11/small-mercies/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch Charlie and the Chocolate factory last night &amp;#8211; which I thought was great, compared to the original preconceptions I had of it from trailers, reviews and the like. Anyways, I was sat there at the end as all the children were walking out of the factory thinking, &amp;#8220;Well, at least I&amp;#8217;m not as thin as Mike TV&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwanted Affection?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/10/unwanted-affection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/10/unwanted-affection/</guid>
      <description>So, after renewing my insurance policy today, I get handed the piece of paper with my policy number and the words &amp;#8220;Ashley, love&amp;#8221;. I&amp;#8217;m unsure whether the guy wrote this in awe of myself or indeed it had been written previously on the pad in use. Either way, the words in that order don&amp;#8217;t make any sense. Dyslexia perhaps? There&amp;#8217;s been a bit of talk and reading recently involving dating with integrity, not settling with second best and the like, but this ranks a few rungs below that upon my ladder unfortunately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal Images</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/03/ideal-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/03/ideal-images/</guid>
      <description>On a lighter note, I went to a &amp;#8216;focus group&amp;#8217; last night which was fairly surreal. I&amp;#8217;d been asked last week to attend, and had agreed not actually knowing the subject matter. On sunday I was informed that it was going to be on &amp;#8216;mens cosmetics&amp;#8217; (something I&amp;#8217;m obviously very familiar with!) so didn&amp;#8217;t really know what to expect. After arriving, discovering two of my old coursemates were there (and on the same course as Garima), we sat down for like 45 minutes talking about our opinions about luxuries, cosmetics and as many tangents we could stray off on as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Wrongs don&#39;t Make it Right</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I&amp;#8217;d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it&amp;#8217;s quite the opposite really.
My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it&amp;#8217;s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a difference a year makes....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</guid>
      <description>So, in the absence of students, life continues as normal for the various research teams down here in the Queens buildings. We wake, march to University and sit in our little boxes reading, theorising and tearing our hair out until 5 o&amp;#8217;clock when we march back, only to be repeated the next day. I hate routines&amp;#8230;
Today marked the graduation of Year 3&amp;#8242;s which brought back memories of my graduation last year, which was pretty depressing to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weddings, Unicycles and Money</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/07/weddings-unicycles-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/07/weddings-unicycles-and-money/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been a good week thus far. Saturday marked a return to Somerset to attend Steve and Hannah&amp;#8217;s wedding, which I was a little late for due to having to pick up a number of interesting things I&amp;#8217;ve been given by Gran. I felt a little harsh having to dash in, collect and leave, it felt a little like Dad and I were looting the place.
Being late was ok as one of the speakers was following in just after me (apparently a bit of a search was going on for him prior to the service), confirming we were good to creep through the large arched doors as the sound of singing could be heard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Mental</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</guid>
      <description>Today I travelled on 2 planes, 3 buses and 1 car (thats a full house and extra) to make the 800 mile round trip to Edinburgh for part of a BioDiveristyWorld conference. I&amp;#8217;m quite surprised I managed to organise and sort out everything since Monday and it go according to plan.
I was actually really overwhelmed at how amazing the place was for the brief time I was there, the sheer scale of the city was something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writers Block</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to write a classic quote I found in &amp;#8216;Boy&amp;#8217; while I was away so I thought I&amp;#8217;d shove it up now. I think it encompasses how I feel about work at the moment. Really enjoyed just lazing about reading in France for ages, finished Pi, although I found it to drag on somewhat, the quirky bit at the end made it fairly clever. Onto some Pratchett now after resisiting for ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normality Check</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</guid>
      <description>Our last day in Jard was rather less exciting than we&amp;#8217;d hoped, we decided to clean the place* we were staying in, so spent the morning doing that and unfortunately the weather was cack so didn&amp;#8217;t make for much of an afternoon either. We apparently caught the back end of a heatwave this week which has been rather fortunate, although pretty uncomfortable in the evenings. (Tim had it worse being in the same room as Mr &amp;#8216;Exorcist&amp;#8217; Pete, I had to endure that in Germany so it&amp;#8217;s his turn this time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastis and Miniatures - 22/06/2005 - 23/06/2005</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday not a lot happened, except for much reading and bumming around the house whilst trying out my newly found juggling skills. We also went on our search for pastis, after discovering that it actually tasted much the same as oizo, a wicked aniseed flavour&amp;#8230;I think Rach may need to be educated in its use however, due to filling a wine glass neat with the stuff, which I would of been dead if I&amp;#8217;d actually consumed undiluted, or at least extremely quiet for the rest of the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Decided to make a move on to our next beach today, taking with us a picnic and a load of beer. This one is situated right next to a forest, which was ace for our picnic.
Tim, after 3 years of living with one another has finally managed to teach me to juggle and give me the bug for continuing it. It&amp;#8217;s actually easier to learn using boule, forcing you to use correct arm movements, though its a little dangerous on the beach if you have a distinct lack of footwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Marshes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</guid>
      <description>Today we went over to the salt marshes in Olonne, it being slightly more manageable weather and all. Tim basically wanted to do a little birdwatching and Heledd and Dave didn&amp;#8217;t fancy such french beauty so went to have coffee in a suitable village somewhere. It was really cool, took lots of photos of the strange green murky waters and had a bunch of exercise too. Saw loads of eels while we were there &amp;#8211; horrible things writhing about&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Sunday&amp;#8217;s morning events weren&amp;#8217;t overly exciting &amp;#8211; the weather has been so hot that it would be a bit much to go off and try to do anything. Instead has been a morning of reading (Dahl&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Boy&amp;#8217; &amp;#8211; bizzarrely featuring Cardiff, La Rochelle and Somerset within) and people trying to juggle. The afternoon became overcast so we decided to make the trip down to the beach, where Tim, Rach and Pete all got rather dirty trying to recreate a eurotunnel experience, which was destroyed as soon as it was completed by Dave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Journeys - 17/06/05 - 18/06/05</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</guid>
      <description>So, it begins, the holiday season that is and with it my two day trip across England and back down the west coast of France to Jard Su Mer. Todays trip was fairly long, spending two hours bombing down the M4 to meet with the guys in Reading, then a further few to reach the underside of London on the M25, and a bit more to finally bundle over toward the Eurotunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another One Bites the Dust</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that the title might refer to Pop&amp;#8217;s funeral this week, but no, I mean the fact that finally after 7 years in courtship Mike and Jo have become hitched. Thats strike 5 from the core Yeovil lad&amp;#8217;s posse&amp;#8230;
It was a fab day, with schoolfriends from yesteryear I haven&amp;#8217;t kept up to date with, and family members I never knew existed. My sister always seems to find it amusing that Jo&amp;#8217;s sis, Sarah got hitched before them being a couple of years younger, having her been to school with Sarah and Jo in my form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUMO!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</guid>
      <description>No, not the monthly breaks event in Clwb Ifor, though you&amp;#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that&amp;#8217;s what this post would be about due to regular raving about it, no, *actual *Sumo.
So I started my trip off at 9:45am &amp;#8211; realising that actually that Tesco&amp;#8217;s would be shut if I left earlier and I&amp;#8217;d not get fuel.. After faffing getting burgers and the like, I set off about 10:20am to Bournemouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackalicious - Make You Feel That Way</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Ya know its like ahh like the most greatest feeling you could ever feel, you know, like, just total elation. Sunny day, just got paid&amp;#8230;.
You know its just like, you know, just the most joyous feeling you could ever comprehend. You know, chilling with your family.
You know just you know just really really feeling, feeling the moment, with the folks. Ya know really really really just chilling.
It&amp;#8217;s love&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Places</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</guid>
      <description>To cheer me up a bit I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to go to my happy place (which doesn&amp;#8217;t involve dwarfs on tricycles before you ask), merely great places nearby which hold fantastic memories for me &amp;#8211; &amp;#8216;Ham Hill&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8220;West Bay&amp;#8221; being two notable ones. Ham Hill has all those fantastic bike rides, barbeques, moonlit evenings, Christmas moments and stupid uni friends wondering where we got all the pigs from. West Bay holds a bunch more cycle rides, youth camps (with lots of sheep, golf courses and jogs), barbeques, baptisms (including my own), boating moments and horrible toilets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rank</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I found most amusing yesterday, which made me laugh lots is that my website is currently ranked #5 in msn for &amp;#8220;childrens farting jokes&amp;#8221;, Microsoft are obviously doing their jobs well once again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highs and Lows, Peaks and Troughs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</guid>
      <description>It was great to have the bank holiday this monday once again, allowed me to recover from the mad weekend that I had. The Vineyardites met at Living Stones for a great packed lunch (which had been moved from the park due to Cardiff&amp;#8217;s dodgy weather), followed by new take on a game of miniature bowls on the snooker table by Jon and Rob. After this I moved on to Roath Park with Lewis and one of his mates from home before meeting up with Vineyardites once again and chucking bread at feathered creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same Old, Same Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a fair while, I&amp;#8217;ve been getting jip off of people about not writing, but to be honest, there&amp;#8217;s not exactly been a lot happening in my neck of the woods which is all that exciting. I&amp;#8217;ve pooled everything I can remember from the last two weeks and bunged them into one post&amp;#8230;
Sat 14th &amp;#8211; Featured a grandma squashing her child by clipping her foot on a paving slab on albany junction and falling straight onto him whilst carrying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put on a brave face</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been feeling a bit off today &amp;#8211; maybe its the fact I had to cook dinner amidst housemates washing up at like 8:30pm yesterday, I had my wall banged on by neighbours last night due to noisy Tim (he has a gig soon so can be forgiven), or couldn&amp;#8217;t get to sleep last night again for the same reason, radiators blaring and a noisy neighbour party or maybe its because I had to wait around forever at home today to collect a parcel from the Royal Snail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academia</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had the fairly bizarre experience this week of attending the CCGrid 05 conference at city hall. This is my first conference and by all means a first introduction to my peers outside of the group involved with the PASOA project I am working upon. I think the most interesting thing is how normal each of them actually are &amp;#8211; I was expecting them all to have some sort of superiority complex for some reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Week</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had a really great week this week, mainly due to spending a large majority of it with the wonderful Matthias&amp;#8217;s and crew. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if this was altogether intentional, but it was great however it happened. I enjoy the crazy banter, furious sarcasm and witty jokes which are often made at others expense&amp;#8230;.
Monday we spent the day at Jon and Cathy&amp;#8217;s eating and playing board games due to the unfortunate weather that occurred outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a palava</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</guid>
      <description>I went off to meet up with my Sis and Viv in Swansea on Thursday night, the drive out there and around the bay was fantastic, beautiful scenery in wonderful weather that I don&amp;#8217;t often get to see around Cardiff. I think the comparison was made between the bay and Roath Park by Viv, but to be honest, there isn&amp;#8217;t much of one. After a full on carvery meal and everyone feeling like veritable fat jabba&amp;#8217;s, we drove over to the mumbles to munch on ice-cream (follow the logic there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitch Hikers Guide to the Skittle Alley</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</guid>
      <description>Every time I visit UGC Cardiff it brings back terrible memories of when I went to see &amp;#8216;Matrix Revolutions&amp;#8217; last year. A bit psyched by the fact that it may of be able to redeem the tragedy which was &amp;#8216;Matrix Reloaded&amp;#8217;, I went to see it with some of the Glamorgan crew on its day of release. All was going as well as could be expected, until when 3&amp;frasl;4 way through we were treated to a bit of a fight sequence and aerial acrobatics, which didn&amp;#8217;t really seem to fit with what we had been watching, but could of been some sort of trendy &amp;#8216;dream sequence&amp;#8217;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things you might not know about CV&#39;ers..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s some interesting information I found about fellow Cardiff Vineyard&amp;#8217;ers*.
 Jon Mathais was the producer of the New Romantics and was cut from the Sony Open in Hawaii on the 2005 PGA Tour. Jonathan Morgan holds both a successful &amp;#8216;modeling&amp;#8217; career and since 1999 has also been a Conservative Assembly Member. Zoe Morgan once featured in a Dr Who Episode (Season 25, Episode 152 -&amp;#8217; Remembrance of the Daleks&amp;#8217;) as &amp;#8216;Girl&amp;#8217;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far have I come?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</guid>
      <description>Having free time in the evenings recently is a wonderful thing, and its given me the chance to think about &amp;#8216;stuff&amp;#8217; I might not of done otherwise, recently its been my undergrad life. When I came to University, I was all fired up for an amazing walk through Christendom, I tried to throw myself into the Christian Union, and for a while it was great. Unfortunately my work got a grip of me very quickly, and for all the wrong reasons I backed off from CU and any kind of fellowship with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Busy Busy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been running around a bit like a headless chicken recently, not content with spending lots of time at uni working, I&amp;#8217;ve been partying pretty hard as well.
Spent Friday going to Kez&amp;#8217;s 21st birthday for a meal at Old Orleans, which was rather tasty. Bombed back to hang out with Vineyardites at Marty&amp;#8217;z Kitchen, which we were duely moved on from to Cafe aroma, and back to mine (after a few choice insults were uttered by me) for a nice cuppa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebay Bargains</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</guid>
      <description>If I had something interesting to say I would say it, but I don&amp;#8217;t really so instead I&amp;#8217;ll hit you with a few ebay bargains I&amp;#8217;ve picked up of late. Currently I&amp;#8217;m holding a rating of 166 positive, I reckon thats pretty good. Anybody else bought anything interesting off the net lately?
 Cut N Paste &amp;#8211; Forget It [12&amp;rdquo; Single] (£1.99). I&amp;#8217;ve been after this ever since I heard it on a Fatboy Slim &amp;#8216;On the Floor at the Boutique&amp;#8217; mix CD donkeys years ago&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s loads of places on the net where you can view silly or stupid signs. Most of the ones I&amp;#8217;ve seen aren&amp;#8217;t from the UK though, and I can&amp;#8217;t imagine them any kind of scenario, which I think would make them all the more funny. This place has loads, so many I can&amp;#8217;t afford to look through all of them. I can&amp;#8217;t believe I&amp;#8217;ve missed it before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</guid>
      <description>Well, thats another year over and done with, on to the next. Unfortunately, due to the distinct lack of friends available at Cardiff or at home, it kinda all just happened, and is almost over. I went out for an romantic italian with Tim and Mark on Friday, featuring a couple of very grumpy waitresses. I had hopes to move on later on to bsb with people, but Tim was knackered from returning from a week of training and Mark wanted to save his efforts for the Easter Service on Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Blues</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m trying to decide what to do for my birthday which falls on Bank holiday monday this year. Currently I&amp;#8217;m of the mind to do something on Good Friday like have a meal, then off to town (Chico Fresco and Phantom Beats will be at bsb apparently)&amp;#8230;.Leaving me free to go back and have easter and my actual birthday with family and friends. I&amp;#8217;m going to be 24&amp;#8230;24,24?!, no surely thats not right!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Jelly</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</guid>
      <description>I was a right little Heathen yesterday and skived off of housegroup to meet up with Mr Bryer in Bristol to see the awesome Lemon Jelly. Whats even better was the fact that Ben Lilford had come along too, unbeknown to me before arriving. They are quite literally the most amusing band ever. Prior to the Jel&amp;#8217;s entrance we were treated to Don Partridge (a one man band) whilst trying to play a couple of party games (find 3 stooges hidden in the audience).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oops</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</guid>
      <description>Ok, not to totally contradict my last post, I&amp;#8217;ve just read a comedy web page all about me that was put up 5 years ago which I never knew existed! You might like to take a look here. It seems my music tastes haven&amp;#8217;t changed all that much, as the songs I quote are all still top tunes&amp;#8230;I may of gotten all technical for no reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m finding quite a lot at the moment that my music stirs up far more emotion in me than ever before. I don&amp;#8217;t overly listen to sad songs, but I tend to find myself welling up at the most random of tracks. Quantic, Amon Tobin anyone? Pretty much most of these are without lyrics either, so I guess it really is &amp;#8220;all about the music&amp;#8221;. Tim&amp;#8217;s once told me that there is no reason for us to really gain pleasure in listening to music, its just a bunch of random soundwaves, how can we possibly gain pleasure through that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Packed Weekends</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/21/fun-packed-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/21/fun-packed-weekends/</guid>
      <description>My weekends are getting more and more full of stuff being a PhD student. It&amp;#8217;s nice being able to confine my work to a 9-5 regime (or thereabouts) and do whatever I want outside of that, plus unlike being an undergrad, I get some money.
This weeks been pretty packed, after the fan dabby dosy weekend at Port Eynon with Cardiff Vineyard last week, I stopped by my sis&amp;#8217;s in Swansea for a bit to say hi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrumpy Jack gig</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve got my first &amp;#8216;proper&amp;#8217; gig in Cardiff next week, supporting the mighty &amp;#8216;Eberg&amp;#8217; at Clwb Ifor Bach. If you&amp;#8217;re interested, come along, it&amp;#8217;d be good to see you&amp;#8230;
 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tsunami Relief Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</guid>
      <description>I went to the Tsunami Relief concert held here in Cardiff on Saturday. I have to say, it was absolutely fantastic&amp;#8230;! Made all the more special by the fact it was my first time in the stadium. Completely crazy to think I was in there for a good 7 hours or the hours I&amp;#8217;d work in a day. I think probably best acts include Keane, Feeder (becuase I knew the words!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Photo&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/20/old-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/20/old-photos/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve uploaded some old photo&amp;#8217;s of me performing at an old Infusion gig back in 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas over, back to work</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/07/christmas-over-back-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/07/christmas-over-back-to-work/</guid>
      <description>So, the holiday season is all over and now I suffer the mundane reality that is my own life&amp;#8230;boo hoo. Christmas was a little pants to be honest, as my Mum was in hospital the whole time I was at home, although it did make the place a lot quieter! Christmas Day was quite special as well, the fact that it snowed and all. It just so happened that this was when St John&amp;#8217;s Church doors were opened after the morning service too, so everyone there was quite exciteable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>