<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/01 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/01 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSL</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</guid>
      <description>After spending most of the day working upon it, I have managed to convert the whole template system in my project over to XML. I also added the beginnings of a permissions system which has no functionality yet.
This does need some time for me to go through the motions of Spec, Design, Implementation write-up for this over the weekend so that I can present it next week during my mid-year progress presentation with my project supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSLT</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve spent a large portion of today converting bits of my project over to using XML with XSLT stylesheets. This solves a few issues that I&amp;#8217;d had problems with.
 Generating RSS feeds.
 The masses of files for each template is now reduced to a single XSLT file, easily modified by anyone knowing what they are doing.
 Better compliance with web standards (missing &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;s, closing tags all need to be corrected) means that it should be relatively XHTML compliant when tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huzzah</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</guid>
      <description>Hurrah, exams over for another few months. I&amp;#8217;m glad, and completely exhausted by them all. I was feeling completely overrun by them all. Still now its time to kick back and relax&amp;#8230;until er &amp;#8211; Monday</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ming</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</guid>
      <description>I should really write something about whats been going on over the Christmas hols, but I don&amp;#8217;t want to waste any time which could be used for revision. What I will say though is that I&amp;#8217;ve just discovered a sourceforge project called &amp;#8220;Ming&amp;#8221; which allows for easy SWF (Flash) output with php.
This could come in really handy in that it could be used to generate templates with animated content, such as recent additions or news feeds in side blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>