<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2007/09 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2007/09 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Cardiff Geek Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiff geeks will be having its first ever face to face on Wednesday 17th October from 7pm at Cafe Floyd, just opposite the castle. Props to Dan Zambonini for organising the venue.
This is an informal, introduction between us all. If you&amp;#8217;re a geek, or interested in chatting with us about what we and you are passionate about, make sure you get over there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undeserved Job Titles</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</guid>
      <description>Today on the return from uni I passed the new Subway that is opening up soon near Queen Street train station. On one of their job adverts, they were advertising for team leaders and sandwich artists. I&amp;#8217;ve never really noticed my sandwiches being arranged in a artistic fashion before, maybe it would brighten my day if they were. I feel sorry for the poor art school graduate who ends up filling baguettes for a living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</guid>
      <description>Yes, yes I know I already posted about the FOWA Roadtrip in Bristol, but I live in Cardiff and have friends and colleagues in Bristol too. I promise I didn&amp;#8217;t just head there for free drinks once again. This time the Carson Systems team had pulled together some funky little FOWA Roadtrip badges that they handed out on the door, rather than the stickers at Bristol. I&amp;#8217;d previously learned that Ryan&amp;#8217;s wife, Gillian had taken a MSc in Cardiff and it seems the same is true of Lisa Price too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my &amp;#8220;business&amp;#8221; cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; on hand hand-made ones or something&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of &amp;#8220;The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain&amp;#8221;, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Geeks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve long wondered why there doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be much happening in terms of community of the web professionals in wales. There is a vibrant collection of people sporting different skill sets in the area, yet as I can see not a lot of chat amongst everyone in between different groups. On a whim, I decided to create a facebook group &amp;#8220;Cardiff Web Geeks&amp;#8221; to try and get people to come out of their shells and actually participate in a bit of discussion about tech topics in wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New iPods - 160Gb or Touch Interface?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods---160gb-or-touch-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods---160gb-or-touch-interface/</guid>
      <description>Wow, Apple have released a new touch version of the iPod (think the iPhone with no phone) as well as updating the classic iPod (160Gb!) and new nano versions. This actually means I&amp;#8217;d be able to have an iPod which fits my entire music collection upon it with room to spare. I&amp;#8217;ve waited a long time for that. The iPod touch also allows wireless browsing and download of new music via iTunes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>