<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2009 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2009 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Plugin v0.2</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just updated my amazon associates plugin to take into account the recent signiture changes which amazon have introduced for their webservices api.
This now also means you&amp;#8217;ll have to enter your amazon secret access key in the plugin configuration page.
You can download the updated version over here.
It also means my wishlist has finally been brought back to life. Just in time for Christmas&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Google</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve recently read a post over on the guardians technology site which gave a whistle-stop history of the internet as it turns 40. I thought I&amp;#8217;d share here my own experiences of growing up alongside the web, more for my own record than anything.
I remember at school a time at which there was no external connection, nor internal network (which we the pupils used) so the Acorn machines used at our school at the time could communicate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aardman</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/09/26/aardman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/09/26/aardman/</guid>
      <description>In order for me to generate this post I&amp;#8217;ve created something quite novel on my blog &amp;#8211; a new category which I&amp;#8217;ve not had a great deal of experience in previously, &amp;#8220;work&amp;#8221;. For the last couple of months I&amp;#8217;ve been working for Aardman features in Bristol on their forthcoming feature film, &amp;#8220;Pirates&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; building software, which I&amp;#8217;ll be doing at least for the next couple of months too.
I&amp;#8217;ve been having an amazing experience over this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Your Own TinyURL Service for WordPress</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t particularly like using URL shortening services. I think I first noticed them getting used rather prolificly in the Guardians technology section to include lots of random links to bizarre web content. TinyURL&amp;#8217;s own web site wouldn&amp;#8217;t particularly inspire me to go ahead and make use of it either. But, because of my own use of services such as twitter, I&amp;#8217;m forced to shrink down links to get within those 144 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vicious Circle of Posting Quality Content</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/15/my-vicious-circle-of-posting-quality-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/15/my-vicious-circle-of-posting-quality-content/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been looking back at the posts on this site and the commitment that I supposedly made (internally) a couple of months ago about posting regular, interesting content. But it seemed to die a death very promptly.
I think that there may be a bit of a vicious circle here (in my own situation at least). I&amp;#8217;d love to post regular interesting stuff, but for that to happen I need to feel that it might be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has web use changed your life?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been pondering this morning how the use of the internet has (or may have) changed my life. As a child/teen during the web&amp;#8217;s infancy, I was blissfully unaware that so many lifes/careers/relationships would be enabled or changed as a result of the interactions it might facilitate. I hadn&amp;#8217;t even heard of google prior to arriving at university and two years prior to that had never had internet access anywhere locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Fry and the Ascent of &#34;Micro Blogging&#34;</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/06/stephen-fry-and-the-ascent-of-micro-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/06/stephen-fry-and-the-ascent-of-micro-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is all over the news at the moment. For the uninitiated, it allows you to list short updates of what you are doing at any time. BBC News seemed to have an all-out assault at the end of January raving about it at every opportunity &amp;#8211; the first moments of the Hudson plane landing, an short chat about it by Stephen Fry on Friday Night with Jonathan Ross and this short clip on iPlayer by Stephen Fry again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Music Blogs getting a Raw Deal?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;#8217;t help but feel a little sorry for music blogs as of late. I&amp;#8217;m sure you may be familiar with The Hype Machine and may use it on a daily basis. For the uninitiated, it is essentially a music blog aggregator, which takes details of tracks and ranks them based on how often they appear and how popular they are. I&amp;#8217;ve found it really interesting to browse around and discover new artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I have to contribute?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>It has struck me over the last couple of days and it&amp;#8217;s a reflection of my attitude to being interested in geeky things in general. I&amp;#8217;m an elitist. When I started my blog back in 2003, I loved the fact that relatively few of them existed. It was a reflection of my day to day life and I felt my voice was being heard (even though I had no analytics tools to back that up and it was not particularly interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</guid>
      <description>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what&amp;#8217;s going on over at Fair &amp;#038; Bare and if you&amp;#8217;re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I&amp;#8217;ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what&amp;#8217;s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>