<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decade on the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago today, I started this blog. That&amp;#8217;s just under a 3rd of my life. In other words, that&amp;#8217;s quite a long time ago.
I started out using Movable type and very quickly (3 days later) ditched it in favour of the b2 &amp;#8220;weblog tool&amp;#8221;, which WordPress was later spawned from.
Back then, I blogged frequently about what was going on in my life, which tended to centre around University coursework rather than technical posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate, Don’t Preach</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</guid>
      <description>Last week, tickets went on sale for dConstruct 2011 and sold out within an impressive 7 hours. Having attended in 2010 and 2008 and judging it to be filled with the highest calibre web celebs from across the globe, I coughed up the entrance fee as part of the excited gold-rush. The cost of £150 includes access to the pre and after parties and the conference itself.
These type of events are stuffed to the brim with amazing, intelligent web professionals, many of whom I would consider to be colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has web use changed your life?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been pondering this morning how the use of the internet has (or may have) changed my life. As a child/teen during the web&amp;#8217;s infancy, I was blissfully unaware that so many lifes/careers/relationships would be enabled or changed as a result of the interactions it might facilitate. I hadn&amp;#8217;t even heard of google prior to arriving at university and two years prior to that had never had internet access anywhere locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Web Meetup #3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to remind people that this coming week is the third Cardiff meetup for web types in wales. It&amp;#8217;s in 10 Feet Tall on Church St on Wednesday 4th June from 6.30pm. Featured speakers include Matthew Cashmore (Development Producer for BBC Future Media &amp;#038; Technology, Research and Innovation) and Tim Holmes (Course co-ordinator for the Postgraduate Diploma in Magazine Journalism and the MA International Journalism: Magazine Pathway at Cardiff University&amp;#8217;s School of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>