<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vineyard reclaiming the web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Cardiff Vineyard have got to be the biggest bunch of bloggers I&amp;#8217;ve ever met, in a non-derogitory sense. Makes a change to Yeovil Community Church. Browsing around their main site and links from it, I&amp;#8217;ve found, hmm, lets see:
Cardiff Vineyard
Jon Matthias
Helen Carslaw
Lewis Parfitt
Neil Morgan
Zo&amp;euml; Morgan
Sarah-Louise
Thats crazy&amp;#8230;.! &amp;#8211; We&amp;#8217;ve got say 25 ppl max when I&amp;#8217;ve gone along, so thats over a 5th turned blogging converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple PHP Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/13/simple-php-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/13/simple-php-gallery/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve got rid of the old phpautogallery that I had and dumped simple php gallery up instead. I&amp;#8217;ve also converted shedloads of photos over so that peeps can see what I&amp;#8217;ve been up to recently and not so recently. This includes most of the weddings I&amp;#8217;ve attended over the last few years of very close friends, plus a few random ones for good measure.
Check them all out here http://users.cs.cf.ac.uk/I.M.Wootten/gallery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas feelings</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/09/christmas-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/09/christmas-feelings/</guid>
      <description>Can it be December already? What have I been doing? Wheres the last 3 months gone? I have to say I feel more Christmas-sy this year in Cardiff than I have ever been up here.
There seems to have been a bit of a build up so far.. Watching &amp;#8220;Bad Santa&amp;#8221; back in Nov (quite possibly the most amount of swearing I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen in a film), going to Germany the other week with all the festive fun over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boo hoo....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/11/08/boo-hoo..../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/11/08/boo-hoo..../</guid>
      <description>Thought I&amp;#8217;d have a moan about a few bits and bobs&amp;#8230;same old, same old
I had a bit of an interesting experience today when my speedo decided to die halfway to Rhwibina. Could have been worse I guess, could of been on the motorway. Anyway, best get that sorted.
Uni seems to be going ok, the works piling up a bit though. It&amp;#8217;s a bit of a nightmare to think about teaching and researching within the same day, takes me ages to adjust and concentrate for that matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weddings Galore</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/10/11/weddings-galore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/10/11/weddings-galore/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been to so many of my close mates wedding over the last couple of years&amp;#8230; In fact I don&amp;#8217;t actually think any of the old school crew are still single! Anyway in celebration of this, and Pauls recent marriage to Lisa, I&amp;#8217;ve shoved up a gallery to show off some of the pics I have for them.
The gallery is located here, and for the blog here&amp;#8217;s Paul in his new found role:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/16/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/16/update/</guid>
      <description>Seeing as how I haven&amp;#8217;t posted anything here properly for far too long, I thought I&amp;#8217;d give an update on everything I&amp;#8217;ve been doing since we last spoke..
Firstly, I got my degree, with the grades I wanted, although not perhaps in the subjects I expected to get them in, though I guess thats always the way. As a result of that, I&amp;#8217;m going to be staying on at Cardiff for a PhD conducting research into the PASOA project over the coming year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/08/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/08/security/</guid>
      <description>Blimey, some cheeky blighter signed up and posted on my blog! Well, I suppose it was my fault really seeing as how wordpress was configured to allow it! Anyway, I removed the offending post and reconfigured so we&amp;#8217;re now back to normality&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Breasts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/06/chicken-breasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/06/chicken-breasts/</guid>
      <description>In order to give a little more items of interest here, these are a few of the images which I&amp;#8217;ve been creating to assist me with my Image Processing module here at Cardiff&amp;#8230;
Basically, an image of a Chicken Breast is taken, and the best approximation to a cardioid found and displayed. This involves taking an image, performing Median filtering upon it to remove noise, edge detecting it with sobel masks, forming an accumulator space from the approximate gradient determined, and finally locating the largest peak within this space&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s been a while</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/03/its-been-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/03/its-been-a-while/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, haven&amp;#8217;t really written much here in a while. Things are going ok, I have my final 4 exams over the next fortnight which I&amp;#8217;m currently struggling revising for. Will hopefully pull out the grades I want, but I&amp;#8217;m cutting it fine..
I&amp;#8217;ve also finished my project, and its up and running on the web at www.understroke.com (requires client side XSL processing, IE 6+ Mozilla 1.4+).
Anyway, thats all I have to say for now, I&amp;#8217;m off to watch Kill Bill 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Processing - Connected Component Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/03/05/image-processing---connected-component-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/03/05/image-processing---connected-component-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Ahh, theres a result.
I&amp;#8217;ve been working some image processing coursework trying to correctly label an B+W image with a different label for each object in the image&amp;#8230;it&amp;#8217;s taken ages!&amp;#8230;.
The basic premise is, go through each pixel in the image. If this pixel has a neighbour which is labelled, label it with that label, if two pixel neighbours labels differ, store the equivalence in a table and resolve it later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arggh</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m realling struggling at the moment to get a visual interface all sorted and loverly so people can literally &amp;#8220;point-and-click&amp;#8221;. I made the decision to do this after talks with both my supervisor and moderator and have been trying like crazy to get it sorted, its taken over a week so far! Not good.
My moderator also suggested that trying to find example XML schemas for CMS&amp;#8217;s which were already out on the market at the moment for would make for good reading also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Year with Moderator</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</guid>
      <description>Just had my mid-year meeting follow-up with my moderator. It seems he would like to see a focus on XML standards for this system, rather than just a botch of XML which I decided on. Don&amp;#8217;t really know how I decide on that.
On searching for them though I found a CMS XML framework (uh-oh) which basically just outputs everything as XML. Find it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</guid>
      <description>Just realised that my cms doesn&amp;#8217;t display properly in IE6. Might explain why it looked so dodgy at my mid-year meeting with my supervisor.
Got a few extra things in my project, permission system is fully functional, priorities for roles, workflow management &amp;#8211; all of which still have bugs. Going to get down to the actual &amp;#8220;management&amp;#8221; part of the CMS tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a waste</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</guid>
      <description>What a waste of a day that was&amp;#8230;I hate programming.
I&amp;#8217;ve spent most of the day stuck on trivial little tasks like trying to pass back multi-dimensional arrays through scripts, and interpret the results.
On an upside, I&amp;#8217;ve managed to get XSL producing XHTML output and generated a working grid for the actions in the system. I also found a bug in XSL which means that it will condense textarea tags to their smallest form, and resulting in incorrect display in most web browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSL</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</guid>
      <description>After spending most of the day working upon it, I have managed to convert the whole template system in my project over to XML. I also added the beginnings of a permissions system which has no functionality yet.
This does need some time for me to go through the motions of Spec, Design, Implementation write-up for this over the weekend so that I can present it next week during my mid-year progress presentation with my project supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSLT</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve spent a large portion of today converting bits of my project over to using XML with XSLT stylesheets. This solves a few issues that I&amp;#8217;d had problems with.
 Generating RSS feeds.
 The masses of files for each template is now reduced to a single XSLT file, easily modified by anyone knowing what they are doing.
 Better compliance with web standards (missing &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;s, closing tags all need to be corrected) means that it should be relatively XHTML compliant when tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huzzah</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</guid>
      <description>Hurrah, exams over for another few months. I&amp;#8217;m glad, and completely exhausted by them all. I was feeling completely overrun by them all. Still now its time to kick back and relax&amp;#8230;until er &amp;#8211; Monday</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ming</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</guid>
      <description>I should really write something about whats been going on over the Christmas hols, but I don&amp;#8217;t want to waste any time which could be used for revision. What I will say though is that I&amp;#8217;ve just discovered a sourceforge project called &amp;#8220;Ming&amp;#8221; which allows for easy SWF (Flash) output with php.
This could come in really handy in that it could be used to generate templates with animated content, such as recent additions or news feeds in side blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>