<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/12/06/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/12/06/purpose/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking recently about purpose for Nifty Digits and myself, reviewing the clients I’ve done work for in the past and that work which I’ve felt most fulfilled by.
I’ve straddled a path between web/pipeline developer thus far - so it’s fairly difficult to pin down what I do in a single mission statement. A more enterprising developer may well have done that as part of a business plan when they first started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhealthy Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/21/unhealthy-comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/21/unhealthy-comparisons/</guid>
      <description>As we nearing Christmas, we’re met with the familiar annual trickle of uplifting, heartwarming adverts that show just how wonderful your world will be if only you would buy your gifts from a particular retailer. After several weeks of this I’m already feeling bad for thinking our simple, paired down family Christmas experience might just not compare and wondering how anyone can’t help but feel any different after two months of constant commercial brainwashing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web Development Stack in 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Over my time as a web developer, I’ve jumped between many frameworks and languages, attempting to find ones that work well for me. This seems to be pretty typical for developers who always have a take on the latest trend, either to quickly adopt or criticise it.
I really wanted to be a member of the Ruby crew for a time and ended up buying multiple copies of “Agile Web Development with Rails”, before having the opportunity to really apply it to a project and disposing of them because the material was outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s in a name?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>I usually get one of two looks when I announce the name of my company as &amp;ldquo;Nifty Digits&amp;rdquo;. Either a “Ah, I like that” or a raised eyebrow. Generally, it’s the person latter in years who might raise an eyebrow.
When I picked the name, I was still a PhD student at University and wanted something that “sounded technical (digits), but also sort of British (nifty)”. I also was heavily influenced number of web design bloggers at the time, particularly Dan Cedarholm’s blog “Simple Bits”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/04/blogging-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/04/blogging-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>All my most recent blog posts seem to be about updating my blog tooling (much as Rick commented earlier today). By recent, I obviously mean within the last 5 years.
I back tracked through my blog updates and discovered I&amp;rsquo;ve used 5 different tools over my 15 year history on the web.
 Moveable Type (2003) b2/Cafelog (2003) WordPress (2003) Jekyll (2014) Metalsmith (2015) Hugo (2018)  Something got lost in the process of migrating through all these blogging platforms, using increasingly complex plugins to generate what is simple static html.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
