<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
    <title>ianwootten.co.uk - Category: development</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Shipping in March: Weeks 2 &#038; 3</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>So, anybody paying close attention may have noticed I’ve skipped a week on updating my progress on <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march">shipping in March</a>. There wasn’t much to report in week 2 aside from I was busily updating my <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> site. This hasn’t yet gone live, mainly due to some restrictions on current client projects and publishing about my previous work. I hope to be able to publish it before the end of the month. I spent approximately 3 days on this, 1 on client work and 1 on working on <a href="http://hourglass.io">Hourglass</a>.</p>

<p>This past week however I’ve been working on a revamp for <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> and breaking out the shopping software I built for it into a new product. The reasoning for this is two-fold – we have stock for <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> we want to rave about and sell and I spent a long time building a shopping cart system that’s only ever been used by me! It makes sense (at least to me) that making this byproduct available (as per the <a href="https://signalvnoise.com/posts/1620-sell-your-by-products">37signals mantra</a>). <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> has existed for 7 years now and it’s backend has barely changed in that time and it’s still happily taking orders. This week has been an opportunity to rebuild it in a more robust manner, with more features and without everything that annoys me about current checkout systems.</p>

<p>Granted, it’s currently small and will probably won’t compare in terms of the number of features to cart provider’s that already exist – but what I hope it will provide is a simple, easy to manage way of selling stuff online. I’ve had a huge amount of thoughts on what would be the best way to package it, but have settled on a SaaS based system, rather than self hosted. I’ve been able to use stripe to simplify the way payments are taken and I’m planning on integrating a number of other tools to make life easier for developers.</p>

<p>Again, it’s incomplete and not ready to release – but it is in a place that I’m able to use it as an admin. I’m planning on getting <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">F&#038;B</a> using it and then releasing it on it’s own. If you’d like to see some features then please comment below and let me know. </p>

<p>The one thing I have realised about working on my own projects is the freedom I have to talk about it. No NDAs, no worry of treading on people’s toes, just (hopefully) helpful info. Several blog post ideas have been found over the course of the work I’ve been doing so far this month, one of which has already been published. I’m hoping I’ll finally have something to show you all before the end of this week.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Decrypting Filezilla Passwords with PHP</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>One of the most frustrating things I find in managing a number of websites is that I’m always forgetting passwords. The version of Filezilla I’m running however makes it easy to remember them again through its use of weak XOR encryption and a the key being hard coded into the software. I’ve used a program previously called the <a href="http://www.devpro.it/filezilla_pr/">Filezilla Password Recover</a>, but it turns out that this is also extremely easy to extract them using a simple PHP script. The following code makes use of the nice XML parsing in PHP5 and a decryption function I found over <a href="http://www.thinksheep.nl/php-filezilla-passwords-ophalen">here</a>. I’ve added some comments to roughly describe what is going on.</p>

<p>Note: Apparently this encryption has been dropped from version 3 with absolutely no encryption featured at all, that’ll make my job easier now. &lt;pre class='php'&gt;$filezilla_password_file = “FileZilla.xml”;</p>

<p>$xml = file_get_contents($filezilla_password_file);</p>

<p>$simple_xml = simplexml_load_string($xml);</p>

<p>foreach($simple_xml-&gt;Sites-&gt;Site as $site)
{
	$attributes =  $site-&gt;attributes();</p>

<pre><code>print "Site: ".$attributes-&gt;Name."\n";
print "User: ".$attributes-&gt;User."\n";
print "Encrypted Pass: ".$attributes-&gt;Pass."\n";
print "Unencrypted Pass:".decryptPass((string)$attributes-&gt;Pass)."\n\n"; }
</code></pre>

<p>function decryptPass($pass) 
{
        // Encryption Key for FileZilla 2 Passwords
	$key = “FILEZILLA1234567890ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ”;</p>

<pre><code>// Find the offset position in the key for this pass
$pos=(strlen($pass)/3) % strlen($key);
$decrypt = '';

$t=0;
	
//Loop through each 3rd of the password
for($i=0;$i &amp;lt; strlen($pass) / 3;$i++) {
	    
    //Get 3 characters, remove the 0 at the 
//front to get ASCII code to represent the character 
$num = substr($pass,$i * 3,3);

if (substr($num,0,1) == 0) {
	$num = substr($num,1,2);
}
		
//Get the ascii code of the unencrypted character
//by performing XOR against current ASCII and key
//before converting back and adding to decrypted pass
	$t = $num ^ ord($key[($i + $pos) % strlen($pass)]);
	 $decrypt .= chr($t);
	    
}
	
// Return the decrypted pass
   return $decrypt; }
</code></pre>
<p>&lt;/pre&gt;</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Bash bash</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2006-10-16T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I was quite impressed with myself the other day that I’d actually managed to write a bash script within ubuntu which served a purpose. I wanted to be able to monitor the size of files within a particular directory, and report back their size when a change was observed.</p>

<p>I found a program called <a href="http://fileschanged.sourceforge.net">fileschanged</a>, which fulfilled half the problem, namely reporting back a file had changed, but I needed a greater level of detail than that. What it did allow me to do however was pass the filename as an argument (along with some other parameter) to another program. I duely spent an hour or so trying to figure out a script to take that filename and report back its filesize and the current time (which I assume is close enough to that which the file was changed). This is what it looks like: &lt;div class="wp_syntax"&gt;</p>
<table>
    <tr>
      <td class="code">
        <pre class="bash" style="font-family:monospace;"><span style="color: #666666; font-style: italic;">#!/bin/bash</span>
<span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">if</span> <span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#91;</span> <span style="color: #660033;">-z</span> <span style="color: #ff0000;">"$1"</span> <span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#93;</span> <span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">&amp;&amp;</span> <span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#91;</span> <span style="color: #660033;">-z</span> <span style="color: #ff0000;">"$2"</span> <span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#93;</span>; <span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">then</span>
	<span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">exit</span>
<span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">fi</span>
<span style="color: #007800;">FN</span>=<span style="color: #007800;">$2</span>
<span style="color: #007800;">DATE</span>=$<span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#40;</span><span style="color: #c20cb9; font-weight: bold;">date</span> +<span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">%</span>s<span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#41;</span>
<span style="color: #007800;">FILESIZE</span>=$<span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#40;</span><span style="color: #c20cb9; font-weight: bold;">stat</span> -c<span style="color: #000000; font-weight: bold;">%</span>s <span style="color: #ff0000;">"<span style="color: #007800;">$FN</span>"</span><span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">&#41;</span>
<span style="color: #7a0874; font-weight: bold;">echo</span> <span style="color: #ff0000;">"<span style="color: #007800;">$DATE</span>,<span style="color: #007800;">$FN</span>,<span style="color: #007800;">$FILESIZE</span>"</span></pre>
      </td>
    </tr>
  </table>
<p>&lt;/div&gt;</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>