<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
    <title>ianwootten.co.uk - Category: wordpress</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>New Year, New Theme</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve long made use of the default theme on WordPress, which I’ve always felt wasn’t entirely “me”. The theme now live is one I’ve been tinkering with for a while now based on the lovely preview design used in the <a href="http://prose.io">prose.io</a> document editing tool for github. I really like the focus on simplicity and think it suits me well.</p>

<p>I’ve added some different styling for the navigation elements, given they didn’t already exist on <a href="http://prose.io">prose.io</a>. I’ve also added some subtle colour changes when navigating between pages, many of which are based on <a href="http://laurakalbag.com">Laura Kalbag</a>‘s palettes over on <a href="http://www.colourlovers.com/lover/LJK">colour lovers</a>.</p>

<p>One of the things I hadn’t counted on was consolidating 10 years worth of blog posts into sensible categories as it was becoming a bit of a mess. When I first started blogging, wordpress didn’t exist, let alone tagging and I think I started out using categories in a manner to replicate them.</p>

<p>There’s still a few things I’m not entirely happy with, such as how navigation is represented for single posts. I intend to tidy the theme up and release it back to the WordPress community, but for now I’m enjoying having finally got it out in the open. Feel free to let me know what you think.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin v0.2</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0-2</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2011-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0-2</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Just a quick note to say I’ve updated the plugin that generates my <a href="http://ianwootten.co.uk/filmstream">filmstream pages</a>. It’s become obvious that the <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">Lovefilm API</a> only exposes the last 10 features that you’ve rented in their “at home” list. This isn’t that great if you’ve been renting more than a few months. This is the same as the information you’d see in your account when logged in.</p>

<p>I’ve made a simple modification to use the actual ids that <a href="http://lovefilm.com">Lovefilm</a> issue for films, rather than a autoincrement value. This way, there’s no need to empty what’s currently stored when updating and we capture the users history of rentals…</p>

<p>You can grab it over <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/filmstream.zip">here</a></p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Updating WordPress Automatically over SFTP</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2011-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Heres a quick how to on getting wordpress to update over SFTP. On a default install of php, wordpress only gives the option to update over FTP. I wanted to get it working as it’s more secure and means I don’t have to open up FTP on my virtual server and open another port up in the firewall.</p>

<p>I’m using ubuntu and the sequence of commands I followed were:</p>

<pre class="bash">sudo apt-get install libssh2-1-dev libssh2-php
</pre>

<p>You should now find that if you list the modules installed in php and check if ssh2 is now there, you get the result “ssh2″:</p>

<pre class="bash">php -m | grep ssh2
</pre>

<p>You’ll need to restart apache for the changes to begin being used.</p>

<pre class="bash">sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 restart
</pre>

<p>If you head to updates in your dashboard, you should now see an extra option “SSH2″ and spaces for public and private authentication keys. I had to head back to the terminal and create these particular files.</p>

<pre class="bash">cd ~
ssh-keygen
cat .ssh/id_rsa.pub &gt;&gt; .ssh/authorized_keys
chmod 755 .ssh
chmod 644 .ssh/*
sudo chown -R ian:www-data /var/www/pathtowordpress/
</pre>

<p>Now you can head into the updates page again, enter your username and password and the locations to your public and private keys (/home/ian/.ssh/id_rsa.pub and /home/ian/.ssh/id_rsa in my case). If you’re running ssh on a non standard port, be sure to append that to your hostname. </p>

<p>Thanks to the following helpful posts: http://kevin.vanzonneveld.net/techblog/article/make_ssh_connections_with_php/</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin is No More</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I think my post title says it all really. I’ve just discovered that amazon has deprecated use of its ListLookup method since October 15th. I had used this in order to retrieve details of my amazon wishlist and display neatly on my blog using <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin">my wishlist plugin</a>. Now it seems I’m forced to generate one with their own widget builder. This in turn means my wordpress plugin will no longer work. Sorry for those who were making use of it, or would like to use it. It’s also apparent that this is a kick in the teeth for developers building sites entirely dependant on this method. <a href="https://forums.aws.amazon.com/thread.jspa?threadID=53342">This chap estimates he made $11k in the last year using this function</a>. This is the trouble with building stuff that relies on third party services. I wonder how much more of their api they will gradually remove?</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Something I’ve thought I’d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I’ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I’m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I’ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I’ve got the opportunity to do this.</p>

<p>Our television came with a years subscription to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a>, which means I can now track our past film watching history. At four blu rays a month, that’s quite a lot of films over the course of the year.</p>

<p>Love Film have recently opened up their doors with an api and <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">developer area</a> (which unfortunately is not particularly active at the moment). Anyway – their documentation is pretty thorough and has made the process of creating a wordpress plugin to display my past rentals really simple. You can see some example output of it on my site <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/filmstream">over here</a>.</p>

<p>You can grab the plugin over <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/filmstream.zip">here</a>. It’s authenticated by oauth (for which you’ll require php on your blog host to be compiled with oauth enabled) and so will bounce you over to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a> to ask for access to your account, but after that will update on a daily basis. Just click “Fetch Items” on the filmstream admin page and stick <code>&lt;!--filmstream_content--&gt;</code> in any page to display a table containing all your past rentals. There’s no options to speak of right now, but I’m sure I’ll be extending it in the future.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Plugin v0.2</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0-2</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2009-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0-2</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve just updated my amazon associates plugin to take into account the recent signiture changes which amazon have introduced for their webservices api.</p>

<p>This now also means you’ll have to enter your amazon secret access key in the plugin configuration page.</p>

<p>You can download the updated version over <a href="http://ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/wishlist.zip">here</a>.</p>

<p>It also means <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wishlist">my wishlist</a> has finally been brought back to life. Just in time for Christmas…</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Create Your Own TinyURL Service for WordPress</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2009-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I don’t particularly like using URL shortening services. I think I first noticed them getting used rather prolificly in the Guardians technology section to include lots of random links to bizarre web content. <a href="http://tinyurl.com">TinyURL’s own web site</a> wouldn’t particularly inspire me to go ahead and make use of it either. But, because of <a href="http://twitter.com/ironyboy">my own use</a> of services such as twitter, I’m forced to shrink down links to get within those 144 characters.</p>

<p>Herein lies a problem – If said URL shortening service disappears, all my links are broken to all that interesting content I worked so hard to find. Not good.</p>

<p>In order to our bit to help, <a href="http://simonwillison.net/2009/Apr/11/revcanonical/">a</a> <a href="http://adactio.com/journal/?start=10">number</a> <a href="http://www.colly.com/comments/ee_shortener_plugin_your_own_short_urls_using_revcanonical_and_permanent_re/">of</a> <a href="http://bokardo.com/">developers</a> and even <a href="http://baconfile.com/">services</a> have taken action in order to make sure they provide alternatives for the links over which they’re responsible.</p>

<p>I’ve <a href="http://whomwah.com/2009/04/14/revcanonical-a-revcanonical-wordpress-plugin/">installed a plugin here</a> which uses the recently puchased domain “<a href="http://woot10.eu">woot10.eu</a>” to provide alternative links using the code <code>&lt;link rev="canonical" href="shorter link" /&gt;</code>. My full ianwootten.co.uk domain does not lend itself well to be able to provide a shorter URL on the same domain unforunately.</p>

<p>There is a whole huge discussion on the approriateness of using this technique (mainly) due to the rev attribute not being included in the HTML5 spec. See the comments in <a href="http://shiflett.org/blog/2009/apr/save-the-internet-with-rev-canonical">Chris Shifletts post</a> for more on this.</p>

<p>Anyway, Duncans plugin takes the id of any wordpress post and coverts it to base 36 (instead of 10) and offers up the alternative in the header of each post. I believe the conversion could go all the way up to 62, if php’s base conversion actually supported the use of different cases in conversion.</p>

<p>In my own case, I’ve had to forward the links from woot10.eu across to www.ianwootten.co.uk using a .htaccess file so that the plugin is actually able to pick them up.</p>

<p>Now when you visit:</p>

<p><code>http://woot10.eu/p8p</code> you’ll be forwarded on to the longer URL such as <code>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/15/my-vicious-circle-of-posting-quality-content</code>.</p>

<p>This isn’t particularly useful if you want to find the alternative for URL, as you’ll have to hunt through the source of a post. For that I’d suggest <a href="http://simonwillison.net/2009/Apr/11/revcanonical/">Simons bookmarklet</a> which looks for an alternative link, or creates one if it doesn’t exist using tinyurl. As an aside, there looks to be an interesting talk on the canonical attribute and link element by Matt Cutts of google <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cm9onOGTgeM">here</a>.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-04-02T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>One of the things that’s bugged me for a while whilst having a website is that at certain times of the year when people might actually like to buy me a gift they’re unable to find my wishlist. This is mainly because they’re simple folk who might not think to check amazon for my name. I’m also signed up with amazon associates, so I decided it could do me well to post my wishlist items along with my referral tag in the links in order to earn a bob or two on my own homepage. All this data is available on the web already its just a case of putting it together.</p>

<p>Some keen readers might of noticed the wishlist page I stuck up recently and want something similar on their own site and (like myself) either can’t be bothered or didn’t have the time to create a plugin to pull this data together. I’m putting up here my own quick and dirty plugin I built a few weeks ago to achieve this.</p>

<p>It uses amazon web services to look up a wishlist, stick in a specified associates id in each of my item links and replace where I put the text <!-- wishlist_content --> (without spaces) in a post with my wishlist items. The plugin regularly updates this (hourly) as a scheduled event in wordpress in case someone decides to actually buy me something. Of course you’ll need a services key to use it, which you can easily get by signing up with amazon at aws.amazon.com. Fill out your services id, your wishlist id (found by logging into amazon and heading to your wishlist page) and your locale (the bit after amazon. so mine is .co.uk) and press the fetch items to pull all the items in. If you don’t have an associates id, feel free to leave as my own : )</p>

<p>I used curl to get the remote data from amazon as the file_get_content methods generally aren’t enabled on normal web hosts. If you’d like the items to be fetched less regularly, then install the plugin with and updated wp_schedule_event method in the main wishlist.php to a value of your choice.</p>

<p>You can download it over <a href="http://ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/wishlist.zip">here</a>.</p>

<p><em>Double alliteration in a post title? Not sure I’ve attempted that before.</em></p>

<p>[Edit: You’ll need to be running on PHP5 to make use of this plugin]<br />
[Edit: I released an updated version based on Amazon’s move to use of signitures, see the details <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0-2">here</a>]</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>