<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright Law Finally Aligns with Me</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me/</guid>
      <description>On June 1st 2014, some much needed changes are being made to exceptions to copyright law which amongst other things, will allow conversion of personal media between file formats.
Finally, we&amp;#8217;ll able to make personal conversions of digital media (at least they will be now counted as legal copies). I&amp;#8217;ve long made copies of my cd&amp;#8217;s to listen to whilst coding (iTunes allows me to do so simply) &amp;#8211; but it is not currently legal to move these files to another storage medium, such as an mp3 player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thou Shalt Always Kill</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</guid>
      <description>I am loving this track I just discovered on Adam Fletchers blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s up with Last.fm?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</guid>
      <description>Last.fm seems to be down at the moment for the last couple of minutes. Anyone know what&amp;#8217;s going on?[Update:Looks like this was just a blip, ho hum]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashup!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for Beatbox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</guid>
      <description>This link sent to me by Lewis made me laugh quite a lot. Funnily, it looks a lot like him with a wig on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It&amp;#8217;s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I&amp;#8217;d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she&amp;#8217;d brave the border as well to make those &amp;#8220;all important&amp;#8221; first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oblivious</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;#8217;m a little less than perceptive of situations in which I&amp;#8217;m involved. Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve been clued in to a number of things which makes me think I&amp;#8217;ve been carrying freeriding on this life while I could of been part of something so much more interesting. This isn&amp;#8217;t a direct attack on anyone but myself, so don&amp;#8217;t anyone take it to heart. I think this is best shown through the forming of a type of relationship I&amp;#8217;ve been starved of for the best part of my life, one with my lovely new girlfriend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing the Effects of Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</guid>
      <description>I went round to Living Stones last night for a bit of a lads night with Jon, Dan, Rob and Joe for music and watching Batman Begins. I took a number of Cd&amp;#8217;s for Dan and I to listen to, which basically reflected the &amp;#8220;base&amp;#8221; around which the majority of all my other music stems from. It&amp;#8217;s quite odd trying to verbalise how a particular song makes you feel, why you feel uplifted by it, how it captures a particular moment in time, thought, etc etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daft Punk</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been attending a fair few &amp;#8216;live&amp;#8217; gigs recently as oppose to the frequenting of clubs in Cardiff. The first was the fantastic R&amp;ouml;yksopp, whom I was dubious to see alone, but glad I did. Quite frankly they were as great live as I could possibly hope for and the addition of the huge inflatable tape and scrolling info about each song added to the experience.
More recently, I got to see &amp;#8220;Bowling for Soup&amp;#8221; at union on Friday, which allowed me to experience the &amp;#8216;delights&amp;#8217; of teen punk as well as some awful &amp;#8220;post-punk laptop &amp;copy;rap&amp;#8221; from Mc Lars who seemed confused as to where exactly Cardiff featured in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD Greedy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve always bought lots of music. Those of you who&amp;#8217;ve had the privilege of viewing my collection will have seen it spans all manner of media, Tape, CD, MD, Vinyl. I&amp;#8217;ve recently been doing a lot of random browsing on ebay for CD&amp;#8217;s that have previously escaped me and possibly buying a few other items from the same seller to save on postage. My biggest one though has to be my most recent, 12 albums from the same seller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not quite the iflea, but...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</guid>
      <description>So Apple announces this week that they release their new version of iTunes, the ROKR E1 &amp;#8211; a mobile phone featuring iTunes and finally, the iPod nano &amp;#8211; a super-small, thinner version of the iPod to replace the iPod mini. Another iPod &amp;#8211; how many have there been now? There&amp;#8217;s still no move on a larger capacity front, so nowhere to house my 7000 high quality mp3&amp;#8242;s just yet &amp;#8211; except my portable fat hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Interludes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</guid>
      <description>These last couple of weeks have been fairly exciting from a musical point of view. I dj&amp;#8217;ed for both Sarah Lou and Zoe&amp;#8217;s birthday parties, which were both fantabulous, getting to hang with new and making even newer friends. My mixing on each was somewhat dodgy, but to be honest I&amp;#8217;m a bit out of practice.
Tim had been preparing for his CD launch for his band &amp;#8220;Walking Wounded&amp;#8221; all week last week, and their performance upon Thursday at Journeys showed off all their hard work (although unfortunately, I don&amp;#8217;t think the same can be said of the random geezer who decided to perform last minute inbetween them and the support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Wrongs don&#39;t Make it Right</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I&amp;#8217;d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it&amp;#8217;s quite the opposite really.
My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it&amp;#8217;s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackalicious - Make You Feel That Way</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Ya know its like ahh like the most greatest feeling you could ever feel, you know, like, just total elation. Sunny day, just got paid&amp;#8230;.
You know its just like, you know, just the most joyous feeling you could ever comprehend. You know, chilling with your family.
You know just you know just really really feeling, feeling the moment, with the folks. Ya know really really really just chilling.
It&amp;#8217;s love&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Jelly</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</guid>
      <description>I was a right little Heathen yesterday and skived off of housegroup to meet up with Mr Bryer in Bristol to see the awesome Lemon Jelly. Whats even better was the fact that Ben Lilford had come along too, unbeknown to me before arriving. They are quite literally the most amusing band ever. Prior to the Jel&amp;#8217;s entrance we were treated to Don Partridge (a one man band) whilst trying to play a couple of party games (find 3 stooges hidden in the audience).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oops</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</guid>
      <description>Ok, not to totally contradict my last post, I&amp;#8217;ve just read a comedy web page all about me that was put up 5 years ago which I never knew existed! You might like to take a look here. It seems my music tastes haven&amp;#8217;t changed all that much, as the songs I quote are all still top tunes&amp;#8230;I may of gotten all technical for no reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m finding quite a lot at the moment that my music stirs up far more emotion in me than ever before. I don&amp;#8217;t overly listen to sad songs, but I tend to find myself welling up at the most random of tracks. Quantic, Amon Tobin anyone? Pretty much most of these are without lyrics either, so I guess it really is &amp;#8220;all about the music&amp;#8221;. Tim&amp;#8217;s once told me that there is no reason for us to really gain pleasure in listening to music, its just a bunch of random soundwaves, how can we possibly gain pleasure through that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrumpy Jack gig</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve got my first &amp;#8216;proper&amp;#8217; gig in Cardiff next week, supporting the mighty &amp;#8216;Eberg&amp;#8217; at Clwb Ifor Bach. If you&amp;#8217;re interested, come along, it&amp;#8217;d be good to see you&amp;#8230;
 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tsunami Relief Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</guid>
      <description>I went to the Tsunami Relief concert held here in Cardiff on Saturday. I have to say, it was absolutely fantastic&amp;#8230;! Made all the more special by the fact it was my first time in the stadium. Completely crazy to think I was in there for a good 7 hours or the hours I&amp;#8217;d work in a day. I think probably best acts include Keane, Feeder (becuase I knew the words!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>