<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
    <title>ianwootten.co.uk - Category: business</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Tips for being a more Productive Freelancer</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Having heard the question raised on <a href="http://workingoutpodcast.com">@workingoutshow</a>, I thought I’d take some time to share the things that I’ve found have really helped me be productive in my work. These may not work for everyone, but hopefully some points will help for others.</p>

<h2 id="find-a-good-environment">Find a Good Environment</h2>

<p>The single biggest change I’ve found which has had a major impact on my work is changing my environment. We’re lucky enough to have a small garden at our house and with the arrival of my daughter back in October, I was quick to realise that working in the open plan lounge in our house just wasn’t a viable option any more. Here in Cardiff, we’ve been lucky enough to have several co-working spaces open locally, but for me I prefer being able to switch off background noise and clear my head when I really need to knuckle down and focus. Around the same time, we made some major changes to the back of our house and garden which meant that there was space enough for a desk in our sunroom which overlooks it. I now spend 90% of my working time looking out over our little green space, which makes for a welcome break from staring at my screen and gives me a self-contained and more importantly, quiet environment in which to think. I also get to enjoy the space more overlooking the various wildlife that visits during the day. It’s funny how good a little bird taking a dust bath every now and again will make you feel.</p>

<h2 id="organise-your-tasks">Organise Your Tasks</h2>

<p>I use trello for organising tasks I want to get done, with a board for each project. These are organised in descending priority, using trellos card defaults of “To Do”, “Done” and “Doing” to track what I’ve achieved for a project. If whilst during the course of one task, I realise something needs doing over and above the scope of the task I’m currently working on, I’ll add it to my todo list and work on it when all other tasks with a higher priority have been completed. This strategy works well for me in terms of being able to blast through a whole heap of development tasks without having to think too much about what I need to do next.</p>

<h2 id="plan-your-next-day-before-leaving-your-desk">Plan Your Next Day Before Leaving Your Desk</h2>

<p>I like to end my day at a distinct break between tasks. If my day ends at a point where something is incomplete, I’ll be sure to keep it in my to-do list for the following day, where I can come back to it. Before I leave my desk each day I’ll generally try and plan out what makes sense to cover (given the time I have) in the following working day. This allows me to hit the ground running each day, without any getting up to speed time first thing in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="track-your-time">Track Your Time</h2>

<p>Tracking my time is important not only for my client work, but also my own projects. As well as giving me exact totals for invoicing, it allows me to compare estimates against the reality of a project and all the unforeseen problems that may arise during the course of it. My time tracking is a simple project based on/off approach, where I use a <a href="http://hourglass.io">custom tool</a> I developed myself.</p>

<h2 id="eliminate-distractions">Eliminate Distractions</h2>

<p>Although obvious, trying to cut down on distractions pays dividends. Switch off tweetdeck, close skype and either disable notifications on your phone or (my favourite) put it out of your sight completely. I don’t tend to pay any thought to my phone if I can’t see it, and it’s like a nervous twitch to pick it up and check whether anything has happened in the last 5 mins. When not aware it’s an option, I probably get twice as much work done. It’s easy to kid yourself that checking devices like this is part of your work, but when at the detriment of your day’s schedule you need to switch off and focus on the bigger picture.</p>

<p>These are just a few measures I take to be more productive in my day - I’d welcome any tips other freelancers have for their own situations.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Shipping in March</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>This month, I’ve decided to take some time out to ship projects. </p>

<p>I have a huge list of projects accumulating I’d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.</p>

<p>Currently I don’t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we’ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released. </p>

<p>That sounds easy, but I’m well aware from past experience it isn’t. I don’t want to work outside of working hours (9-5.30pm) as I know the impact it has on my family. My hope is by setting myself some achievable goals I can at least get some way to ticking off some checkboxes on this growing todo list. </p>

<p>Some of these projects are products I’ve not yet completed, projects I’ve released but need work or ideas that haven’t made it to the build stage yet. As a freelancer, I hope that some of them may even help out other people in a similar situation to me.</p>

<p>Over the coming month, I’m going to attempt to ship at least 4 projects out of the door. 1 a week for 4 weeks. I’ll be blogging about my progress here, and posting summaries of how it went at the end of each week. The end date of the 28th is also my birthday, so it would be great present to myself to have come some way to meeting my goal.</p>

<p>If you’re interested in receiving progress updates via email, signup here: <a href="http://eepurl.com/PxGe9">http://eepurl.com/PxGe9</a></p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Second Rate Britizens</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I decided to attempt a simple app this week, first using <a href="http://gocardless.com">GoCardless</a>, then later the <a href="http://stripe.com">beta of Stripe</a>. It requires the payment of funds between two individuals, neither of which might be a business. GoCardless suggests signing up to use their <a href="https://gocardless.com/docs/partner_guide">partner programme</a>, which involves registering a user as a merchant. This isn’t entirely suitable given the individual will be asked many queries on the nature of their business (which they don’t have). Stripe have a similar offering, known as <a href="https://stripe.com/connect">“Connect”</a> which asks similar questions. It’s at this point users would probably start turning away.</p>

<p>The recently announced <a href="https://stripe.com/blog/send-payouts-with-stripe">“Payouts”</a> from Stripe, seems like the most appropriate solution, but it doesn’t yet exist in the UK (and it’ll probably be a while before it does). Bigger players like Amazon’s fps require that you have a US card and haven’t ever made noises that they may be expanding into European markets.</p>

<p>As developers in the UK, we get a bit of a bum deal. Software products are often first targeted towards the biggest (US) market and we fine folks have to sit around and wait until the smaller pieces of the puzzle are picked up and put in place. Sucks to be us.</p>

<p>I’ve blogged in the past about the many payment providers cropping up and their services being unavailable in the UK. I can understand why this happens, but it’s frustrating not least because it hinders any momentum that might be able to be built at an earlier date. </p>

<p>I doubt I’ll ever have the same momentum as I did with my idea this week. It’s unlikely therefore, it will ever see the light of day. A US counterpart could easily offer an international version of my idea today.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>So You Want to Run a Fairtrade Business?</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>This is a brief retrospective of what I’ve learned in the 6 years I’ve been running <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com" title="Fair &#038; Bare">Fair &#038; Bare</a>, a Fairtrade t-shirt company along with my wife. </p>

<p>If you’re a new follower of mine, you heard right – <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">I run a Fairtrade t-shirt company</a>. I’ve not actively been marketing it more recently for a number of reasons, but I still have a strong belief in our original vision. That vision was that Fairtrade shirts at the time weren’t being well received by the world, despite being available. We believed they could be, if we were only to find some that had good designs (and were possibly less ‘preachy’).</p>

<p>So that’s what we set out to do. From 2007-2011 we were running as an online design competition, inspired mainly by Threadless and Emptees, and helped via a great community of designers through a site I built entirely myself (whilst doing a PhD, getting married and buying a house). I’ve since learned that I don’t believe the competition sourced design is the best fit for what we are trying to do, but it constantly excited me that we *could* do it. I still hope some day to be proved wrong though.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h2>

<p>The Ethical market pales in comparison to the cheaper alternatives. That probably won’t come as news to you. Most people – like it or not, will buy cheap over quality if they’re perceived to be comparable. This has certainly been my experience so far, having touted our wares at student markets, Fairtrade stalls and online. Be prepared to experience it first hand, and to repeatedly go over your story to get people to part with their cash. That is, after all, your unique selling point.</p>

<p>While we’re at it, if you’re selling online, be prepared to experience the same. When so much hard work has gone into creating your goods, you’ll find it heartbreaking to have a couple of people take up an offer from a newsletter of thousands. My advice would be not to get your hopes up….</p>

<p>But don’t entirely despair. When you make those few sales you’ll feel such a strong connection with your customer, even though you may never meet them. Repeat customers will give you a warm glow inside and smile all day long.</p>

<p>The Fairtrade supply chain is slow(er) and (more) fallible. We constantly had trouble with every supplier we used for our shirts over how quickly we could obtain stock and sometimes with the stock itself. Obviously, once our community had selected a design, we wanted it printed and available for sale. We knew we would have to wait for designs to be printed, but what we hadn’t counted on was how long it could take to get hold of shirts we’d ordered. Other businesses might be able to cope better with such delays. 2 months to go from selected to online is not ideal for our business model that relies on constant momentum, especially when we were dealing with a a single product at a time. </p>

<p>Depending on your supplier, you may also experience variations in sizes and colour. Be wary, you’re going to have to deal with all the resulting issues that arise from these problems with your customers or be lumbered with stock you’re unable to shift.</p>

<p>Times are hard for everyone. Since having started, 2 of the 3 suppliers we used have shut up shop and the third has changed it’s supplier. This has drastically reduced the options for us to the point of being unviable, which is one of the reasons we haven’t put out a new design since 2011. (If anyone is able to point me in the direction of other wholesale ethical brands, I’d be keen to hear about them).</p>

<p>Fairtrade cotton, Fairtrade or fair trade? Organic? Soil association certified? You need to be aware of the differences, because competitors will use similar terms. Even though they mean different things to you, most customers don’t know the difference and lump them all in the same good for the producer pot.</p>

<p>First impressions count. Originally, we used to send out our t-shirts in recycled packaging we sourced from envelopes we had kicking around our house. I have to cringe at this now – the idea that old crumply packets were being received with sticky-taped-on labels. That was our first physical impression on our customer. *Sigh*. Our heart was in the right place though, we didn’t (and still don’t) want to be creating more waste. We’ve since moved on to shipping goods out in recycled packets.</p>

<p>Marketing is key. When you’re not marketing your goods, you’re not seen to be active. Just by talking about your business, you’ll get interest in your product and make sales. Our buzz came from regular competitions and launches of new shirts. With every new shirt we’d let our mailing list, community and followers know of its arrival.</p>

<p>Finally, a word on branding. I constantly wrestle with wether we would have been better off branding ourselves first and foremost a t-shirt design company, rather than a Fairtrade one. I think the answer is yes. Our whole ethos was originally based around the lack of well designed Fairtrade shirts. Ultimately, if a design looks good, a customer is going to be happy paying a little more if it’s what they want. The ethical aspect of the cotton is, in their mind, a bonus. But if they’re not even visiting your site or stall because they see you first and foremost as an ethical brand, and that doesn’t entirely float their boat, then you’ve lost a sale.</p>

<p>The whole experience of running <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> has been a bit of a roller coaster of highs and lows. I’ve learned so much from running it and hope to continue to do so.</p>

<p>It wouldn’t be right of me to post about <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> here without letting my readers in on a special offer. For this Easter weekend, when you buy two shirts, you’ll get the third free on using the code “EASTEREGG” when checking out.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair &#038; Bare &#8211; January £10 Sale!</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair-bare-january-10-sale</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair-bare-january-10-sale</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/fairandbare/images/banners/jansale.jpg" alt="£10 January Sale" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/7/my_own_personal_robot"><br />
<img src="http://www.fairandbare.com/images/shirts/7/1.jpg" alt="My Own Personal Robot" /><br />
</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/6/the_red_sparrows"><img src="http://www.fairandbare.com/images/shirts/6/1.jpg" alt="The Red Sparrows" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> &#8211; The little shop I run (with a little help from my wife) is having a January Sale right now in celebration of entering the year 2010. Every shirt we&#8217;ve made to date is just 10 squid! Hurry up people, it only runs until Sunday.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2009-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what’s going on over at <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a> and if you’re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I’ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what’s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</p>

<p>We’re holding our <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/challenge/fairytales">second design challenge</a> right now and calling for designs based around the concept of a unique twist on a fairy tale. The prize is our biggest ever, at £200 + a copy of Adobe Photoshop CS3 (which was kindly donated by one of F&#038;B’s community!). You have until 15th February to both submit a design and get it voted on by the F&#038;B peeps!</p>

<p>It looks like I’ve also failed to mention over here the winner of our Snowdodgers competition as the amazing <a href="http://www.mistershrew.co.uk">Mister Shrew</a>. The shirts we printed look amazing and you should pick one up now if you haven’t already.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/challenge/fairytales"><img alt="" src="http://www.fairandbare.com/images/challenges/fairy_challenge.gif" title="Fair &#038; Bare - Fairy Tale Design Challenge" class="alignnone" width="398" height="300" /></a></p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair &#038; Bare Snowdodgers Challenge</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair-bare-snowdodgers-challenge</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair-bare-snowdodgers-challenge</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Yesterday I announced that we’re running our <a href="http://fairandbare.com/challenge/snowdodgers">first design challenge</a> in conjunction with <a href="http://snowdodgers.co.uk">team Snowdodgers</a> at <a href="http://www.fairandbare.com">Fair &#038; Bare</a>. These are some really amazing fellas who are trying to raise £48,000 for charity by rallying a £200 banger round 4000 miles involving the Arctic circle. We’re asking designers to get in designs relating to the chilly weather and the guys crazy antics!</p>

<p>If you’re interested, you’ve got just a month to get an entry in. You’ll win £100 plus a space on the rally car for your design!</p>

<p>Check out <a href="http://fairandbare.com/challenge/snowdodgers">the challenge page</a> for full details of how to enter!</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair and Bare&#8217;s first shirt!</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>So, its been a long time coming, but Fair and Bare&#8217;s first t-shirt is now available to purchase!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/view/1/tree_huggin"><br />
<img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/fairandbare/images/banners/shop_banner.jpg" alt="Tree Huggin'" /><br />
</a></p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who&#8217;s participated since we kicked off. Really appreciate all your designs, words and support. We&#8217;re still taking submissions for our competitions, so if you haven&#8217;t hit us up already make sure you do!</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair and Bare &#8211; Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I’m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with <a href="http://fairdos.com">fairdos</a> and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don’t appeal to us at all. Some of these friends are people who are right up there within prominent fairtrade companies, who although avid promoters, won’t wear fairtrade on a day to day basis if it means they have to sacrifice their style. It seems that the fairtrade companies don’t do design and so we’re not given a choice between two similar products. The end result is we’re faced with looking great and feeling a little discontent that the garment isn’t as fantastic as it could be, or feeling great about a product – but not looking so awesome. We’ve often spoken of beginning a fairtrade company that puts out clothing that is both ethically produced and well designed, but held off doing so because it felt a little beyond us. I can say here now that we’ve made the first step in bringing that vision a little closer.</p>

<p><a href="http://fairandbare.com">Fair and Bare</a> is a crowdsourcing project which pays out comission to designers who successfully produce t shirt design ideas for fairtrade t shirts. It’s also an attempt for the fairtrade community to lose that somewhat ‘serious face’ with which I think they are often associated and relax the shoulders a bit whilst having some fun. We’re currently offering £200 for designs and £50 for design ideas which we think are worth printing up onto fairtrade cotton. We then hope to offer shirts at a somewhat more accessible price than other fairtrade shirts. It’s a fun, small project at the moment, but I hope that we can help rejuvinate an otherwise awesome product and maybe inspire others to do the same.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>