<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: marine parade</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Stick to your guns &#8211; You&#8217;ll be rewarded</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’m a firm believer that by upholding my own principles, I’ll be rewarded. It’s a tag line I adopted for the <a href="http://www.xen10.com">small hosting company</a> that I’ve been running for a while now. It also has been reflected this year in a nasty situation I was left in with my landlords, the council and a previous housemate (who doesn’t really deserve that title, more just a person whom shared the house). In all these situations things have turned out better for me in the long run, due to myself re-enforcing what I believe should be done – even if it does mean a longer struggle through.</p>

<p>Today, one of my favourite breaks record labels (Marine Parade) were offering a compo to win a cd by responding to them over myspace. (Ok, maybe a somewhat less grandiose scenario than this post may have made out, but still!) I’ve long refused to sign up to myspace out of principles (it looks bloody awful, mainly) so I sent them a message to point it out:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As much as I’d like to respond to get the cd via myspace, I feel I shouldn’t have to be forced to use that poor excuse for an interweb page.</p>

  <p>Anyway, here is my address just in case you feel like sending me Adam Freelands – Tectonics.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>To my joy, they didn’t care!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>fair enough, you get one! </p>
</blockquote>

<p>I don’t think I’ve ever won a competition due to principles. Maybe I should start bending the rules of other competitions and still try to win prizes?</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>