<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2005/03 on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/</link><description>Recent content in 2005/03 on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Birthday</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</guid><description>Well, thats another year over and done with, on to the next. Unfortunately, due to the distinct lack of friends available at Cardiff or at home, it kinda all just happened, and is almost over. I went out for an romantic italian with Tim and Mark on Friday, featuring a couple of very grumpy waitresses. I had hopes to move on later on to bsb with people, but Tim was knackered from returning from a week of training and Mark wanted to save his efforts for the Easter Service on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Birthday Blues</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</guid><description>I’m trying to decide what to do for my birthday which falls on Bank holiday monday this year. Currently I’m of the mind to do something on Good Friday like have a meal, then off to town (Chico Fresco and Phantom Beats will be at bsb apparently)….Leaving me free to go back and have easter and my actual birthday with family and friends. I’m going to be 24…24,24?!, no surely thats not right!</description></item><item><title>Lemon Jelly</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</guid><description>I was a right little Heathen yesterday and skived off of housegroup to meet up with Mr Bryer in Bristol to see the awesome Lemon Jelly. Whats even better was the fact that Ben Lilford had come along too, unbeknown to me before arriving. They are quite literally the most amusing band ever. Prior to the Jel’s entrance we were treated to Don Partridge (a one man band) whilst trying to play a couple of party games (find 3 stooges hidden in the audience).</description></item><item><title>Oops</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</guid><description>Ok, not to totally contradict my last post, I’ve just read a comedy web page all about me that was put up 5 years ago which I never knew existed! You might like to take a look here. It seems my music tastes haven’t changed all that much, as the songs I quote are all still top tunes…I may of gotten all technical for no reason.</description></item></channel></rss>