<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introvert Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</guid>
      <description>You pay for your ticket, hotels, travel and then spend the rest of the year excitedly awaiting being able to attend the conference everyone is speaking about. Having travelled halfway across the country, braving weather you&amp;#8217;d never ordinarily leave the house for, you arrive in the unrecognisable city. You&amp;#8217;ve left your family to be here, which is heart wrenching at the best of times and your lonely hotel room is no comfort (especially given the number of beds it has).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/02/2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/02/2012/</guid>
      <description>So here we are in a brand new year. 2012 came and went without even the slightest apocalypse. Reflecting on what has been achieved this past year has found favour with others in the web profession so I thought I might try it. More importantly to me, it also seems like a good way to perhaps spur me on to achieve some firm targets this year.
My circumstances have dramatically changed since January last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate, Don’t Preach</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</guid>
      <description>Last week, tickets went on sale for dConstruct 2011 and sold out within an impressive 7 hours. Having attended in 2010 and 2008 and judging it to be filled with the highest calibre web celebs from across the globe, I coughed up the entrance fee as part of the excited gold-rush. The cost of £150 includes access to the pre and after parties and the conference itself.
These type of events are stuffed to the brim with amazing, intelligent web professionals, many of whom I would consider to be colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>