<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2009/01 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2009/01 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Music Blogs getting a Raw Deal?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;#8217;t help but feel a little sorry for music blogs as of late. I&amp;#8217;m sure you may be familiar with The Hype Machine and may use it on a daily basis. For the uninitiated, it is essentially a music blog aggregator, which takes details of tracks and ranks them based on how often they appear and how popular they are. I&amp;#8217;ve found it really interesting to browse around and discover new artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I have to contribute?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>It has struck me over the last couple of days and it&amp;#8217;s a reflection of my attitude to being interested in geeky things in general. I&amp;#8217;m an elitist. When I started my blog back in 2003, I loved the fact that relatively few of them existed. It was a reflection of my day to day life and I felt my voice was being heard (even though I had no analytics tools to back that up and it was not particularly interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</guid>
      <description>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what&amp;#8217;s going on over at Fair &amp;#038; Bare and if you&amp;#8217;re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I&amp;#8217;ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what&amp;#8217;s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>