<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: faith</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Encouragement</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I cleaned out one of the boxes of papers kicking around my room the other evening. In it, I found an old lunch pass from school (featuring a photo sporting a lovely little version of me) and lots of old encouragement sheets we used to pass around our youth group to gets lots of positive comments on ourselves. Most of these are at least 5 years old and some stretch back to 10. Here are a few of my favourites. If you’re an old mate, you might find something you’ve written. I particularly love the one about being “reasonably safe”. 
*   Ian, you are without a doubt the next Paul Merton. How you reel so many classic witty lines I don’t know, but could you tell cos I wanna be like you.
*   Dry sense of humour that makes me wet my pants. Stay cool.
*   Lord of the one-line. No messin with Ian.
*   Hey man, you’re fantastic – Your sense of humour so dry, but so refreshing. Love Ya.
*   God loves you sooooo much, just believe it. You are a well loved person by us all, you are so caring to others. Bless your legs.
*   A good team mat.
*   NICE ARSE. You’re a honey, my phone number is *<strong>*</strong>*.
*   Ian, you’re fantastic. You’re such a good bloke and are always making me laugh. Your faithfulness to God is really cool and its been great seeing you grow in him this last year or two. May God keep blessing you in your life and in your music. Thanks for being a cool friend.
*   You’re fat and you know you are.
*   Ian – nice bloke – fun and reasonably safe.
*   Chuckle…how odd. Makes me want to giggle like an insane fool.
*   Lovely hands!
*   Makes me laugh, especially when things don’t go to plan.
*   He’s a “SMOOTH OPERATOR” and one of my best mates, great to talk to.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Introducing&#8230;</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It’s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I’d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she’d brave the border as well to make those “all important” first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</p>

<p>I got to see all my fabulous pals as well as witness the dedication of Jase and Stephs daughter Eden at the service on Sunday with lots of fireworks type “ooh’s and ahh’s” from the elderly members to express her cuteness. As a gesture of thanks, the Helyars bought everyone there a doughnut, putting my previous contributions to Vineyard somewhat to shame.</p>

<p>After a detour to clarks village with Paul tagging along (after a number of bump starts – remember to keep the keys in the ignition mate), we made it back to Cardiff and headed off to see the amazing Prodigy. I was so tired by now it was ridiculous, I used to remember home as a quiet place, it didn’t seem to be the case this visit but still somehow managed to roll up at the CIA. The warm up act (Audio Bully’s) really sucked big time, and it was quite amusing to hear the roar as the first track from the dj’s came on afterwards. Anyway, after feeling suitably psyched, Paul, I and the large group in the bit that formed around us spent the next 2 hours going mental to all the classics, without a black eye in sight. Lot’s of fond childhood memories came flooding back of music sharing in Pauls living room. Twas brill it twas.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Millions of Wrongs don&#8217;t Make it Right</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I’d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it’s quite the opposite really.</p>

<p>My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it’s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase. If you download or copy cd’s with no intention of rewarding those who created it with payment of some way shape or form, I’m sorry, I really can’t see it as a good thing. You might argue that fat cats mark up media with artificially high prices, with little going to the original artists, but it’s untrue for the most part (there are a huge number of people involved in producing most albums) and goes a short way as to why you should award those artists with no payment whatsoever…these artists do after all sign contracts and know what they’re getting themselves into for the most part.</p>

<p>Admittedly, there are occasions where my opinions blur. In the case of mix cd’s, I see the cd as a showcase for the DJ’s mixing skills, as well as those songs upon it, so I’d quite happily download mixes from the net. If there is a good track within, I’ll add it to my collection anyway, the majority of the dance music scene seems to encourage these methods anyway – getting their artists to produce mixes and distribute them online so people buy the bare, unmixed, tracks. It gets really messy with the issue of sampling – I’m not even going there….</p>

<p>What’s a little more scary, is the attitude Christians take to piracy. I’ve known in the past Christians quite happily pirating software worth thousands to produce albums or websites for projects in the Church, with little or no concern for what they’re doing. Surely there’s something wrong there – making Church websites with stolen software? The majority of the time its simply not necessary for the tasks in hand either, there are other ways of achieving the results in a more ethical way. (Ask me if you want to know how)… I’m probably more sensitive in this area, due to the fact I create software myself.</p>

<p>I was really disturbed when I first got into sharing applications as a teenager at the volume of Christian music available, Delerious, Redman, Jars of Clay, you want it its there…it seems we’re just as bad as the rest of the world here. The Gospel Music Association even has the stats to <a href="http://www.cmta.com/research.htm" title="GMA">prove it</a>. The Bible calls for us to ‘abide by the laws of the land’ because such authorities ‘have been established by God’ (Romans 13:1-7) – if we’re going against them we’re going against God. I can’t see that laws for copyrighting music, films go against what God says, so really we have no reason for being so lax in this department.</p>

<p>I was reading a book called the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/exec/obidos/ASIN/0851112587/qid%3D1122935165/026-6844478-8087659" title="Amazon">Net Commandments</a> back along which describes how easy technology has made it for us to sin (or cybersin – but that sounds like you need a peripheral). Not only this, but its also removed a large majority of the barriers which have been in place which otherwise may have presented us from sinning. I’d love to see some of us going into Virgin and using our MD to record the album we’re sampling at the listening point, it’d never happen.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>How far have I come?</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Having free time in the evenings recently is a wonderful thing, and its given me the chance to think about ‘stuff’ I might not of done otherwise, recently its been my undergrad life. When I came to University, I was all fired up for an amazing walk through Christendom, I tried to throw myself into the Christian Union, and for a while it was great. Unfortunately my work got a grip of me very quickly, and for all the wrong reasons I backed off from CU and any kind of fellowship with others. I didn’t really settle at any Church well here and the year I spent at home made it even worse by becoming more disjointed from my Cardiff life….</p>

<p>I got my degree, and a good one at that, but I can’t help but think I put myself through hell (this time last year was awful for me) for absolutely zero benefit over what could have been. I know I’ve been taken down this path for a reason and while I might think there wasn’t anything going on, the whole experience is a lesson in discipline in itself.</p>

<p>Changing churches and attending a housegroup this year has been great, I’ve made some fantastic friends and its pushed me forward in ways I wouldn’t of thought possible, building me (and I hope others) up with far more on the horizon. Anyway, suffice to say reflecting on this hasn’t been great for me this week, but I’ve also felt encouraged by a few words I’ve been given of late about my character…trying to be a little more confident and forthcoming about my feelings, due to my unique slant on the world.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Vineyard reclaiming the web</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2004-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Cardiff Vineyard have got to be the biggest bunch of bloggers I’ve ever met, in a non-derogitory sense. Makes a change to Yeovil Community Church. Browsing around their main site and links from it, I’ve found, hmm, lets see:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.cardiffvineyard.org/cvblog2.html" title="Cardiff Vineyards blog">Cardiff Vineyard</a><br />
<a href="http://freelancetheology.typepad.com/">Jon Matthias</a><br />
<a href="http://helsc.blogspot.com/" title="Hels' Blog">Helen Carslaw</a><br />
<a href="http://www.lewisparfitt.com/blog.html" title="Lewis Parfitts blog">Lewis Parfitt</a><br />
<a href="http://www.cardiffvineyard.org/neil.html" title="Neil Morgan's Blog">Neil Morgan</a><br />
<a href="http://icklemissmo.blogspot.com/" title="Zo&euml; Morgan's Blog">Zoë Morgan</a><br />
<a href="http://sarahloumoo.blogspot.com/" title="Sarah Lou's Blog">Sarah-Louise</a></p>

<p>Thats crazy….! – We’ve got say 25 ppl max when I’ve gone along, so thats over a 5th turned blogging converts. There are more, but I’ve not actually met them, or if I have I’ve not remembered their names! Quite reassuring to know that systems such as the one I did for my dissertation are being used out there. I expect YCC has like 5 people blogging in some shape or form, yet the Church is maybe 10 – 20 times that size. Talk about cutting edge…..</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Family Fun</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2003-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve just got back from my Churches “family fun” event. They have been doing a whole bunch of different events this week as an opportunity to witness to those who might not normally come to YCC otherwise. Today was the big finale of the week and was basically all the families who had been a part of the week meeting up with the members of the Church.</p>

<p>What that amounts to is lots of barbeques and little kiddies events galore. I think most people appreciated the afternoon and the weather has been really nice as well.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>