<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Metalsmith</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2015/06/30/blogging-with-metalsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2015/06/30/blogging-with-metalsmith/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m switching blogging platforms once more. Moving from Wordpress to Jekyll enabled me to no longer deal with the multitude of updates and protected me hacks I could be susceptible to, but Jekyll being written in Ruby (a language I&amp;rsquo;m not overly familiar with) has been a problem. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to cobble together scripts to deal with the custom parts of my blog build, but it&amp;rsquo;s never felt like home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a Linear Domain to an Ordinal Range with d3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had the opportunity of using d3 quite a lot over the past few months for a number of clients. It offers some amazing flexibility for chart generation and much more.
Anyway, I thought I’d share a quick tip I developed for mapping a linear set of values onto an ordinal scale. For those who’re seasoned pros at d3, this probably seems trivial, but had me stumped for some time today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Full Stack JS Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</guid>
      <description>Whilst node.js heralded an era of being able to use a single language for both server and client side development, nobody mentioned the confusion such an approach could cause. It’s inevitable that there’s going to be similarities in code that constructs data on the server and that which presents it on the client. The fact that the two are written in the same language and the structure of them is so tightly coupled can make it easy to lose track of where you are and what you’re doing when knee deep in code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up Relationships with CouchDB</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/01/breaking-up-relationships-with-couchdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/01/breaking-up-relationships-with-couchdb/</guid>
      <description>[NB: This is an unpublished post I wrote in 2010 on getting started with CouchDB. Therefore, despite all the code and examples being relevant, it may be considered somewhat &amp;lsquo;belated&amp;rsquo;]
Beware – there’s a bunch of home wreckers out there intent on removing the love of your life and replacing it with a wicked mistress.
For me, my first experiments working with databases were performed with Oracle, the staple of our computer science course at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Choose Popular Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>I feel compelled to write this post so late in the day after clocking Tyler Renelle’s rant on github about his problems with the popularity of certain JS frameworks (in the main Backbone.js). After having written apps in a variety of JS frameworks (Backbone, Spine and Meteor), I’ve learned that the feature set of a framework is not the only thing I hold dear when making a choice between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Crap, I&#39;m a Frontend Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</guid>
      <description>When I was first tiptoeing in the waters of web development (early 2000′s), getting a grips on job descriptions was simple. There were 2 types of people in our industry: designers or developers. You either drew websites, or you built websites – that was it.
As time went on people seemed to invent new titles: “UX Designers” were the first to appear on the scene to me, and we’re still to this day figuring out what this role really entails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagination in CouchDB Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/11/02/pagination-in-couchdb-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/11/02/pagination-in-couchdb-apps/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on some fun little node.js / couchdb projects of late. Given the fact I don’t use either as part of my work, I’ve spent some downtime experimenting and slowly iterating my approaches as I learn best practice.
I hit what I consider to be a fairly frustrating hurdle that couchdb threw up that I’ve been blissfully unaware of through all my couchdb dev. When it came to doing pagination it turns out I’ve always been doing it the “bad” way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining References to Sockets with Express and Socket.io</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/04/maintaining-references-to-sockets-with-express-and-socket-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/04/maintaining-references-to-sockets-with-express-and-socket-io/</guid>
      <description>I hit a frustrating problem when trying to use expressjs alongside socket.io recently. The solution may seem somewhat trivial, but I struggled with it for a while, until finally asking for help on the socket.io irc channel. I’m not sure if a better solution exists for my case, but this is what I have for now.
In the main route of my express app, I needed to iterate across an array, performing a REST call using each element as a parameter and spit the results back for socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog rolling with CouchDB, Express and Node.js</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/02/07/blog-rolling-with-couchdb-express-and-node-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/02/07/blog-rolling-with-couchdb-express-and-node-js/</guid>
      <description>Over the last little while, I’ve been doing a lot of playing with Node.js, mostly to run data collection scripts. Last week, I started following Ciaran Jessup’s tutorial on getting started with node.js, Express and mongoDB. Express acts as a framework to node.js, allowing you to work in a familiar mvc format in a not so familar server side language. I hit a few problems along the way in the tutorial, so I thought I’ve list a few of my findings here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Learning jQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
