<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scientist in an Adventure with Pirates</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</guid>
      <description>This is a talk I did back in May at unifieddiff about my time working as a web developer at Aardman Features. I talk quite a bit about the production process and what we take from staff in order to help them do their jobs properly. I quite enjoyed giving this talk &amp;#8211; more so than those I&amp;#8217;ve given in an academic capacity in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2012 - Self Help for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>Last week, like many others working on the web, I took the trip to Nottingham for New Adventures 2012. I&amp;#8217;d seen the wonderful praise dished out for it last year and felt like I wanted to see what it was all about first hand.
I&amp;#8217;ve learnt from experience that the most important part of any conference is not the talks or speakers involved, but the community around it and therefore I headed up the night before to ensure I didn&amp;#8217;t miss a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate, Don’t Preach</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</guid>
      <description>Last week, tickets went on sale for dConstruct 2011 and sold out within an impressive 7 hours. Having attended in 2010 and 2008 and judging it to be filled with the highest calibre web celebs from across the globe, I coughed up the entrance fee as part of the excited gold-rush. The cost of £150 includes access to the pre and after parties and the conference itself.
These type of events are stuffed to the brim with amazing, intelligent web professionals, many of whom I would consider to be colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How not to: Do A Hack Day</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s been well over a month since I attended science hack day and I&amp;#8217;d thought I&amp;#8217;d put out some notes on my time there. Rather than do a run down of the event, for which I&amp;#8217;m sure there&amp;#8217;s far more comprehensive blog posts available already, I thought I&amp;#8217;d share my experiences based on attendance of a number of different hack events I&amp;#8217;ve been to over the years. I went with the full intention of doing some hardcore hacking, but didn&amp;#8217;t entirely meet my own expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Web Meetup #3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to remind people that this coming week is the third Cardiff meetup for web types in wales. It&amp;#8217;s in 10 Feet Tall on Church St on Wednesday 4th June from 6.30pm. Featured speakers include Matthew Cashmore (Development Producer for BBC Future Media &amp;#038; Technology, Research and Innovation) and Tim Holmes (Course co-ordinator for the Postgraduate Diploma in Magazine Journalism and the MA International Journalism: Magazine Pathway at Cardiff University&amp;#8217;s School of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Cardiff Geek Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiff geeks will be having its first ever face to face on Wednesday 17th October from 7pm at Cafe Floyd, just opposite the castle. Props to Dan Zambonini for organising the venue.
This is an informal, introduction between us all. If you&amp;#8217;re a geek, or interested in chatting with us about what we and you are passionate about, make sure you get over there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</guid>
      <description>Yes, yes I know I already posted about the FOWA Roadtrip in Bristol, but I live in Cardiff and have friends and colleagues in Bristol too. I promise I didn&amp;#8217;t just head there for free drinks once again. This time the Carson Systems team had pulled together some funky little FOWA Roadtrip badges that they handed out on the door, rather than the stickers at Bristol. I&amp;#8217;d previously learned that Ryan&amp;#8217;s wife, Gillian had taken a MSc in Cardiff and it seems the same is true of Lisa Price too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my &amp;#8220;business&amp;#8221; cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; on hand hand-made ones or something&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Geeks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve long wondered why there doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be much happening in terms of community of the web professionals in wales. There is a vibrant collection of people sporting different skill sets in the area, yet as I can see not a lot of chat amongst everyone in between different groups. On a whim, I decided to create a facebook group &amp;#8220;Cardiff Web Geeks&amp;#8221; to try and get people to come out of their shells and actually participate in a bit of discussion about tech topics in wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Bristol</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday evening I had the pleasure of meeting up with a bunch of fellow geeks and web peeps over in Bristol as part of Ryan Carsons Future of Web Applications Roadtrip. It was a bit of a crazy evening, with me stuck in Cardiff for the best part of two hours prior to leaving. This was due to a &amp;#8220;large fire&amp;#8221; in Newport which was smoking out the rail line so the fire brigade shut everything down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re off to see the Hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</guid>
      <description>The wonderful hackers of, er Britain. When I say we, I actually mean me because my wife to be has to head back to Abergavenny before me. Which means that actually I&amp;#8217;ll be the only one able to make use of my free invite to see the rumble strips. Oh well.I&amp;#8217;m actually a bit nervy about heading over &amp;#8211; I have done an extreme lack of preparation in terms of programming and I&amp;#8217;m going to be sleeping in a room full of nerds and pcs, or possibly not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Developer Day</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just returned from my stint in the South East after being invited to attend Googles London Developer day on thursday and remaining there to hang out in Haddenham for the weekend. Theres a ton of photo&amp;#8217;s over on a picasa web album which has been built up from peoples pics. I even got interviewed regarding using the google web toolkit, but my experience was not exactly extended so I don&amp;#8217;t know if it would get used at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay for Hackday!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</guid>
      <description>I just heard I&amp;#8217;ve got invited to Hackday! That&amp;#8217;s totally awesome, I&amp;#8217;m really excited! I signed up half expecting to be told to &amp;#8220;go jump&amp;#8221; and I&amp;#8217;d contacted the administrators of the list due to hearing nothing about it and some confusing responses at first &amp;#8211; but I just got my proper invite. Woo! &amp;#8211; Impressive as I didn&amp;#8217;t put much of an explanation of my work on there. I guess it was my sob story about my ongoing PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>