<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/05 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/05 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Same Old, Same Old</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a fair while, I&amp;#8217;ve been getting jip off of people about not writing, but to be honest, there&amp;#8217;s not exactly been a lot happening in my neck of the woods which is all that exciting. I&amp;#8217;ve pooled everything I can remember from the last two weeks and bunged them into one post&amp;#8230;
Sat 14th &amp;#8211; Featured a grandma squashing her child by clipping her foot on a paving slab on albany junction and falling straight onto him whilst carrying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put on a brave face</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been feeling a bit off today &amp;#8211; maybe its the fact I had to cook dinner amidst housemates washing up at like 8:30pm yesterday, I had my wall banged on by neighbours last night due to noisy Tim (he has a gig soon so can be forgiven), or couldn&amp;#8217;t get to sleep last night again for the same reason, radiators blaring and a noisy neighbour party or maybe its because I had to wait around forever at home today to collect a parcel from the Royal Snail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academia</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had the fairly bizarre experience this week of attending the CCGrid 05 conference at city hall. This is my first conference and by all means a first introduction to my peers outside of the group involved with the PASOA project I am working upon. I think the most interesting thing is how normal each of them actually are &amp;#8211; I was expecting them all to have some sort of superiority complex for some reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Week</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had a really great week this week, mainly due to spending a large majority of it with the wonderful Matthias&amp;#8217;s and crew. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if this was altogether intentional, but it was great however it happened. I enjoy the crazy banter, furious sarcasm and witty jokes which are often made at others expense&amp;#8230;.
Monday we spent the day at Jon and Cathy&amp;#8217;s eating and playing board games due to the unfortunate weather that occurred outside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>