<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2007/01 on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/</link><description>Recent content in 2007/01 on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hotdealsuk - Indexing the webs best deals</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</guid><description>I came across hotdealsukprior to christmas and I think its an absolute must for any techie thats currently residing in the uk. Basically, a sophisticated messageboard, bargains of interest to the community are highlighted and then voted upon. Those more highly voted make it through to the front page.
I absolutely love it and so far have managed to purchase 1 xbox (with 4 games) @ £50 and a 400Gb harddrive @ £83.</description></item><item><title>Future of Web Apps, Future of Web Design</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</guid><description>If anyone would like to contribute to allow me to attend the Future of Web Apps or the Future of Web Design conferences over the next few months, I’d put together some independent reviews of the events on this site. As the funds of a lowly research student are not all that much cop, you can donate some funds using the donation page.At the moment, registration for Web Apps is £195 + VAT (£595 + VAT including workshops), and Web Design is £59 +VAT.</description></item><item><title>MS Firefox</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</guid><description>Microsoft and Firefox have joined to bring us MSFirefox. Finally Microsoft have seen the light.</description></item><item><title>Today is not a good day to cycle!</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</guid><description>Richmond road in Cardiff today is pretty much like a river all the way down today, due to all the horrid weather hitting it, resulting in the following set of footprints (post cycling to work) around my office.</description></item><item><title>Why can't every day be a holiday?</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</guid><description>I had a some great times away on holidays recently. The first was at New Year in Rhayader with the usual suspects getting absolutely soaked and vowing never to let anyone else plan a walk ever again. It was good to get outside away from these pesky machines.
As if that wasn’t enough, I went away to France to the slightly more exciting Alps for a skiing holiday for a week too.</description></item></channel></rss>