<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Cinema According to Lovefilm</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</guid>
      <description>Given there&amp;#8217;s a bit of lovefilm bashing going on in Wales at the moment, I thought I&amp;#8217;d chime in with the most frustrating thing I found with communications from lovefilm.
Check out the following weekly email I used to receive (I&amp;#8217;ve since unsubscribed), along with my annotations.

I really couldn&amp;#8217;t care less about who lovefilm are sending into cinema&amp;#8217;s to perform reviews and certainly don&amp;#8217;t want it to be the first text I see in relation to that image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2012 - Self Help for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>Last week, like many others working on the web, I took the trip to Nottingham for New Adventures 2012. I&amp;#8217;d seen the wonderful praise dished out for it last year and felt like I wanted to see what it was all about first hand.
I&amp;#8217;ve learnt from experience that the most important part of any conference is not the talks or speakers involved, but the community around it and therefore I headed up the night before to ensure I didn&amp;#8217;t miss a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare&#39;s first shirt!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a long time coming, but Fair and Bare&amp;#8217;s first t-shirt is now available to purchase!

Thanks to everyone who&amp;#8217;s participated since we kicked off. Really appreciate all your designs, words and support. We&amp;#8217;re still taking submissions for our competitions, so if you haven&amp;#8217;t hit us up already make sure you do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare - Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</guid>
      <description>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I&amp;#8217;m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with fairdos and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don&amp;#8217;t appeal to us at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my &amp;#8220;business&amp;#8221; cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; on hand hand-made ones or something&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pMachine changes its name</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</guid>
      <description>pMachine has changed its name to Ellislab, and are sporting a shiny new website for all to see. The reason for the change is the expansion over the last 6 years to encompass products which don&amp;#8217;t fall under the same banner now. I&amp;#8217;m glad to see that the CodeIgniter website has got a facelift. 31three did the hard graft on the design and they all look awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>