<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a New M1 Mac for Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</guid>
      <description>I recently updated my 2012 Mac Mini with a 2021 M1 Mac Mini and decided to document the first time setup process. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up. What follows is all the steps in written form as a handy reference for you to copy and paste from - or future me. Surprisingly, the installation process was fairly simple now there are versions of software written for Apples new architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy a Django App to the DigitalOcean App Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</guid>
      <description>Digitalocean recently launched their App platform, a platform as a service (PaaS) which can be seen as a competitor to the likes of Heroku. As a Python developer, I wanted to see how easy it was to deploy a django app to App platform. It took me a little while to configure everything correctly so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go through some of the points that tripped me up here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for some time for a relatively simple method for deploying my projects, but I also want to use a pattern where my repo is the primary source of truth for my app.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
