<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Threadless launches Threadlesskids.com</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</guid><description>Threadless has launched threadlesskids.com – like threadless, but for kids. I suppose that should come in handy for Jake and Shondis recent announcement. Anyway, it looks wicked – its amazing how the kids stuff costs more than adult though! My friends told me kids are expensive.</description></item><item><title>TechcrunchUK Non-Pantomime Continues</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</guid><description>Apparently, according to the free English dictionary there is a couple of definitions other than the traditional UK understanding of the word pantomime. For those international readers who don’t know, a pantomime is a pretty awful example of B-List celebrities acting ability in the UK in which involves them dressing up in bad costumes and acting out a fairy tale or story. In Cardiff, the big panto is Jack and the Giant Beanstalk – where Jack is played by John Barrowman (or Captain Jack from Torchwood and Dr Who).</description></item><item><title>Digg gets Video and Podcasts</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</guid><description>Digg.com is sporting the ability to be able to now rate online video and podcasts. Postcast searching is in limited beta for registered users only.I just spent a while perusing some items of interest, and found a great segment of play! over on google. This just builds on the fact that Mario has the most awesome music ever.The searching of podcasts is dangerously close to an idea I’ve currently working on myself for a while now.</description></item><item><title>Sam Sethi has Nowhere to Blog?</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</guid><description>It seems, according to Ben Metcalfe, that Sam Sethi has had his typepad account disabled by Six Apart, rendering him unable to post any updates on his recent departure from TechcrunchUK. Loic Le Meur (Executive Vice President of Six Apart and General Manager of Europe, Middle East and Africa) is currently giving no information about the whole scenario upon his own blog.UPDATE: Apparently Sam Sethi’s blog is up and running, though he has to yet confirm this and post his take on the whole scenario.</description></item><item><title>Sam Sethi is sacked from Techcrunch UK</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</guid><description>Techcrunch UK, Techcrunch’s european sister site has recently had a lot of activiity from some notes which the editor at the time, Sam Sethi made about the recent leweb3 event.This invited some comments from Six Apart’s Loic Le Meur in which he called Sam “an asshole”. Sam subsequently posted another blog about the fact that TechcrunchUK would be setting up its own events and workshops in the forthcoming year. It seems this displeased techcrunch’s Mike Arrington enough to give Sam the boot.</description></item><item><title>Does Threadless rule or not?</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</guid><description>Last night I perused a number of articles describing the success of my favourite t-shirt store threadless, the first of which – over at 37Signals reviews in a positive light and the second in a more negative one.Threadless is a t-shirt company with a difference, it’s a 24-7 competition allow you to become the designer. Designs are chosen by the team, and are able to be rated by the community that operates around the website.</description></item><item><title>Future of Web Applications - London 07</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</guid><description>Registration is open for the Future of Web Apps conference in London 07. I’d love to go, loads of great companies/people talking (good to see Last.fm making an appearance), loads of schmoozing (if thats the appropriate word), but unfortunately absolutely jack to do with my PhD, so no funding.</description></item><item><title>Carson Systems shows us the money</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</guid><description>Carson Systems is showing the details of how dropsend stacks up in terms of monthly profit. Ryan states that at a conservative estimate by December ’07, it’ll be making $21k/mo. He also seems to be beating off a bit of bad feedback on the advertising which has/hasn’t been done.</description></item><item><title>DropSend is up for sale</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</guid><description>Carson Systems DropSend has recently been put up for sale by Ryan Carson. He states that currently they don’t have enough time to give it the attention it deserves, although the application is profitable with customers accumulating month by month.DropSend allows users to email huge files to one another via uploading them to dropsend and sending an email to the reciever to detail where it can be collected from. It’s quite interesting as the costs involved in its building are quite detailed within Ryans talk at a previous Future of Web Apps conference (also broken down here at 37 signals).</description></item></channel></rss>