<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/06 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/06 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Mental</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</guid>
      <description>Today I travelled on 2 planes, 3 buses and 1 car (thats a full house and extra) to make the 800 mile round trip to Edinburgh for part of a BioDiveristyWorld conference. I&amp;#8217;m quite surprised I managed to organise and sort out everything since Monday and it go according to plan.
I was actually really overwhelmed at how amazing the place was for the brief time I was there, the sheer scale of the city was something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writers Block</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to write a classic quote I found in &amp;#8216;Boy&amp;#8217; while I was away so I thought I&amp;#8217;d shove it up now. I think it encompasses how I feel about work at the moment. Really enjoyed just lazing about reading in France for ages, finished Pi, although I found it to drag on somewhat, the quirky bit at the end made it fairly clever. Onto some Pratchett now after resisiting for ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normality Check</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</guid>
      <description>Our last day in Jard was rather less exciting than we&amp;#8217;d hoped, we decided to clean the place* we were staying in, so spent the morning doing that and unfortunately the weather was cack so didn&amp;#8217;t make for much of an afternoon either. We apparently caught the back end of a heatwave this week which has been rather fortunate, although pretty uncomfortable in the evenings. (Tim had it worse being in the same room as Mr &amp;#8216;Exorcist&amp;#8217; Pete, I had to endure that in Germany so it&amp;#8217;s his turn this time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastis and Miniatures - 22/06/2005 - 23/06/2005</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday not a lot happened, except for much reading and bumming around the house whilst trying out my newly found juggling skills. We also went on our search for pastis, after discovering that it actually tasted much the same as oizo, a wicked aniseed flavour&amp;#8230;I think Rach may need to be educated in its use however, due to filling a wine glass neat with the stuff, which I would of been dead if I&amp;#8217;d actually consumed undiluted, or at least extremely quiet for the rest of the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Decided to make a move on to our next beach today, taking with us a picnic and a load of beer. This one is situated right next to a forest, which was ace for our picnic.
Tim, after 3 years of living with one another has finally managed to teach me to juggle and give me the bug for continuing it. It&amp;#8217;s actually easier to learn using boule, forcing you to use correct arm movements, though its a little dangerous on the beach if you have a distinct lack of footwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Marshes</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</guid>
      <description>Today we went over to the salt marshes in Olonne, it being slightly more manageable weather and all. Tim basically wanted to do a little birdwatching and Heledd and Dave didn&amp;#8217;t fancy such french beauty so went to have coffee in a suitable village somewhere. It was really cool, took lots of photos of the strange green murky waters and had a bunch of exercise too. Saw loads of eels while we were there &amp;#8211; horrible things writhing about&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Sunday&amp;#8217;s morning events weren&amp;#8217;t overly exciting &amp;#8211; the weather has been so hot that it would be a bit much to go off and try to do anything. Instead has been a morning of reading (Dahl&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Boy&amp;#8217; &amp;#8211; bizzarrely featuring Cardiff, La Rochelle and Somerset within) and people trying to juggle. The afternoon became overcast so we decided to make the trip down to the beach, where Tim, Rach and Pete all got rather dirty trying to recreate a eurotunnel experience, which was destroyed as soon as it was completed by Dave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Journeys - 17/06/05 - 18/06/05</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</guid>
      <description>So, it begins, the holiday season that is and with it my two day trip across England and back down the west coast of France to Jard Su Mer. Todays trip was fairly long, spending two hours bombing down the M4 to meet with the guys in Reading, then a further few to reach the underside of London on the M25, and a bit more to finally bundle over toward the Eurotunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another One Bites the Dust</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that the title might refer to Pop&amp;#8217;s funeral this week, but no, I mean the fact that finally after 7 years in courtship Mike and Jo have become hitched. Thats strike 5 from the core Yeovil lad&amp;#8217;s posse&amp;#8230;
It was a fab day, with schoolfriends from yesteryear I haven&amp;#8217;t kept up to date with, and family members I never knew existed. My sister always seems to find it amusing that Jo&amp;#8217;s sis, Sarah got hitched before them being a couple of years younger, having her been to school with Sarah and Jo in my form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUMO!</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</guid>
      <description>No, not the monthly breaks event in Clwb Ifor, though you&amp;#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that&amp;#8217;s what this post would be about due to regular raving about it, no, *actual *Sumo.
So I started my trip off at 9:45am &amp;#8211; realising that actually that Tesco&amp;#8217;s would be shut if I left earlier and I&amp;#8217;d not get fuel.. After faffing getting burgers and the like, I set off about 10:20am to Bournemouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackalicious - Make You Feel That Way</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious---make-you-feel-that-way/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Ya know its like ahh like the most greatest feeling you could ever feel, you know, like, just total elation. Sunny day, just got paid&amp;#8230;.
You know its just like, you know, just the most joyous feeling you could ever comprehend. You know, chilling with your family.
You know just you know just really really feeling, feeling the moment, with the folks. Ya know really really really just chilling.
It&amp;#8217;s love&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Places</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</guid>
      <description>To cheer me up a bit I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to go to my happy place (which doesn&amp;#8217;t involve dwarfs on tricycles before you ask), merely great places nearby which hold fantastic memories for me &amp;#8211; &amp;#8216;Ham Hill&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8220;West Bay&amp;#8221; being two notable ones. Ham Hill has all those fantastic bike rides, barbeques, moonlit evenings, Christmas moments and stupid uni friends wondering where we got all the pigs from. West Bay holds a bunch more cycle rides, youth camps (with lots of sheep, golf courses and jogs), barbeques, baptisms (including my own), boating moments and horrible toilets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rank</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I found most amusing yesterday, which made me laugh lots is that my website is currently ranked #5 in msn for &amp;#8220;childrens farting jokes&amp;#8221;, Microsoft are obviously doing their jobs well once again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highs and Lows, Peaks and Troughs</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</guid>
      <description>It was great to have the bank holiday this monday once again, allowed me to recover from the mad weekend that I had. The Vineyardites met at Living Stones for a great packed lunch (which had been moved from the park due to Cardiff&amp;#8217;s dodgy weather), followed by new take on a game of miniature bowls on the snooker table by Jon and Rob. After this I moved on to Roath Park with Lewis and one of his mates from home before meeting up with Vineyardites once again and chucking bread at feathered creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>