<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s in a name?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>I usually get one of two looks when I announce the name of my company as &amp;ldquo;Nifty Digits&amp;rdquo;. Either a “Ah, I like that” or a raised eyebrow. Generally, it’s the person latter in years who might raise an eyebrow.
When I picked the name, I was still a PhD student at University and wanted something that “sounded technical (digits), but also sort of British (nifty)”. I also was heavily influenced number of web design bloggers at the time, particularly Dan Cedarholm’s blog “Simple Bits”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for being a more Productive Freelancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer/</guid>
      <description>Having heard the question raised on @workingoutshow, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take some time to share the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve found have really helped me be productive in my work. These may not work for everyone, but hopefully some points will help for others.
Find a Good Environment The single biggest change I&amp;rsquo;ve found which has had a major impact on my work is changing my environment. We&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to have a small garden at our house and with the arrival of my daughter back in October, I was quick to realise that working in the open plan lounge in our house just wasn&amp;rsquo;t a viable option any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</guid>
      <description>This month, I&amp;#8217;ve decided to take some time out to ship projects.
I have a huge list of projects accumulating I&amp;#8217;d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.
Currently I don&amp;#8217;t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we&amp;#8217;ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Rate Britizens</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens/</guid>
      <description>I decided to attempt a simple app this week, first using GoCardless, then later the beta of Stripe. It requires the payment of funds between two individuals, neither of which might be a business. GoCardless suggests signing up to use their partner programme, which involves registering a user as a merchant. This isn&amp;#8217;t entirely suitable given the individual will be asked many queries on the nature of their business (which they don&amp;#8217;t have).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Run a Fairtrade Business?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief retrospective of what I&amp;#8217;ve learned in the 6 years I&amp;#8217;ve been running Fair &amp;#038; Bare, a Fairtrade t-shirt company along with my wife.
If you&amp;#8217;re a new follower of mine, you heard right &amp;#8211; I run a Fairtrade t-shirt company. I&amp;#8217;ve not actively been marketing it more recently for a number of reasons, but I still have a strong belief in our original vision. That vision was that Fairtrade shirts at the time weren&amp;#8217;t being well received by the world, despite being available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair  Bare - January £10 Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</guid>
      <description>Fair &amp;#038; Bare &amp;#8211; The little shop I run (with a little help from my wife) is having a January Sale right now in celebration of entering the year 2010. Every shirt we&amp;#8217;ve made to date is just 10 squid! Hurry up people, it only runs until Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</guid>
      <description>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what&amp;#8217;s going on over at Fair &amp;#038; Bare and if you&amp;#8217;re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I&amp;#8217;ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what&amp;#8217;s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair &amp; Bare Snowdodgers Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair--bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair--bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I announced that we&amp;#8217;re running our first design challenge in conjunction with team Snowdodgers at Fair &amp;#038; Bare. These are some really amazing fellas who are trying to raise £48,000 for charity by rallying a £200 banger round 4000 miles involving the Arctic circle. We&amp;#8217;re asking designers to get in designs relating to the chilly weather and the guys crazy antics!
If you&amp;#8217;re interested, you&amp;#8217;ve got just a month to get an entry in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare&#39;s first shirt!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a long time coming, but Fair and Bare&amp;#8217;s first t-shirt is now available to purchase!

Thanks to everyone who&amp;#8217;s participated since we kicked off. Really appreciate all your designs, words and support. We&amp;#8217;re still taking submissions for our competitions, so if you haven&amp;#8217;t hit us up already make sure you do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare - Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</guid>
      <description>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I&amp;#8217;m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with fairdos and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don&amp;#8217;t appeal to us at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>