<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: design</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Essential Cinema According to Lovefilm</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-lovefilm</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2012-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-lovefilm</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Given there’s a bit of lovefilm bashing <a href="http://www.tomalloyd.com/lovefilm-hate-email/">going on in Wales</a> at the moment, I thought I’d chime in with the most frustrating thing I found with communications from lovefilm. </p>

<p>Check out the following weekly email I used to receive (I’ve since unsubscribed), along with my annotations.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lovefilm.com/emailpublic/cmsnewsletter/uk-newsletter/LOVEFiLM-Newsletter/2012/Newsletter-Issue-No-409?cid=lfnl409tlweb&#038;brand=lovefilm"><img src="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Read-Newsletter-Issue-409-5.jpg" alt="" title="Read Newsletter Issue 409 5" width="470" height="906" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-569" /></a></p>

<p>I really couldn’t care less about who lovefilm are sending into cinema’s to perform reviews and certainly don’t want it to be the first text I see in relation to that image. </p>

<p>Also, the first thing I’m drawn to is the image. Why lead me away from the title of that movie and make work to find the text for the heading? Don’t make the title and preview exactly the same size, or divide them up!</p>

<p>End of rant.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>New Adventures 2012 &#8211; Self Help for Web Designers</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012-self-help-for-web-designers</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2012-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012-self-help-for-web-designers</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Last week, like many others working on the web, I took the trip to Nottingham for <a href="http://2012.newadventuresconf.com/">New Adventures 2012</a>. I’d seen the wonderful praise dished out for it last year and felt like I wanted to see what it was all about first hand. </p>

<p>I’ve learnt from experience that the most important part of any conference is not the talks or speakers involved, but the community around it and therefore I headed up the night before to ensure I didn’t miss a thing.</p>

<p>Colly and his team had done a lovely job of organising enough to keep us busy what with bowling, screenprinting, fr00tball, the after party and of course the main event.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/20120119_092906_small.jpg"><img src="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/20120119_092906_small-1024x768.jpg" alt="" title="The Albert Hall" width="640" height="480" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-515" /></a></p>

<p>Despite not actually branding myself as a web designer, it was great to feel welcomed and able to chat one on one with others about our day to day work. Dan Mall’s talked helped somewhat here, forcing introductions with everyone around me. I’m pretty much work in solitary confinement as a developer and to discuss the thoughts and ideas I have with other like minded creatives is always welcome.</p>

<p>During a dinner following the conference, another dev commented that the most of the presentations weren’t specific to web design. They were in fact so abstract, that it was more a “Self Help Class for Web Designers”. I pretty much agree with this. But that’s with a caveat – what else do you attend these presentations for? NA Conf is there to share, inspire and enable designers to be better designers. I want to leave giddy eyed with possibilities. Remember there are workshops too for specifics…</p>

<p>After the whole conference, I feel like there’s a whole lot more I could do to better myself at my craft. Hopefully over the course of the year I’ll do something about it. Most of the notes I made are to this effect too and I’m sure I’ll take away something different each time I look at them.</p>

<p>There’s only so much that can be covered in 45 mins, and for me I want to see a speaker paint me the big picture. After NAConf, I’ve got a whole bunch of big pictures to get through.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair and Bare&#8217;s first shirt!</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>So, its been a long time coming, but Fair and Bare&#8217;s first t-shirt is now available to purchase!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fairandbare.com/product/view/1/tree_huggin"><br />
<img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/fairandbare/images/banners/shop_banner.jpg" alt="Tree Huggin'" /><br />
</a></p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who&#8217;s participated since we kicked off. Really appreciate all your designs, words and support. We&#8217;re still taking submissions for our competitions, so if you haven&#8217;t hit us up already make sure you do!</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Fair and Bare &#8211; Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2008-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I’m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with <a href="http://fairdos.com">fairdos</a> and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don’t appeal to us at all. Some of these friends are people who are right up there within prominent fairtrade companies, who although avid promoters, won’t wear fairtrade on a day to day basis if it means they have to sacrifice their style. It seems that the fairtrade companies don’t do design and so we’re not given a choice between two similar products. The end result is we’re faced with looking great and feeling a little discontent that the garment isn’t as fantastic as it could be, or feeling great about a product – but not looking so awesome. We’ve often spoken of beginning a fairtrade company that puts out clothing that is both ethically produced and well designed, but held off doing so because it felt a little beyond us. I can say here now that we’ve made the first step in bringing that vision a little closer.</p>

<p><a href="http://fairandbare.com">Fair and Bare</a> is a crowdsourcing project which pays out comission to designers who successfully produce t shirt design ideas for fairtrade t shirts. It’s also an attempt for the fairtrade community to lose that somewhat ‘serious face’ with which I think they are often associated and relax the shoulders a bit whilst having some fun. We’re currently offering £200 for designs and £50 for design ideas which we think are worth printing up onto fairtrade cotton. We then hope to offer shirts at a somewhat more accessible price than other fairtrade shirts. It’s a fun, small project at the moment, but I hope that we can help rejuvinate an otherwise awesome product and maybe inspire others to do the same.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-09-11T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my “business” cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing “beta” on hand hand-made ones or something…</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/imw/1358538413/" title="Photo Sharing"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1399/1358538413_8f41f4ee63.jpg" width="500" height="375" alt="Which would you rather introduce yourself with?" /></a></p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>pMachine changes its name</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>pMachine has changed its name to <a href="http://ellislab.com">Ellislab</a>, and are <a href="http://ellislab.com">sporting a shiny new website for all to see</a>. The reason for the change is the expansion over the last 6 years to encompass products which don’t fall under the same banner now. I’m glad to see that the <a href="http://codeigniter.com">CodeIgniter</a> website has got a facelift. <a href="http://31three.com/">31three</a> did the hard graft on the design and <a href="http://ellislab.com">they</a> all <a href="http://expressionengine.com">look</a> <a href="http://codeigniter.com">awesome</a>.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>