<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
    <title>ianwootten.co.uk - Category: music</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Copyright Law Finally Aligns with Me</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2014-04-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>On June 1st 2014, some much needed changes are being made to exceptions to copyright law which amongst other things, will allow conversion of personal media between file formats.</p>

<p>Finally, we’ll able to make personal conversions of digital media (at least they will be now counted as legal copies). I’ve long made copies of my cd’s to listen to whilst coding (iTunes allows me to do so simply) – but it is not currently legal to move these files to another storage medium, such as an mp3 player. The fact is that most people have been ripping cds and copying them to iPods since it was technically possible, but music companies have never prosecuted anyone as the implications would stem far and wide and would the costs would too prohibitive to be able to enforce them.</p>

<p>It’s also not currently legal to rip movies to another format. So copying a dvd to a mkv file to play elsewhere is construed illegal. The fact movie studios put protection in place on their dvds to prevent you from doing so puts most people off doing so anyway. From June 1st this also changes so it will also be legal (but probably will be as difficult due to the copy protection in place). The guidance doesn’t specifically mention blu-rays by name, but it does say “The exception will apply to any copies you have bought, other than computer programs” – which I see to include blu-rays. However, it does also mention that copy protection may still be in place on those formats. Which you can raise a complaint to the secretary of state about if you think it’s too restrictive (good luck getting a response there!).</p>

<p>I’m a big fan of said changes, mainly due to the fact I own a huge amount of discs which aren’t currently allowed to be any format other than that they were distributed in. DVD’s, CD’s and Vinyl(!). I’ve found this frustrating, as my own stance is I should be able to manipulate the media to my hearts content within my own 4 walls. In fact, in order to listen to myself practicing when I used to dj, I need to make recordings which change their format. The fact that I’ll be able to do this within the law makes me a very happy chap indeed. Up until now, the law has been fairly grey on the matter, but hasn’t prosecuted anyone for format conversion (as far as I’m aware).</p>

<p>The new guidance is quick to point out that it’ll still be illegal to distribute the media you create – You have to “own” the media you’re converting. Therefore duplicating a friends mp3 collection at work from their hard drive will still be illegal. If you sell the original format from which you made copies, then your copies will again be illegal. Again this aligns with how I feel things should be done. I feel like I should be paying someone for the entertainment I enjoy from said media. The artist/record labels decide a price and that’s what I should pay – but I don’t feel like they can make me pay multiple times for the same thing, especially if I can create said formats from media I already own. If you hold a copy but haven’t paid for it, I feel it fair for it to be deemed illegal, however possible it is technically to achieve.</p>

<p>In summary, I feel these changes are great (but long overdue). </p>

<p>You can read a full summary of changes to consumers issued by the Intellectual Property Office <a href="http://www.ipo.gov.uk/copyright-guidance-consumers.pdf">here</a>. Amusingly, the document explains you may be affected if you “read books, watch films or listen to music” – or my favourite “use electronic devices”. I guess that covers anyone reading this then.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Thou Shalt Always Kill</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I am loving this track I just discovered on <a href="http://hiphipuk.co.uk">Adam Fletchers</a> blog.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>What&#8217;s up with Last.fm?</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-lastfm</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-lastfm</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p><a href="http://last.fm">Last.fm</a> seems to be down at the moment for the last couple of minutes. Anyone know what’s going on?[Update:Looks like this was just a blip, ho hum]</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Mashup!</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-04-03T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Recipe for Beatbox</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>This link sent to me by Lewis made me laugh quite a lot. Funnily, it looks a lot like him with a wig on.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Introducing&#8230;</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It’s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I’d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she’d brave the border as well to make those “all important” first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</p>

<p>I got to see all my fabulous pals as well as witness the dedication of Jase and Stephs daughter Eden at the service on Sunday with lots of fireworks type “ooh’s and ahh’s” from the elderly members to express her cuteness. As a gesture of thanks, the Helyars bought everyone there a doughnut, putting my previous contributions to Vineyard somewhat to shame.</p>

<p>After a detour to clarks village with Paul tagging along (after a number of bump starts – remember to keep the keys in the ignition mate), we made it back to Cardiff and headed off to see the amazing Prodigy. I was so tired by now it was ridiculous, I used to remember home as a quiet place, it didn’t seem to be the case this visit but still somehow managed to roll up at the CIA. The warm up act (Audio Bully’s) really sucked big time, and it was quite amusing to hear the roar as the first track from the dj’s came on afterwards. Anyway, after feeling suitably psyched, Paul, I and the large group in the bit that formed around us spent the next 2 hours going mental to all the classics, without a black eye in sight. Lot’s of fond childhood memories came flooding back of music sharing in Pauls living room. Twas brill it twas.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Oblivious</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I think I’m a little less than perceptive of situations in which I’m involved. Recently, I’ve been clued in to a number of things which makes me think I’ve been carrying freeriding on this life while I could of been part of something so much more interesting. This isn’t a direct attack on anyone but myself, so don’t anyone take it to heart. I think this is best shown through the forming of a type of relationship I’ve been starved of for the best part of my life, one with my lovely new girlfriend.</p>

<p>Also, I’ve discovered “the best” electronic album I’ve heard in goodness knows how long, once again confirming my above suspicions. <a href="http://www.boomkat.com/item.cfm?id=10674">“Ulrich Schnauss – A Strangely Isolated Place”</a> is currently making my spare time bliss though the tracklisting could lead you to believe the contrary and summises where I’ve been for a while. I advise anyone with a pulse and a desire to feel uplifted to contemplate the benefits of purchase. For all the others (without a pulse or a desire not to be uplifted), theres some free tracks on his <a href="http://www.ulrich-schnauss.com/">website</a>.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Describing the Effects of Music</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I went round to Living Stones last night for a bit of a lads night with Jon, Dan, Rob and Joe for music and watching Batman Begins. I took a number of Cd’s for Dan and I to listen to, which basically reflected the “base” around which the majority of all my other music stems from. It’s quite odd trying to verbalise how a particular song makes you feel, why you feel uplifted by it, how it captures a particular moment in time, thought, etc etc. It’s more odd because I don’t tend to talk about my music tastes much and coming to terms with what mainstream music means to me is surreal.</p>

<p>“It’s not who we are, but what we do that defines us…”</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Daft Punk</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve been attending a fair few ‘live’ gigs recently as oppose to the frequenting of clubs in Cardiff. The first was the fantastic <a href="http://www.royksopp.com/">Röyksopp</a>, whom I was dubious to see alone, but glad I did. Quite frankly they were as great live as I could possibly hope for and the addition of the huge inflatable tape and scrolling info about each song added to the experience.</p>

<p>More recently, I got to see <a href="http://www.bowlingforsoup.com">“Bowling for Soup”</a> at union on Friday, which allowed me to experience the ‘delights’ of teen punk as well as some awful “post-punk laptop (c)rap” from <a href="http://www.mclars.com">Mc Lars</a> who seemed confused as to where exactly Cardiff featured in the UK. When <a href="http://www.americanhi-fi.com/">American Hi-Fi</a> landed as support, the kiddies got a tad excited and decided to vent their frustrations of the last week before half-term by forming a number of mosh pits and jumping into one another. Not fully understanding this myself, we backed off to safer havens and observed further stupidity from there.</p>

<p>Saturday was a return to old pastures for me, providing a warm-up for <a href="http://www.todah.co.uk/2005/">Todah</a>, who are as great live as their website suggests. The venue (the old apostolic church in swansea), was highly unique allowing me to play in the most random room ever as the youth were crammed in like sardines. It was great fun, reminding me of the older youth events we used to hold in Yeovil prior to the move into the new building. It was also awesome to get paid to perform and enjoy worship. I decided to give Heledd a buzz whilst I was there (possibly a little belated I realise) and we ended up going for a fab Indian with the band after, with much laughter involved. Unfortunately it seems some CV’ers might have inferred a little too much from the outing, (big stick, wrong end), but to be fair it’s nice to know that people pay enough of an interest in my life to be bothered by that.</p>

<center>
  <br /> <wpg2id>8796</wpg2id><br /> <wpg2id>8882</wpg2id><br />
</center>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>CD Greedy</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve always bought lots of music. Those of you who’ve had the privilege of viewing my collection will have seen it spans all manner of media, Tape, CD, MD, Vinyl. I’ve recently been doing a lot of random browsing on ebay for CD’s that have previously escaped me and possibly buying a few other items from the same seller to save on postage. My biggest one though has to be my most recent, 12 albums from the same seller. It’s allowed me to reminice the awesome Orb, along with Orbital, Goldie and earlier William Orbit albums whilst exploring a bunch of cheesy trance as well. All for the bargain price of £17! – a sum which I may have paid for a single album in the past. My how times change…</p>

<p>My latest favourite ol’ electronica hit as a result is “Orb – Little Fluffy Clouds”.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>