<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006/03 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006/03 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>worpdress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I noticed that worpdress.com, org and net weren’t registered, despite their similarity to the excellent blogging tool wordpress’s domain. I thought it was too good an opportunity to be missed, and registered the lot of them.After a couple of posts on the wordpress forums, and the realisation that there was no way in hell I’d ever have the time to put anything there, I decided to donate them to Matt Mullenweg, so at least they were redirecting the one or two people who might hit them to the correct wordpress site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nth Fest</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</guid>
      <description>Although I didn’t attend it, it sounds like this event held at my church at home in Somerset was an absolute blast – props to crackers for sorting it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg It</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently, through many searches to do with AJAX, Web 2.0 and the like been perusing digg.com, that fairly new web site for geeks.Basically, it’s a social booking marking site where users “digg” those sites which they find interesting, as more users digg the same pages, they get promoted up through to the main page, or higher up through the rankings within particular categories. Its a really interesting concept, quite similar to del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Pancakes!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Flipping pancakes eh? They’re crafty beggars they are..
Would you believe that in my 24 years knocking around, I’d never actually flipped a pancake until this tuesday? You could understand why I might be a little excited about that particular prospect, and a little nervous. I spent my evening with a bunch of girls, in all shapes and sizes (some tall, some short, some insanely strong) to celebrate this occasion, but when my time to shine came, it was all good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
