<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006/02 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006/02 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MSI RS480M2-IL Motherboard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who would like to have a stable SFF machine, lest ye take heed of my advice…do not buy MSI.I bought a mATX MSI RS480M2-IL back in october, with a view to putting it in my new Antec Aria SFF case. It looked deceptively feature packed with its 939 madness and 3 x PCI and PCI-E slots. There it still currently resides sitting quietly all day until I return from work in the evening to perhaps do a little web design or listen to the 70 odd gigs of music I have stashed away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geeks gone out</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started a new blog over at webtyrant.com for all of you who visit my site and need a fix of techie-type jazz. I figured most of you didn’t, hence my placement on a different domain. You might notice a similar theme over there, so that’ll make you feel right at home even if the content doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just been informed that my paper for CCGRID06 has been accepted, which I’m very pleased about. It’s my first paper acceptance in my 14 months of being based as a PhD at Cardiff University so really its about time I got some ideas out in the open to people. It’s also based in Singapore, and I’ve never left Europe – yeah it’s two days, but I’m chuffed nonetheless.
The ironic thing is I was a bit annoyed last year at the fact CCGRID05 was in Cardiff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</guid>
      <description>Romantic rose petals and normal ones?
Probably about £6 I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</guid>
      <description>My day was brightened lots yesterday when my my PhD supervisor informed me he had a blog on the subject of grid computing. It was intended for members of our research group to contribute to and discuss things. The most amusing part was, being cutting edge and all, you’d expect it to be a bustling hive of activity. What I actually found was a site with two posts covering the last 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</guid>
      <description>and so it begins….a new website, a new era of web geeking to the max, free from the shackles of mere mortal mens minds.A place to be geeks are creative, explore and communicate…Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you, The Web Tyrant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
