<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/12 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/12 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Out with the Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</guid>
      <description>If anyone is interested in puchasing my old computer, I&amp;#8217;m getting rid of it.
It features:
 Athlon 2500XP Barton CPU 512Mb 3200 DDR Memory 80Gb 7200RPM Hard Disk Sound Blaster Live Drive 5.1 with Remote Control Sony DVD-ROM LG 52x24x52 CDRW Tyan Tachyon 128Mb G9600Pro (Ati Radeon &amp;#8211; fully boxed) 350W Levicom Blue Lit Dual Fan Power Supply (fully boxed) Antec Plusview Case (with side panel)  (fully boxed) 17&amp;#8243; Hansol 710D CRT Flat Monitor Logitech Keyboard/Mouse  Boxes/driver disks included, but supplied without any operating system (unless you want Ubuntu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</guid>
      <description>I cleaned out one of the boxes of papers kicking around my room the other evening. In it, I found an old lunch pass from school (featuring a photo sporting a lovely little version of me) and lots of old encouragement sheets we used to pass around our youth group to gets lots of positive comments on ourselves. Most of these are at least 5 years old and some stretch back to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Long</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday morning, Maggie, our eldest labrador at home was taken to the vet to be put down. She&amp;#8217;d been poorly for sometime and had become unable to walk, for any reason whatsoever. Maggie was a member of our family for the past 13 years, so it&amp;#8217;s understandably a bit of a loss to us all. It&amp;#8217;s strange to think back to when we first got her, making apologies to numerous teachers for the state the new books I&amp;#8217;d been given had gotten into so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>