<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2012 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2012 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Crap, I&#39;m a Frontend Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</guid>
      <description>When I was first tiptoeing in the waters of web development (early 2000&amp;#8242;s), getting a grips on job descriptions was simple. There were 2 types of people in our industry: designers or developers. You either drew websites, or you built websites &amp;#8211; that was it.
As time went on people seemed to invent new titles: &amp;#8220;UX Designers&amp;#8221; were the first to appear on the scene to me, and we&amp;#8217;re still to this day figuring out what this role really entails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Cinema According to Lovefilm</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</guid>
      <description>Given there&amp;#8217;s a bit of lovefilm bashing going on in Wales at the moment, I thought I&amp;#8217;d chime in with the most frustrating thing I found with communications from lovefilm.
Check out the following weekly email I used to receive (I&amp;#8217;ve since unsubscribed), along with my annotations.

I really couldn&amp;#8217;t care less about who lovefilm are sending into cinema&amp;#8217;s to perform reviews and certainly don&amp;#8217;t want it to be the first text I see in relation to that image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Images from SD Cards with PhotoRec</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</guid>
      <description>I had the horrible situation last Sunday following removing a number of pictures using an SD reader from my SD card that when I inserted it in my camera, it registered nothing upon it. My heart sunk, because this card is stuffed full of images of me and my family (along with my 1 year old son growing up) and I was unsure of which ones I&amp;#8217;d actually backed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scientist in an Adventure with Pirates</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</guid>
      <description>This is a talk I did back in May at unifieddiff about my time working as a web developer at Aardman Features. I talk quite a bit about the production process and what we take from staff in order to help them do their jobs properly. I quite enjoyed giving this talk &amp;#8211; more so than those I&amp;#8217;ve given in an academic capacity in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You’re Nowhere Near as Good a Hacker as You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/13/youre-nowhere-near-as-good-a-hacker-as-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/13/youre-nowhere-near-as-good-a-hacker-as-you-think/</guid>
      <description>What are you doing? Why would you go down that road? Shouldn’t you be building something else? How long have you been doing this?
Sure you can fool your clients into thinking you’re adding value to their product. I know the truth. But how did you &amp;#8211; with all your expertise get to the point in thinking that’s what you’re really doing?
This is your first project? Shouldn’t you be focusing on your clients problems?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does Steam store Indie Game The Movie?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/06/12/where-does-steam-store-indie-game-the-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/06/12/where-does-steam-store-indie-game-the-movie/</guid>
      <description>A quickie &amp;#8211; but for all those that have downloaded &amp;#8220;Indie Game the Movie&amp;#8221; today from steam and are wondering where the video files are stored, you can find them here:
Steam/SteamApps/common/Indie Game The Movie/data/movies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Build It</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/05/03/if-you-build-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/05/03/if-you-build-it/</guid>
      <description>If my years in academia have taught me anything, it&amp;#8217;s that insight obvious to you isn&amp;#8217;t often obvious to others.
As a result, I&amp;#8217;ve pretty much adopted a gung-ho hacker attitude towards getting my own ideas built whereby I&amp;#8217;ll just often work to get an iteration of an site out as fast as possible. The only factor here is my own time and I&amp;#8217;m in the fortunate position to have some of that available now and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Switch Your VPS in 2 Hours</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/03/01/how-to-switch-your-vps-in-2-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/03/01/how-to-switch-your-vps-in-2-hours/</guid>
      <description>Friday last week I woke up to a barrage of emails coming into my inbox. All of these were coming from notification of spam comments upon this very blog. By the time I’d woken up I’d had something like 75 emails. This was pretty strange given that Akismet was there guarding my blog ever since it’s been available and I’d never had a email about a dodgy comment since I’d set it up (something like 5 years ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where&#39;s my Full Stack Payment Service?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/02/16/wheres-my-full-stack-payment-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/02/16/wheres-my-full-stack-payment-service/</guid>
      <description>Unless you&amp;#8217;ve been living under a rock, you&amp;#8217;ll realise that there&amp;#8217;s an uprising against paypal amongst developers. Most of this stems from the multitude of crazy requirements they put upon sellers and the locks they can put upon your account without notice.
This in part has led to a number of payment alternatives cropping up. Here in the UK for instance, you have Google checkout and checkout by Amazon pitching up against paypal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2012 - Self Help for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012---self-help-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>Last week, like many others working on the web, I took the trip to Nottingham for New Adventures 2012. I&amp;#8217;d seen the wonderful praise dished out for it last year and felt like I wanted to see what it was all about first hand.
I&amp;#8217;ve learnt from experience that the most important part of any conference is not the talks or speakers involved, but the community around it and therefore I headed up the night before to ensure I didn&amp;#8217;t miss a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye 1 &amp; 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/12/goodbye-1--1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/12/goodbye-1--1/</guid>
      <description>I just sent the following email to 1 &amp;#038; 1&amp;#8242;s billing department. I&amp;#8217;ve been with them for coming up to 7 years now and they were, when I first used them, the only registraar I knew about and I was really happy.
As the number of domains I own has grown, their account admin has become really totally useless to manage them all. I recieved a payment request out of the blue today and it tipped me over the edge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>