<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: unicycling</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Trials Unicycling</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2005-08-19T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I was inspired yesterday by watching a few vids on the internet of <a href="http://www.unicyclejester.com/video.php">crazy kids</a> doing trials unicycling, so decided to go out for a ride in the evening round Roath Park. It’s been a long time since I’ve ridden, but it seems you don’t forget. Nor do the ‘oh I’m original’ taunts cease, such as “oi, mate, you’ve lost a wheel!”, “pull a wheelie!” etc etc. Anyway, it was nice to finally ride mine without fear of the horrid scratching which I usually obtain from my previous saddle. Alas I think it’ll be a long time before I’m able to perform smooth grinds along benches and the like.</p>

<p>Apparently, I’ve heard in Japan where unicycling was invented, trials unicycling is as popular a sport as mountain biking, but I don’t believe this for a minute as I’ve never seen any evidence. I was also wondering what the policy on unicycling upon pavements was…people don’t seem to mind, seem more bemused than anything and move out of the way. </p>

<p>If anyones interested, they can have a <a href="http://people.brunel.ac.uk/~mepgjdf/ftt/day1.html">look</a> at the Land’s End to John O’Groats record that my mates broke, 5 years ago. I believe today would be the anniversary of Jay wrecking his van.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>