<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Geek on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/geek/</link><description>Recent content in Geek on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/geek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It's not quite the iflea, but...</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</guid><description>So Apple announces this week that they release their new version of iTunes, the ROKR E1 – a mobile phone featuring iTunes and finally, the iPod nano – a super-small, thinner version of the iPod to replace the iPod mini. Another iPod – how many have there been now? There’s still no move on a larger capacity front, so nowhere to house my 7000 high quality mp3′s just yet – except my portable fat hard drive.</description></item><item><title>Millions of Wrongs don't Make it Right</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</guid><description>I’ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I’d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it’s quite the opposite really.
My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it’s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase.</description></item><item><title>How Rank</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</guid><description>One of the things I found most amusing yesterday, which made me laugh lots is that my website is currently ranked #5 in msn for “childrens farting jokes”, Microsoft are obviously doing their jobs well once again.</description></item></channel></rss>