<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2004/02 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2004/02 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arggh</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m realling struggling at the moment to get a visual interface all sorted and loverly so people can literally &amp;#8220;point-and-click&amp;#8221;. I made the decision to do this after talks with both my supervisor and moderator and have been trying like crazy to get it sorted, its taken over a week so far! Not good.
My moderator also suggested that trying to find example XML schemas for CMS&amp;#8217;s which were already out on the market at the moment for would make for good reading also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Year with Moderator</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</guid>
      <description>Just had my mid-year meeting follow-up with my moderator. It seems he would like to see a focus on XML standards for this system, rather than just a botch of XML which I decided on. Don&amp;#8217;t really know how I decide on that.
On searching for them though I found a CMS XML framework (uh-oh) which basically just outputs everything as XML. Find it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</guid>
      <description>Just realised that my cms doesn&amp;#8217;t display properly in IE6. Might explain why it looked so dodgy at my mid-year meeting with my supervisor.
Got a few extra things in my project, permission system is fully functional, priorities for roles, workflow management &amp;#8211; all of which still have bugs. Going to get down to the actual &amp;#8220;management&amp;#8221; part of the CMS tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a waste</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</guid>
      <description>What a waste of a day that was&amp;#8230;I hate programming.
I&amp;#8217;ve spent most of the day stuck on trivial little tasks like trying to pass back multi-dimensional arrays through scripts, and interpret the results.
On an upside, I&amp;#8217;ve managed to get XSL producing XHTML output and generated a working grid for the actions in the system. I also found a bug in XSL which means that it will condense textarea tags to their smallest form, and resulting in incorrect display in most web browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>