<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/09 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/09 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragile</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m feeling rather fragile at the moment, which is really annoying because the majority of the time I&amp;#8217;m the picture of health. It started yesterday, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d got over it only for headaches and tummy aches to return by the evening. Unfortunately, it meant I wasn&amp;#8217;t best of hosts to Hannah who stayed over on Sunday because of a stereophonics gig she was going to. I had to fix her up with Jon to go with as her mate decided to back out on her pretty late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Requirements</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</guid>
      <description>That last post aside heres a mildly amusing anecdote that happened to me whilst in B&amp;#038;Q a couple of weeks ago featuring a sweet old welsh lady.
Old Lady (Looking at lampshades): &amp;#8220;Is that the ACTUAL price of these!?&amp;#8221;
Me (Bewildered, wondering past end of aisle): &amp;#8220;Well, yeah, it says so on the label&amp;#8221;
Old Lady: &amp;#8220;&amp;pound;11.99! I saw &amp;#8216;em for &amp;pound;1 on Newport Road!&amp;#8221;
Me (Still bewildered, now in aisle): &amp;#8220;Oh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who hid the bloomin&#39; remote?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</guid>
      <description>I was contemplating all the stuff I generally tend to blog about. Most of the time, something rather huge has to happen for me in my week to be bothered to blog about it and then a large majority of that goes unnoticed by you, my readers (both of you), due to concerns about upsetting people, getting upset by people or not reflecting myself in the best of light. Other stuff, I just don&amp;#8217;t think is interesting at all, but I&amp;#8217;ve been told that while I think it mundane, it proves amusing to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may have noticed that I&amp;#8217;ve moved. Whats that? You didn&amp;#8217;t? Oh well, cheers then, how much of a friend are you? I never read your blog either. For those who didn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8211; take a look in the address bar, I&amp;#8217;m now at www.ianwootten.co.uk (Highly original I know!).
This week I have been mostly stressing about work, sitting at home alone, watching repeats, finding interesting links through the wonder of del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not quite the iflea, but...</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</guid>
      <description>So Apple announces this week that they release their new version of iTunes, the ROKR E1 &amp;#8211; a mobile phone featuring iTunes and finally, the iPod nano &amp;#8211; a super-small, thinner version of the iPod to replace the iPod mini. Another iPod &amp;#8211; how many have there been now? There&amp;#8217;s still no move on a larger capacity front, so nowhere to house my 7000 high quality mp3&amp;#8242;s just yet &amp;#8211; except my portable fat hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>