<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: update</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Updating WordPress Automatically over SFTP</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2011-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Heres a quick how to on getting wordpress to update over SFTP. On a default install of php, wordpress only gives the option to update over FTP. I wanted to get it working as it’s more secure and means I don’t have to open up FTP on my virtual server and open another port up in the firewall.</p>

<p>I’m using ubuntu and the sequence of commands I followed were:</p>

<pre class="bash">sudo apt-get install libssh2-1-dev libssh2-php
</pre>

<p>You should now find that if you list the modules installed in php and check if ssh2 is now there, you get the result “ssh2″:</p>

<pre class="bash">php -m | grep ssh2
</pre>

<p>You’ll need to restart apache for the changes to begin being used.</p>

<pre class="bash">sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 restart
</pre>

<p>If you head to updates in your dashboard, you should now see an extra option “SSH2″ and spaces for public and private authentication keys. I had to head back to the terminal and create these particular files.</p>

<pre class="bash">cd ~
ssh-keygen
cat .ssh/id_rsa.pub &gt;&gt; .ssh/authorized_keys
chmod 755 .ssh
chmod 644 .ssh/*
sudo chown -R ian:www-data /var/www/pathtowordpress/
</pre>

<p>Now you can head into the updates page again, enter your username and password and the locations to your public and private keys (/home/ian/.ssh/id_rsa.pub and /home/ian/.ssh/id_rsa in my case). If you’re running ssh on a non standard port, be sure to append that to your hostname. </p>

<p>Thanks to the following helpful posts: http://kevin.vanzonneveld.net/techblog/article/make_ssh_connections_with_php/</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>