<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:15:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Code Christmas Tree LEDs (and find their 3D Coordinates)</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/10/how-to-code-christmas-tree-leds-and-find-their-3d-coordinates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/10/how-to-code-christmas-tree-leds-and-find-their-3d-coordinates/</guid>
      <description>For the Christmas of 2021, I decided to make our Christmas tree lights incredibly complex so that I could marvel at my own animations running on them. That&amp;rsquo;s tongue and cheek, but also ended up being very true.
I&amp;rsquo;d been inspired by mathematician Matt Parker in 2020 where he did this. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll describe all the hardware I used and how it was connected and I&amp;rsquo;ll share the code I needed to write to capture the LED&amp;rsquo;s coordinates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Week 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</guid>
      <description>I promised a progress update on how my attempt to get 4 projects shipped this month was going. On my first week, I decided to focus on my time tracking tool, hourglass. I’ve had this in the works for sometime and unfortunately, it’s fallen by the wayside to client work.
I’ve failed on my first week in getting this released to the world, but I’m far happier with how it’s working now and the value it might give to any potential user than previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</guid>
      <description>This month, I’ve decided to take some time out to ship projects.
I have a huge list of projects accumulating I’d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.
Currently I don’t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we’ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-Shirts from Fair &amp; Bare</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>If anyone else like me is considering working in the uk “web 2.0″ market, and finds the posts on common job boards clogged up with all the jobs from america, the small job board I have created and posted online might be a help. You’ll find it over at: http://webtyrant.com/jobs. It aggregates some common job boards together like 37Signals and ThinkVitamin, but removes anything but those located in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geeks gone out</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started a new blog over at webtyrant.com for all of you who visit my site and need a fix of techie-type jazz. I figured most of you didn’t, hence my placement on a different domain. You might notice a similar theme over there, so that’ll make you feel right at home even if the content doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arggh</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</guid>
      <description>I’m realling struggling at the moment to get a visual interface all sorted and loverly so people can literally “point-and-click”. I made the decision to do this after talks with both my supervisor and moderator and have been trying like crazy to get it sorted, its taken over a week so far! Not good.
My moderator also suggested that trying to find example XML schemas for CMS’s which were already out on the market at the moment for would make for good reading also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</guid>
      <description>Just realised that my cms doesn’t display properly in IE6. Might explain why it looked so dodgy at my mid-year meeting with my supervisor.
Got a few extra things in my project, permission system is fully functional, priorities for roles, workflow management – all of which still have bugs. Going to get down to the actual “management” part of the CMS tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a waste</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</guid>
      <description>What a waste of a day that was…I hate programming.
I’ve spent most of the day stuck on trivial little tasks like trying to pass back multi-dimensional arrays through scripts, and interpret the results.
On an upside, I’ve managed to get XSL producing XHTML output and generated a working grid for the actions in the system. I also found a bug in XSL which means that it will condense textarea tags to their smallest form, and resulting in incorrect display in most web browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSL</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</guid>
      <description>After spending most of the day working upon it, I have managed to convert the whole template system in my project over to XML. I also added the beginnings of a permissions system which has no functionality yet.
This does need some time for me to go through the motions of Spec, Design, Implementation write-up for this over the weekend so that I can present it next week during my mid-year progress presentation with my project supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSLT</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent a large portion of today converting bits of my project over to using XML with XSLT stylesheets. This solves a few issues that I’d had problems with.
 Generating RSS feeds. The masses of files for each template is now reduced to a single XSLT file, easily modified by anyone knowing what they are doing. Better compliance with web standards (missing “‘s, closing tags all need to be corrected) means that it should be relatively XHTML compliant when tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project - again...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project-again.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project-again.../</guid>
      <description>After having been working like theres no tomorrow on other coursework, I’ve finally managed to come back to my project work.
I’ve really not got very much productive work done on it aside from a few class diagrams and workflow routines which I’ve put together. I have been working on a prototype over the last month however in order to have that side of things produced on time. Currently it doesn’t do a lot more than add or delete users and needs to come a lot further before its something impressive which is worthy to be shown to my supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh deary me..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</guid>
      <description>I’ve been trying to make some headway on my cms project today in order to get ahead and not end up in the same situation as I had in the second year. Seeing as I have a distinct lack of all things coursework related at the mo, I thought that would be a diamond idea. Unfortunately my knowledge of what now goes into a project is somewhat sparse, and I’m finding it a right job knowing where to tackle first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And so it begins..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</guid>
      <description>Used today (yesterday, actually) to take a look over the various things that can be done when using XML and XLST together. All in all it seems very impressive, and can hugely alter the way which a document may first be formatted. This may be a valid reason to choose this method over more standard CSS techniques, which generally just alter bog standard settings like color, font-size ….
On a side note, I also managed to get an NT install of CVS sorted and working nicely on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
