<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 15:20:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buying Refurbished Just isn&#39;t the Same for the M1 Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/04/10/buying-refurbished-just-isnt-the-same-for-the-m1-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 15:20:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/04/10/buying-refurbished-just-isnt-the-same-for-the-m1-pro/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 11 Years, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from PC die hard to owning 4 different Macs for development. There&amp;rsquo;s one place I&amp;rsquo;ve bought them all over this time and that&amp;rsquo;s through the Apple Certified Refurbished store (US, UK). If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with it, this is where Apple resells returned hardware which has undergone a thorough certification process at a discount to customers. Best of all, it comes with the same 1 year warranty as if you bought it brand new from Apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With $15 in Sales, My First Digital Product is My Most Successful Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/03/21/with-15-in-sales-my-first-digital-product-is-my-most-successful-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 10:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/03/21/with-15-in-sales-my-first-digital-product-is-my-most-successful-ever/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I released my first ever digital product. It&amp;rsquo;s only been available for 2 days and is already my most successful product ever with a grand total of 3 sales, yielding a massive $15! I jest, but this is all totally true. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve run a web hosting service, a TShirt company before becoming an employee and then freelance developer 10 years ago. I still have boxes of tshirts that I haven&amp;rsquo;t sold and none of my previous product ventures have made me a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Principles You Can Use for Blogging</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/23/investment-principles-you-can-use-for-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 10:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/23/investment-principles-you-can-use-for-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Your blog is a financial investment and you should treat it as such. I know, that might be stretch to some - but I have 15 years worth of analytics for this very blog that shows what happens when you don&amp;rsquo;t.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always found it strange that those who are deeply involved in building the web don&amp;rsquo;t have any form of online presence. Most of that time I&amp;rsquo;ve thought of a website as a great advertisement that gives clients and employers a way of finding more out about you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use .env files with Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I love Poetry, but one thing I always find frustrating is having to add an additional package to my environments to read from .env files and access them as environment variables. I quite often default to Pipenv for simple projects to get round this. Turns out there’s now another way.
Poetry 1.2 will add plugin support to tweak or add to it&amp;rsquo;s default package management behaviour and @mpeteuil made one for .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Query the Product Hunt API Responsibly with Python</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/15/how-to-query-the-product-hunt-api-responsibly-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/15/how-to-query-the-product-hunt-api-responsibly-with-python/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote an article that got to the #1 spot on Hacker News for the folks at ScrapingBee. It focused on retrieving details for the 90,000+ featured products from the Product Hunt API and digging into interesting facets of the data. I was excited to see it sat at the #1 for a few hours and the frontpage for longer whilst I repeatedly took screenshots to regale my children with in later life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create AWS Lambda Layers for Python Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Using AWS Lambda for your serverless Python app can give significant cost and management benefits. However, unless your needs are simple you will quickly need to bundle your dependencies along with your functions. Doing so with an AWS Lambda Layer works much like installing dependencies within a local environment. You are able to reduce each functions size, maintain your core code separately and simply tell the function to use the layer when setting it up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
