<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 14:37:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python isn’t Used in Prod</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/10/19/python-isnt-used-in-prod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 14:37:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/10/19/python-isnt-used-in-prod/</guid>
      <description>I watched a video earlier this week by comedian and mathematician Matt Parker. It’s an entertaining walkthrough of some impressive optimisation of his own Python code by his community but there&amp;rsquo;s a comment about Python that I thought warranted some pushback.
That comment was that ‘Python will very rarely make it into production’. The implication being that it’s a language used only really for prototyping at which point you’ll bring out the raw grunt of another language - such as C++ or C to do some real work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon UK 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/20/pycon-uk-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 09:40:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/20/pycon-uk-2022/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend I&amp;rsquo;ve been attending PyCon UK. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly lucky in that I live a 10 min train ride from where it is located in Cardiff meaning its incredibly convenient and economic for me. As a Python dev located here, there&amp;rsquo;s literally no excuse not to attend.
What makes it even more special this time round is that this is the first event since the pandemic started - the last being held in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Poetry to use the active Pyenv to Create a Virtual Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/05/getting-poetry-to-use-the-active-pyenv-to-create-a-virtual-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/05/getting-poetry-to-use-the-active-pyenv-to-create-a-virtual-environment/</guid>
      <description>I found with a new poetry install that it refused to use the pyenv version of Python.
I needed to explicitly tell Poetry where to find the active pyenv:
poetry env use -- $(which python) After this, it works as expected.
Source: https://github.com/python-poetry/poetry/issues/651#issuecomment-861421651
Get Updates to Your Inbox My newsletter comes out every month and is stuffed with helpful stories, tools and code showing how developers like yourself ship efficiently. It also features articles and videos I&#39;ve recently published so you&#39;ll never miss out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing on the Framework Laptop</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/08/25/developing-on-the-framework-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:19:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/08/25/developing-on-the-framework-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I bought the 11th gen Framework Laptop to develop on. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll share what I liked and disliked and how I got on with it.
I’m sure you’re aware if you’re reading this Frameworks first laptop is billed as one that is completely upgradeable. So every part within can be replaced if you ever want to upgrade or need to replace broken parts. In fact, Framework actively encourages you to do so by including a nifty little screwdriver and spudger tool that can completely disassemble the entire machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set the Locale Used in Cypress Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/07/26/how-to-set-the-locale-used-in-cypress-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/07/26/how-to-set-the-locale-used-in-cypress-tests/</guid>
      <description>When running some Cypress tests in Github Actions that were inspecting dates recently, I wanted to be able to set the locale of the browser - specifically for Chrome which I was using with Cypress.
The tests checked the date format of dd/mm/yyyy and ran fine locally in my own locale of Great Britain, but when my Github action workflow executed them they appeared in a mm/dd/yyyy format.
Originally, I’d thought this require a step within setting up the github action environment itself which set my linux box to have the appropriate locale, but this doesn’t change anything - presumably because the Cypress github action runs in a separate step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Pay for Github Copilot?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/06/23/should-you-pay-for-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/06/23/should-you-pay-for-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>Unless you’ve been hidden under a rock, you’re likely aware of Copilot - Github’s (or Microsofts) AI pair programmer. It allows you to get help on the code you’re writing by bringing up suggestions through an autocomplete snippets when you begin typing code in your editor.
 Since it started its free beta back in the summer of last year, it’s been the subject of many developers videos and it’s even played a part in a few of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pass Vue Route Params as Component Props</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/06/09/how-to-pass-vue-route-params-as-component-props/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/06/09/how-to-pass-vue-route-params-as-component-props/</guid>
      <description>If you’re using vues router to link to dynamic URLs you may get stuck wondering why your props on router-links aren’t being sent to your components. Vue’s router doesn’t support sending props directly. So you can’t do something like this:
&amp;lt;router-link class=&amp;#34;...&amp;#34; :to=&amp;#34;{ path: `/user/edit/`, id=id }&amp;#34; &amp;gt;Edit &amp;lt;/router-link&amp;gt; Here the id prop will never get passed in routers default configuration. Instead you need to configure each of your routes to pass the route params as props like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Refurbished Just isn&#39;t the Same for the M1 Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/04/10/buying-refurbished-just-isnt-the-same-for-the-m1-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 15:20:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/04/10/buying-refurbished-just-isnt-the-same-for-the-m1-pro/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 11 Years, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from PC die hard to owning 4 different Macs for development. There&amp;rsquo;s one place I&amp;rsquo;ve bought them all over this time and that&amp;rsquo;s through the Apple Certified Refurbished store (US, UK). If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with it, this is where Apple resells returned hardware which has undergone a thorough certification process at a discount to customers. Best of all, it comes with the same 1 year warranty as if you bought it brand new from Apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With $15 in Sales, My First Digital Product is My Most Successful Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/03/21/with-15-in-sales-my-first-digital-product-is-my-most-successful-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 10:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/03/21/with-15-in-sales-my-first-digital-product-is-my-most-successful-ever/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I released my first ever digital product. It&amp;rsquo;s only been available for 2 days and is already my most successful product ever with a grand total of 3 sales, yielding a massive $15! I jest, but this is all totally true. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve run a web hosting service, a TShirt company before becoming an employee and then freelance developer 10 years ago. I still have boxes of tshirts that I haven&amp;rsquo;t sold and none of my previous product ventures have made me a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Principles You Can Use for Blogging</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/23/investment-principles-you-can-use-for-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 10:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/23/investment-principles-you-can-use-for-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Your blog is a financial investment and you should treat it as such. I know, that might be stretch to some - but I have 15 years worth of analytics for this very blog that shows what happens when you don&amp;rsquo;t.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always found it strange that those who are deeply involved in building the web don&amp;rsquo;t have any form of online presence. Most of that time I&amp;rsquo;ve thought of a website as a great advertisement that gives clients and employers a way of finding more out about you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use .env files with Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I love Poetry, but one thing I always find frustrating is having to add an additional package to my environments to read from .env files and access them as environment variables. I quite often default to Pipenv for simple projects to get round this. Turns out there’s now another way.
Poetry 1.2 will add plugin support to tweak or add to it&amp;rsquo;s default package management behaviour and @mpeteuil made one for .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Query the Product Hunt API Responsibly with Python</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/15/how-to-query-the-product-hunt-api-responsibly-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/15/how-to-query-the-product-hunt-api-responsibly-with-python/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote an article that got to the #1 spot on Hacker News for the folks at ScrapingBee. It focused on retrieving details for the 90,000+ featured products from the Product Hunt API and digging into interesting facets of the data. I was excited to see it sat at the #1 for a few hours and the frontpage for longer whilst I repeatedly took screenshots to regale my children with in later life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create AWS Lambda Layers for Python Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Using AWS Lambda for your serverless Python app can give significant cost and management benefits. However, unless your needs are simple you will quickly need to bundle your dependencies along with your functions. Doing so with an AWS Lambda Layer works much like installing dependencies within a local environment. You are able to reduce each functions size, maintain your core code separately and simply tell the function to use the layer when setting it up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
