<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: Geek</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>How has web use changed your life?</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2009-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I’ve been pondering this morning how the use of the internet has (or may have) changed my life. As a child/teen during the web’s infancy, I was blissfully unaware that so many lifes/careers/relationships would be enabled or changed as a result of the interactions it might facilitate. I hadn’t even heard of google prior to arriving at university and two years prior to that had never had internet access anywhere locally.<br />
I am sure my behaviour today would be pretty different if the web wasn’t around due to the massive impact its had in my world view. It seems a far smaller place and more tightly coupled. I feel free to drop messages to strangers and write blog posts into the ether. I won a T4 competition in my early uni years which landed me a car and £4k richer, which I wouldn’t have entered if I’d had to phone – so I’d definitely be poorer. There are however, <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/6187554.stm">examples</a> where the use of the web has had a detrimental effect on particular individual lives.</p>

<p>It’s a huge one to think about. Would my life be better as a result of the web having not been so widely adopted in the way it has? Would yours?</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>