<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decade on the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago today, I started this blog. That&amp;#8217;s just under a 3rd of my life. In other words, that&amp;#8217;s quite a long time ago.
I started out using Movable type and very quickly (3 days later) ditched it in favour of the b2 &amp;#8220;weblog tool&amp;#8221;, which WordPress was later spawned from.
Back then, I blogged frequently about what was going on in my life, which tended to centre around University coursework rather than technical posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introvert Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</guid>
      <description>You pay for your ticket, hotels, travel and then spend the rest of the year excitedly awaiting being able to attend the conference everyone is speaking about. Having travelled halfway across the country, braving weather you&amp;#8217;d never ordinarily leave the house for, you arrive in the unrecognisable city. You&amp;#8217;ve left your family to be here, which is heart wrenching at the best of times and your lonely hotel room is no comfort (especially given the number of beds it has).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Google</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve recently read a post over on the guardians technology site which gave a whistle-stop history of the internet as it turns 40. I thought I&amp;#8217;d share here my own experiences of growing up alongside the web, more for my own record than anything.
I remember at school a time at which there was no external connection, nor internal network (which we the pupils used) so the Acorn machines used at our school at the time could communicate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I have to contribute?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>It has struck me over the last couple of days and it&amp;#8217;s a reflection of my attitude to being interested in geeky things in general. I&amp;#8217;m an elitist. When I started my blog back in 2003, I loved the fact that relatively few of them existed. It was a reflection of my day to day life and I felt my voice was being heard (even though I had no analytics tools to back that up and it was not particularly interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stick to your guns - You&#39;ll be rewarded</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns---youll-be-rewarded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns---youll-be-rewarded/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m a firm believer that by upholding my own principles, I&amp;#8217;ll be rewarded. It&amp;#8217;s a tag line I adopted for the small hosting company that I&amp;#8217;ve been running for a while now. It also has been reflected this year in a nasty situation I was left in with my landlords, the council and a previous housemate (who doesn&amp;#8217;t really deserve that title, more just a person whom shared the house). In all these situations things have turned out better for me in the long run, due to myself re-enforcing what I believe should be done &amp;#8211; even if it does mean a longer struggle through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of &amp;#8220;The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain&amp;#8221;, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neckache</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</guid>
      <description>The other evening I managed to stretch my back awkwardly and I&amp;#8217;ve been feeling the repercussions of it ever since. It&amp;#8217;s extremely painful to move my head, arm or neck and I&amp;#8217;m getting really frustrated by not being able to sit at the computer without being uncomfortable. Wednesday night I was flat out in bed not able to move an inch, and little more of an improvement last night. It&amp;#8217;s making me really tired and irritable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stag Do</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</guid>
      <description>Now that the big day has passed, I thought I&amp;#8217;d start revealing how some of my days in the lead up to it were spent. For my stag do, firstly we had a fairly quiet night in playing computer games, after doing a shop at Asda and getting the majority of mates locked out of our new pad. Many laughed at my wii fighting skills. Saturday, we travelled over to the Forest of Dean to climb through the tree-course that is Go Ape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where have I been?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</guid>
      <description>Is a question you may have asked yourself once or twice on the absence of any written word on this site. Well, aside from not being here &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;ve been doing many things including moving house from my home of 3 years, playing a small part in organising a wedding and actually getting married (I know!). I&amp;#8217;ve also just returned from honeymoon with wife in tow and now we&amp;#8217;re trying to figure out where all our stuff should go when it&amp;#8217;s never had a home before and we&amp;#8217;ve never owned it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big it Up for Yeovil!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</guid>
      <description>Browsing across Matt Westcotts site yielded this particular gem. [I&amp;rsquo;m from there don&amp;rsquo;t you know?]. I used to love tracking it up in fasttracker, but haven&amp;#8217;t done anything for a very, very long time. Maybe I should start experimenting again&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bills are Boring</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</guid>
      <description>Doing household bills is extremely boring. I just spent two hours dividing up the phone bill and working out who owes what. If marriage brings me anything, at least it will bring me less of a headache when it comes to doing the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wed Designer - I wish I had one!&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer---i-wish-i-had-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer---i-wish-i-had-one/</guid>
      <description>Currently Viv and I are planning our wedding for later in the year, which aside from being the most exciting thing ever, is really, really stressful. Apparently though, there are wed designers about, though I never realised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s my birthday soon</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</guid>
      <description>Did you not know? I&amp;#8217;m going to hit the grand old age of 26 soon. Whooah, thats like ancient. If you want some ideas of what you can get me (I obviously expect a gift), why not check my gift list here and here, to save the embarrasment of some really awful gift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Fools - Learn to Drive!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools---learn-to-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools---learn-to-drive/</guid>
      <description>It wasn&amp;#8217;t that long ago that I posted about coming off of my bike due to a slippery road, but this time was a bit different. Today somebody properly smacked me off of my bike! They were attempting to cut round a light-enabled junction when the lights had gone green in a different direction. As there is a small window of time only 1 or two generally make this turn, but this car decided that it should go even if it wasn&amp;#8217;t its turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ow! My arse!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</guid>
      <description>For the 3rd time I can remember ever I came off my bike this morning. I took a corner too sharply and ended up sliding across the road. So I am currently sitting here with gravel ridden hands and a really sore arse. I thought to go and check my arse when I finally arrived at uni and decided that it might be an idea to find something to stop the injury oozing all over my underwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone want to buy a car?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m selling my car, which has been with me for the last 4&amp;frasl;5 years and always been very reliable. It&amp;#8217;s a very nice Vauxhall Corsa 1.5 TD in red, for more details, check freeads here and drop me an email either through freeads or this website if you&amp;#8217;re interested.
I&amp;#8217;m pretty sad to see the thing go, but as I now have no need for it due to the acquiring of my own personal chauffeur, it seems a bit uneconomical to hang on to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Ubuntu? - ATI 9600 and SBLive</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu---ati-9600-and-sblive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu---ati-9600-and-sblive/</guid>
      <description>Another post about ubuntu? Where will it end?I was fairly excited from thursday evenings antics of getting things working on my machine at home, I thought I&amp;#8217;d give it a try with my dev machine at uni. My graphics card, a 9600 (yes ATI, I know!) had been screwed since the day I&amp;#8217;d put on Dapper, and to be honest, as I&amp;#8217;m not using it that much for GL stuff, I wasn&amp;#8217;t really bothered about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I speak too soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</guid>
      <description>It seems I may have spoken too soon about my linux joys with ubuntu. After performing a dist-upgrade on my previous beta version of Dapper, I discovered I&amp;#8217;d have to go through the same problems of downloading kernel source and linux header packages for my new kernel version.I also discovered after doing this that actually there were further problems on booting Dapper straight up. Apparently the pointers to drives get screwed up somewhere in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Working</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</guid>
      <description>FInally, after a grand total of 10 months, I have a 64bit version of Ubuntu Linux working upon my home machine.This is great news, not only does it mean that I have a wonderful OS to try out for size, but that I can easily convert my subversion server code and latex source to my machine.As I&amp;#8217;ve never mentioned it before, I&amp;#8217;ll detail what the problem was here. First up, the graphics card didn&amp;#8217;t have drivers which were working which meant that my X800 was pretty pathetic to be quite honest with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mull</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</guid>
      <description>So my holiday in Mull more than surpassed the expectations I had for it. Beautiful scenery, solitude, our own private beach, lots of sheep and cows etc etc. In fact, you had to be fairly careful negotiating the roads of Mull for fear of taking out the 50 odd sheep that would block our journey to and from the house. That and the rocks (which we experienced through a blowout). We visited the smaller islands of Iona and Staffa, with both being beautiful but Staffa getting my vote (its full of puffins, rather than americans).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays Soon!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</guid>
      <description>Woohoo, rock on &amp;#8211; its almost holiday season for me. Next week I&amp;#8217;ll be off to Scotland to the Isle of Mull for a week and a bit of unadulterated relaxing. Ahh&amp;#8230;Looking forward to it. Last years summer time in France was one of the best times I&amp;#8217;ve had in donkeys and I hope and expect this to be too. So to those who&amp;#8217;ll be there with me &amp;#8211; you best make it a good&amp;#8217;n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just been informed that my paper for CCGRID06 has been accepted, which I&amp;#8217;m very pleased about. It&amp;#8217;s my first paper acceptance in my 14 months of being based as a PhD at Cardiff University so really its about time I got some ideas out in the open to people. It&amp;#8217;s also based in Singapore, and I&amp;#8217;ve never left Europe &amp;#8211; yeah it&amp;#8217;s two days, but I&amp;#8217;m chuffed nonetheless.
The ironic thing is I was a bit annoyed last year at the fact CCGRID05 was in Cardiff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</guid>
      <description>My day was brightened lots yesterday when my my PhD supervisor informed me he had a blog on the subject of grid computing. It was intended for members of our research group to contribute to and discuss things. The most amusing part was, being cutting edge and all, you&amp;#8217;d expect it to be a bustling hive of activity. What I actually found was a site with two posts covering the last 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out with the Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</guid>
      <description>If anyone is interested in puchasing my old computer, I&amp;#8217;m getting rid of it.
It features:
 Athlon 2500XP Barton CPU 512Mb 3200 DDR Memory 80Gb 7200RPM Hard Disk Sound Blaster Live Drive 5.1 with Remote Control Sony DVD-ROM LG 52x24x52 CDRW Tyan Tachyon 128Mb G9600Pro (Ati Radeon &amp;#8211; fully boxed) 350W Levicom Blue Lit Dual Fan Power Supply (fully boxed) Antec Plusview Case (with side panel)  (fully boxed) 17&amp;#8243; Hansol 710D CRT Flat Monitor Logitech Keyboard/Mouse  Boxes/driver disks included, but supplied without any operating system (unless you want Ubuntu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</guid>
      <description>I cleaned out one of the boxes of papers kicking around my room the other evening. In it, I found an old lunch pass from school (featuring a photo sporting a lovely little version of me) and lots of old encouragement sheets we used to pass around our youth group to gets lots of positive comments on ourselves. Most of these are at least 5 years old and some stretch back to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It&amp;#8217;s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I&amp;#8217;d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she&amp;#8217;d brave the border as well to make those &amp;#8220;all important&amp;#8221; first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Wrongs don&#39;t Make it Right</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I&amp;#8217;d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it&amp;#8217;s quite the opposite really.
My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it&amp;#8217;s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a difference a year makes....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</guid>
      <description>So, in the absence of students, life continues as normal for the various research teams down here in the Queens buildings. We wake, march to University and sit in our little boxes reading, theorising and tearing our hair out until 5 o&amp;#8217;clock when we march back, only to be repeated the next day. I hate routines&amp;#8230;
Today marked the graduation of Year 3&amp;#8242;s which brought back memories of my graduation last year, which was pretty depressing to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Mental</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</guid>
      <description>Today I travelled on 2 planes, 3 buses and 1 car (thats a full house and extra) to make the 800 mile round trip to Edinburgh for part of a BioDiveristyWorld conference. I&amp;#8217;m quite surprised I managed to organise and sort out everything since Monday and it go according to plan.
I was actually really overwhelmed at how amazing the place was for the brief time I was there, the sheer scale of the city was something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normality Check</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</guid>
      <description>Our last day in Jard was rather less exciting than we&amp;#8217;d hoped, we decided to clean the place* we were staying in, so spent the morning doing that and unfortunately the weather was cack so didn&amp;#8217;t make for much of an afternoon either. We apparently caught the back end of a heatwave this week which has been rather fortunate, although pretty uncomfortable in the evenings. (Tim had it worse being in the same room as Mr &amp;#8216;Exorcist&amp;#8217; Pete, I had to endure that in Germany so it&amp;#8217;s his turn this time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastis and Miniatures - 22/06/2005 - 23/06/2005</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures---22/06/2005---23/06/2005/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday not a lot happened, except for much reading and bumming around the house whilst trying out my newly found juggling skills. We also went on our search for pastis, after discovering that it actually tasted much the same as oizo, a wicked aniseed flavour&amp;#8230;I think Rach may need to be educated in its use however, due to filling a wine glass neat with the stuff, which I would of been dead if I&amp;#8217;d actually consumed undiluted, or at least extremely quiet for the rest of the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Decided to make a move on to our next beach today, taking with us a picnic and a load of beer. This one is situated right next to a forest, which was ace for our picnic.
Tim, after 3 years of living with one another has finally managed to teach me to juggle and give me the bug for continuing it. It&amp;#8217;s actually easier to learn using boule, forcing you to use correct arm movements, though its a little dangerous on the beach if you have a distinct lack of footwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Marshes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</guid>
      <description>Today we went over to the salt marshes in Olonne, it being slightly more manageable weather and all. Tim basically wanted to do a little birdwatching and Heledd and Dave didn&amp;#8217;t fancy such french beauty so went to have coffee in a suitable village somewhere. It was really cool, took lots of photos of the strange green murky waters and had a bunch of exercise too. Saw loads of eels while we were there &amp;#8211; horrible things writhing about&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Sunday&amp;#8217;s morning events weren&amp;#8217;t overly exciting &amp;#8211; the weather has been so hot that it would be a bit much to go off and try to do anything. Instead has been a morning of reading (Dahl&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Boy&amp;#8217; &amp;#8211; bizzarrely featuring Cardiff, La Rochelle and Somerset within) and people trying to juggle. The afternoon became overcast so we decided to make the trip down to the beach, where Tim, Rach and Pete all got rather dirty trying to recreate a eurotunnel experience, which was destroyed as soon as it was completed by Dave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Journeys - 17/06/05 - 18/06/05</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys---17/06/05---18/06/05/</guid>
      <description>So, it begins, the holiday season that is and with it my two day trip across England and back down the west coast of France to Jard Su Mer. Todays trip was fairly long, spending two hours bombing down the M4 to meet with the guys in Reading, then a further few to reach the underside of London on the M25, and a bit more to finally bundle over toward the Eurotunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far have I come?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</guid>
      <description>Having free time in the evenings recently is a wonderful thing, and its given me the chance to think about &amp;#8216;stuff&amp;#8217; I might not of done otherwise, recently its been my undergrad life. When I came to University, I was all fired up for an amazing walk through Christendom, I tried to throw myself into the Christian Union, and for a while it was great. Unfortunately my work got a grip of me very quickly, and for all the wrong reasons I backed off from CU and any kind of fellowship with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vineyard reclaiming the web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Cardiff Vineyard have got to be the biggest bunch of bloggers I&amp;#8217;ve ever met, in a non-derogitory sense. Makes a change to Yeovil Community Church. Browsing around their main site and links from it, I&amp;#8217;ve found, hmm, lets see:
Cardiff Vineyard
Jon Matthias
Helen Carslaw
Lewis Parfitt
Neil Morgan
Zo&amp;euml; Morgan
Sarah-Louise
Thats crazy&amp;#8230;.! &amp;#8211; We&amp;#8217;ve got say 25 ppl max when I&amp;#8217;ve gone along, so thats over a 5th turned blogging converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Knackered...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been totally caning it over the last week or so&amp;#8230;. I&amp;#8217;ve got this Opengl graphics project due in very soon, and I&amp;#8217;ve been working like a bit of a bandit on it. On the other side of the coin, I&amp;#8217;ve got a databases piece due in on the same day which I haven&amp;#8217;t made a start on yet. Guess I&amp;#8217;ll be doing that over the weekend. Those will be in next week and then I&amp;#8217;ll have some time to get moving on my project again&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woe is me</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</guid>
      <description>Oh dear, today has not been good&amp;#8230;
After missing Church this morning, I proceeded to backup most of my hard disk onto my old ATA100 so that I could revert my main ATA150 partition back to a &amp;#8220;simple&amp;#8221; partition, so I *might * be able to install Linux.
After spending the best part of the afternoon backing up, I proceeded to download a partition tool to manage my partitions if Linux couldn&amp;#8217;t handle it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back with a vengeance</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</guid>
      <description>After having my account removed (presumably because I should&amp;#8217;ve theoretically graduated by now), making the move up to Cardiff, having my account reinstated and finally finding out that the web hosting had changed servers, with the mysql databases remaining on the same server (meaning that I had to change the &amp;#8220;99% of the time you won&amp;#8217;t need to change this&amp;#8221; value) I am now able to have b2 back up and running smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Joys</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to pummel my friends workmates at a bit of LAN gaming yesterday, I took the initiative and upgraded my computer this week. Placed an order on Monday, ordering just the CPU fan from a different store &amp;#8211; which proved to be a bad idea, it still hasn&amp;#8217;t turned up yet! &amp;#8211; preventing me from installing the CPU on my new motherboard&amp;#8230;..Tut Tut ebuyer..
All well, its nice to have shedloads of space on my machine now, even if I don&amp;#8217;t have any real need for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just got back from my Churches &amp;#8220;family fun&amp;#8221; event. They have been doing a whole bunch of different events this week as an opportunity to witness to those who might not normally come to YCC otherwise. Today was the big finale of the week and was basically all the families who had been a part of the week meeting up with the members of the Church.
What that amounts to is lots of barbeques and little kiddies events galore.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>