<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 12:52:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remove Disqus and 3x Your Blog Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/17/remove-disqus-and-3x-your-blog-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 12:52:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/17/remove-disqus-and-3x-your-blog-performance/</guid>
      <description>I got fed up recently of the insane number of requests that were given over to my use of disqus here on my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it enabled since moving from Wordpress to various other blogging engines, wanting to take my comments with me to a static blogging engine, but enough is enough. I remember disqus being a darling in the startup scene when it first launched in 2007 but it&amp;rsquo;s changed hands several times since and the idea that randoms ads may turn up on my blog at some point is a massive turn off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting an Octopress Blog on Amazon S3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/09/09/hosting-an-octopress-blog-on-amazon-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/09/09/hosting-an-octopress-blog-on-amazon-s3/</guid>
      <description>Octopress is a framework for blogging based on the static site generator jekyll. In short jekyll takes markdown and turns it into blog style html ready to be served straight away with Apache whilst Octopress dresses it up nicely with HTML5, responsive layout goodness and gives you a bunch of options for code formatting and the like. A perfect little blogging setup for hackers for those of us who typically won’t need all the bells and whistles on our blog I’m sure you’ll agree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
