<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:15:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Code Christmas Tree LEDs (and find their 3D Coordinates)</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/12/29/how-to-code-christmas-tree-leds-and-find-their-3d-coordinates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/12/29/how-to-code-christmas-tree-leds-and-find-their-3d-coordinates/</guid><description>This Christmas, I decided to make our tree lights incredibly complex so that I could marvel at my own animations running on them. That&amp;rsquo;s tongue and cheek, but also ended up being very true.
I&amp;rsquo;d been inspired by mathematician Matt Parker in 2020 where he did this. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll describe all the hardware I used and how it was connected and I&amp;rsquo;ll share the code I needed to write to capture the LED&amp;rsquo;s coordinates.</description></item><item><title>How to Setup Raspberry Pi OS: Bullseye like a Python Pro</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/11/29/how-to-setup-raspberry-pi-os-bullseye-like-a-python-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 17:29:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/11/29/how-to-setup-raspberry-pi-os-bullseye-like-a-python-pro/</guid><description>I setup my Raspberry Pi using Bullseye and installed many of the same developer tools I use on my main dev machine for Python upon it. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up here. I did this from scratch with a brand new install, with all available updates installed at the time. Bullseye is the most recent release of Raspberry Pi OS which came out earlier this month, based on Debian Bullseye.</description></item><item><title>Deleting Disqus Made My Blog Run 3x Faster</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/17/deleting-disqus-made-my-blog-run-3x-faster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 12:52:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/17/deleting-disqus-made-my-blog-run-3x-faster/</guid><description>I got fed up recently of the insane number of requests that were given over to my use of disqus here on my blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it enabled since moving from Wordpress to various other blogging engines, wanting to take my comments with me to a static blogging engine, but enough is enough. I remember disqus being a darling in the startup scene when it first launched in 2007 but it&amp;rsquo;s changed hands several times since and the idea that randoms ads may turn up on my blog at some point is a massive turn off.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Static Site Creation with Astro, Supabase and Netlify</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/10/automatic-static-site-creation-with-astro-supabase-and-netlify/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 10:27:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/09/10/automatic-static-site-creation-with-astro-supabase-and-netlify/</guid><description>This week, I revealed mixes.it - a very simple site I&amp;rsquo;ve created for indexing DJ mixes scraped from the web. I wanted a no-frills site that I could get Spotify playlists of DJ&amp;rsquo;s I like to see what new music they were playing and that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to spend much time supporting.
I used Astro and Supabase to create the site itself and the whole thing is currently built using Netlify.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Low-Code Tools as a Developer</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/08/10/comparing-low-code-tools-as-a-developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:02:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/08/10/comparing-low-code-tools-as-a-developer/</guid><description>When first hearing of the concept of &amp;ldquo;no-code&amp;rdquo; I have to admit I cringed a bit. The implication that a mere mortal client could combine services without ever getting a dev involved seemed cute and definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t lead to anything genuinely valuable.
I come from the age of Hackathons, where a devs would quickly put together really interesting combinations of services in the blink of an eye. They would do all this for nothing more than the joy of building, rather than the offer of expensive prizes from some well funded business as a form of motivation.</description></item><item><title>Why Python devs love Requests</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/07/08/why-python-devs-love-requests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:03:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/07/08/why-python-devs-love-requests/</guid><description>Requests is the HTTP client I and every Python developer I know always reach for when we need to pull data from remote sources. It got 121M downloads in June 2021 alone according to PePy and has 45.5k github stars at the time of writing. Developers love making requests with Requests!
At the time of Requests original release in 2011 urllib3 was the high level HTTP library of choice and Requests actually uses it as a dependency.</description></item><item><title>Build Your Own Pico Powered Midi Controller for $35</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/06/08/build-your-own-pico-powered-midi-controller-for-35/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 09:54:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/06/08/build-your-own-pico-powered-midi-controller-for-35/</guid><description>Find the video of this article on youtube
The Launchpad is a midi controller used for audio production with digital audio workstations (or DAWs) like Ableton. In comes in mini and standard forms and features 64 pads, along with 16 additional buttons ready to map to your application of choice. The mini version starts at £75, the standard is £145 and there&amp;rsquo;s an older &amp;ldquo;Pro&amp;rdquo; which is currently available for £179.</description></item><item><title>Installing Module Extras with Pipenv and Poetry</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:13:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</guid><description>I thought it worth documenting how to install &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; dependencies in Pipenv and Poetry after struggling to find the answer myself. Context: I hit a problem with uvicorn where the websockets module hadn&amp;rsquo;t been installed as a result of not including the &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; extras. Rather than return an error, it just failed to connect the websocket which made me think something was wrong with my network configuration.
As an example, take the following pip command:</description></item><item><title>YouTube Videos as Small Experiments</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/30/youtube-videos-as-small-experiments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:07:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/30/youtube-videos-as-small-experiments/</guid><description>The popularity of working on small experiments (or &amp;lsquo;bets&amp;rsquo;) as business ideas before investing a significant amount of time upon one of them is a model of work rapidly gaining traction with indie hackers.
It makes so much sense - when you&amp;rsquo;re small and in need of money to fund your work, you don&amp;rsquo;t waste time on ideas which are unproven. Instead you choose to work on a portfolio of many ideas over a short period of time to see which ones resonate with customers.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a New M1 Mac for Development</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</guid><description>I recently updated my 2012 Mac Mini with a 2021 M1 Mac Mini and decided to document the first time setup process. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up. What follows is all the steps in written form as a handy reference for you to copy and paste from - or future me. Surprisingly, the installation process was fairly simple now there are versions of software written for Apples new architecture.</description></item><item><title>Comparing VAT Solutions for Bootstrapped UK Businesses</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:32:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</guid><description>Laws on when to apply VAT have always been a complex beast - in 2015 the EU made changes that meant that VAT was to be calculated based on a customer location, introducing a VATMOSS system for its collection. Since leaving the EU things have become even more complicated if you happen to be based in the UK. You now are no longer able to make use of the VATMOSS system, meaning you potentially need to register for VAT in every EU country you sell products to (!</description></item><item><title>Creating Social Images with Puppeteer</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/16/creating-social-images-with-puppeteer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:07:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/16/creating-social-images-with-puppeteer/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to show how to generate images for sharing content on social networks like twitter and facebook using Puppeteer. This could be for any content - a post on our blog or something more complex like a dynamic storefront. So long as we correctly include open graph meta tags within the markup appropriate for the sites in question, our nicely designed image will be included as part of the apps feeds, rather than a blank preview.</description></item><item><title>The Years I've Spent on Side Projects Have Not Been Wasted</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/04/the-years-ive-spent-on-side-projects-have-not-been-wasted/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 10:04:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/04/the-years-ive-spent-on-side-projects-have-not-been-wasted/</guid><description>In my 18 years online, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent large chunks of time exploring ideas that never came into fruition. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone years building out software I&amp;rsquo;ve never made into saleable products for a multitude of reasons. The standard indie hacker journey would have you believe that this is time wasted, pointless where iterating quickly and shipping products that sell would get you to that magic monthly recurring revenue you so desperately desire.</description></item><item><title>Building a Cookiecutter Template for Multiple Python Package Managers</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</guid><description>In my previous post, I described how you can use Python and Makefiles to quickly get new projects started. In this post I explore how you can use cookiecutters more advanced Jinja templating techniques to make a cookiecutter that can be used for multiple package managers. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll be extending the existing template to build another that can be used with either Poetry or Pipenv.
Our New Cookiecutter Template As a reminder, Cookiecutter allows us to template project and directory content and structure using Jinja2 logic.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping Python Projects with Cookiecutter and Makefiles</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</guid><description>When starting a new project, it’s easy to get caught up in the excitement of starting the shiny new thing and forget about some basics. What starts out as a script slowly evolves into an application and before long you’ll find yourself repeating common steps for every project to get it to match personal preferences. If you happen to be working within on a team, you may have many repositories that should have the same setup and inconsistencies between them can quickly lead to large amounts of lost time to get them aligned.</description></item></channel></rss>