<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2008 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2008 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-Shirts from Fair &amp; Bare</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair--bare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair--bare/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m really pleased to announce that Fair &amp;#038; Bare has just released 2 new shirts. First up is “Feel the Force” based on a slogan submission by JonnyDanger and secondly is the fantastic Esther Aarts’ “My Bike is My Castle”. 

We printed these on super-soft, Fairtrade certified, organic in-conversion cotton using fantastic waterbased inks. They also look pretty darn good. It&amp;#8217;s the net result of a ton of hard work by our printers, designers, community and the original cotton original farmers that mean that these have been able to be released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair &amp; Bare Snowdodgers Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair--bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair--bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I announced that we&amp;#8217;re running our first design challenge in conjunction with team Snowdodgers at Fair &amp;#038; Bare. These are some really amazing fellas who are trying to raise £48,000 for charity by rallying a £200 banger round 4000 miles involving the Arctic circle. We&amp;#8217;re asking designers to get in designs relating to the chilly weather and the guys crazy antics!
If you&amp;#8217;re interested, you&amp;#8217;ve got just a month to get an entry in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweetcron is pretty sweet at Lifestreaming</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/08/31/sweetcron-is-pretty-sweet-at-lifestreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/08/31/sweetcron-is-pretty-sweet-at-lifestreaming/</guid>
      <description>For people like myself who are fairly erratic at posting regular updates to their blogs, you might do well to pass your eyes over to Sweetcron. Sweetcron does very well at pulling your content from other places on the web you may frequent and gathering it altogether in a neat little summary page automatically. This is otherwise known as a lifestream and has gained popularity as people tend toward exposing more of their activities on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare&#39;s first shirt!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a long time coming, but Fair and Bare&amp;#8217;s first t-shirt is now available to purchase!

Thanks to everyone who&amp;#8217;s participated since we kicked off. Really appreciate all your designs, words and support. We&amp;#8217;re still taking submissions for our competitions, so if you haven&amp;#8217;t hit us up already make sure you do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Web Meetup #3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to remind people that this coming week is the third Cardiff meetup for web types in wales. It&amp;#8217;s in 10 Feet Tall on Church St on Wednesday 4th June from 6.30pm. Featured speakers include Matthew Cashmore (Development Producer for BBC Future Media &amp;#038; Technology, Research and Innovation) and Tim Holmes (Course co-ordinator for the Postgraduate Diploma in Magazine Journalism and the MA International Journalism: Magazine Pathway at Cardiff University&amp;#8217;s School of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnny Lee&#39;s Innovative Uses of Common Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not sure how many visitors have caught this ted talk before, but I&amp;#8217;d thought I&amp;#8217;d post it anyway. Johnny Chung Lee is amazing, turning a $40 wii remote into use an interactive whiteboard or a new way to interact with video games via head tracking. He&amp;#8217;s been at this sort of thing for ages previously putting out a $14 steadycam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare - Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare---bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</guid>
      <description>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I&amp;#8217;m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with fairdos and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don&amp;#8217;t appeal to us at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that&amp;#8217;s bugged me for a while whilst having a website is that at certain times of the year when people might actually like to buy me a gift they&amp;#8217;re unable to find my wishlist. This is mainly because they&amp;#8217;re simple folk who might not think to check amazon for my name. I&amp;#8217;m also signed up with amazon associates, so I decided it could do me well to post my wishlist items along with my referral tag in the links in order to earn a bob or two on my own homepage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Code Igniter for Rapid PHP Application Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/31/book-review-code-igniter-for-rapid-php-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/31/book-review-code-igniter-for-rapid-php-application-development/</guid>
      <description>In this book, author David Upton walks you through use of the Code Igniter framework, which is essentially PHP&amp;#8217;s answer to Ruby on Rails. I&amp;#8217;ve been a avid user of Code Igniter since I discovered it last year, which is a nice waypoint for anyone trying to understand model-view-controller architectures and not wanting to make the move over to ROR quite yet.
The angle of this book is taken from a first time CI developer, but one with some knowledge of both PHP and web development in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location Based Job Boards</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/30/location-based-job-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/30/location-based-job-boards/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find about hearing about possible web development jobs on certain sites is the sheer amount of them which are simply unviable due to my UK location. Previously I decided to post all those jobs I could find to my own webtyrant site and the recent job and profile sites in the django communities has got me thinking about how these two pieces of information on locality could be aggregated together (I don&amp;#8217;t have time myself to do this though unfortunately &amp;#8211; perhaps someone might like to chat about collaborating).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Learning jQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Learning jQuery takes a look at the JavaScript library jQuery by Jonathan Chaffer and Karl Swedberg, whom run learningjquery.com, a popular resource to jQuery developers. Jonathan and Karl work through a example based approach of common problems in web application development to demonstrate how jQuery can be used to minimize the amount of code written by developers and instead focus on the functionality of their code. The book is set for the developer with some knowledge of HTML, CSS and Javascript but a jQuery novice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Filezilla Passwords with PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find in managing a number of websites is that I&amp;#8217;m always forgetting passwords. The version of Filezilla I&amp;#8217;m running however makes it easy to remember them again through its use of weak XOR encryption and a the key being hard coded into the software. I&amp;#8217;ve used a program previously called the Filezilla Password Recover, but it turns out that this is also extremely easy to extract them using a simple PHP script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>