<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poetry on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in poetry on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 09:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/poetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Poetry to use the active Pyenv to Create a Virtual Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/05/getting-poetry-to-use-the-active-pyenv-to-create-a-virtual-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/09/05/getting-poetry-to-use-the-active-pyenv-to-create-a-virtual-environment/</guid>
      <description>I found with a new poetry install that it refused to use the pyenv version of Python.
I needed to explicitly tell Poetry where to find the active pyenv:
poetry env use -- $(which python) After this, it works as expected.
Source: https://github.com/python-poetry/poetry/issues/651#issuecomment-861421651
Get Updates to Your Inbox My newsletter comes out every month and is stuffed with helpful stories, tools and code showing how developers like yourself ship efficiently. It also features articles and videos I&#39;ve recently published so you&#39;ll never miss out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use .env files with Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/02/18/how-to-use-env-files-with-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I love Poetry, but one thing I always find frustrating is having to add an additional package to my environments to read from .env files and access them as environment variables. I quite often default to Pipenv for simple projects to get round this. Turns out there’s now another way.
Poetry 1.2 will add plugin support to tweak or add to it&amp;rsquo;s default package management behaviour and @mpeteuil made one for .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup Raspberry Pi OS: Bullseye like a Python Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/11/29/how-to-setup-raspberry-pi-os-bullseye-like-a-python-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 17:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/11/29/how-to-setup-raspberry-pi-os-bullseye-like-a-python-pro/</guid>
      <description>I setup my Raspberry Pi using Bullseye and installed many of the same developer tools I use on my main dev machine for Python upon it. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up here. I did this from scratch with a brand new install, with all available updates installed at the time. Bullseye is the most recent release of Raspberry Pi OS which came out earlier this month, based on Debian Bullseye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Module Extras with Pipenv and Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I thought it worth documenting how to install &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; dependencies in Pipenv and Poetry after struggling to find the answer myself. Context: I hit a problem with uvicorn where the websockets module hadn&amp;rsquo;t been installed as a result of not including the &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; extras. Rather than return an error, it just failed to connect the websocket which made me think something was wrong with my network configuration.
As an example, take the following pip command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating PyPI Releases Using Poetry and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 10:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>In creating my first package on PyPI, I realised that many of the tasks I&amp;rsquo;d want to do on a subsequent publish would be repetitive. If I wanted to push out a simple fix, I wanted to automate away those tasks so I could focus on my code rather than a sequence of repetitive steps.
Github actions is a simple way to do this and has given me the ability to quickly push out changes without lots of manual work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
