<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Theme</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve long made use of the default theme on WordPress, which I&amp;#8217;ve always felt wasn&amp;#8217;t entirely &amp;#8220;me&amp;#8221;. The theme now live is one I&amp;#8217;ve been tinkering with for a while now based on the lovely preview design used in the prose.io document editing tool for github. I really like the focus on simplicity and think it suits me well.
I&amp;#8217;ve added some different styling for the navigation elements, given they didn&amp;#8217;t already exist on prose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin v0.2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0.2/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to say I&amp;#8217;ve updated the plugin that generates my filmstream pages. It&amp;#8217;s become obvious that the Lovefilm API only exposes the last 10 features that you&amp;#8217;ve rented in their &amp;#8220;at home&amp;#8221; list. This isn&amp;#8217;t that great if you&amp;#8217;ve been renting more than a few months. This is the same as the information you&amp;#8217;d see in your account when logged in.
I&amp;#8217;ve made a simple modification to use the actual ids that Lovefilm issue for films, rather than a autoincrement value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating WordPress Automatically over SFTP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp/</guid>
      <description>Heres a quick how to on getting wordpress to update over SFTP. On a default install of php, wordpress only gives the option to update over FTP. I wanted to get it working as it&amp;#8217;s more secure and means I don&amp;#8217;t have to open up FTP on my virtual server and open another port up in the firewall.
I&amp;#8217;m using ubuntu and the sequence of commands I followed were:
sudo apt-get install libssh2-1-dev libssh2-php  You should now find that if you list the modules installed in php and check if ssh2 is now there, you get the result &amp;#8220;ssh2&amp;#8243;:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin is No More</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more/</guid>
      <description>I think my post title says it all really. I&amp;#8217;ve just discovered that amazon has deprecated use of its ListLookup method since October 15th. I had used this in order to retrieve details of my amazon wishlist and display neatly on my blog using my wishlist plugin. Now it seems I&amp;#8217;m forced to generate one with their own widget builder. This in turn means my wordpress plugin will no longer work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Something I&amp;#8217;ve thought I&amp;#8217;d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I&amp;#8217;ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I&amp;#8217;m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I&amp;#8217;ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I&amp;#8217;ve got the opportunity to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Plugin v0.2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just updated my amazon associates plugin to take into account the recent signiture changes which amazon have introduced for their webservices api.
This now also means you&amp;#8217;ll have to enter your amazon secret access key in the plugin configuration page.
You can download the updated version over here.
It also means my wishlist has finally been brought back to life. Just in time for Christmas&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Your Own TinyURL Service for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t particularly like using URL shortening services. I think I first noticed them getting used rather prolificly in the Guardians technology section to include lots of random links to bizarre web content. TinyURL&amp;#8217;s own web site wouldn&amp;#8217;t particularly inspire me to go ahead and make use of it either. But, because of my own use of services such as twitter, I&amp;#8217;m forced to shrink down links to get within those 144 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that&amp;#8217;s bugged me for a while whilst having a website is that at certain times of the year when people might actually like to buy me a gift they&amp;#8217;re unable to find my wishlist. This is mainly because they&amp;#8217;re simple folk who might not think to check amazon for my name. I&amp;#8217;m also signed up with amazon associates, so I decided it could do me well to post my wishlist items along with my referral tag in the links in order to earn a bob or two on my own homepage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>