<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a New M1 Mac for Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/03/05/setting-up-a-new-m1-mac-for-development/</guid>
      <description>I recently updated my 2012 Mac Mini with a 2021 M1 Mac Mini and decided to document the first time setup process. You can also check out a youtube video I&amp;rsquo;ve made on setting it up. What follows is all the steps in written form as a handy reference for you to copy and paste from - or future me. Surprisingly, the installation process was fairly simple now there are versions of software written for Apples new architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing VAT Solutions for Bootstrapped UK Businesses</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</guid>
      <description>Laws on when to apply VAT have always been a complex beast - in 2015 the EU made changes that meant that VAT was to be calculated based on a customer location, introducing a VATMOSS system for its collection. Since leaving the EU things have become even more complicated if you happen to be based in the UK. You now are no longer able to make use of the VATMOSS system, meaning you potentially need to register for VAT in every EU country you sell products to (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Social Images with Puppeteer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/16/creating-social-images-with-puppeteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/16/creating-social-images-with-puppeteer/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to show how to generate images for sharing content on social networks like twitter and facebook using Puppeteer. This could be for any content - a post on our blog or something more complex like a dynamic storefront. So long as we correctly include open graph meta tags within the markup appropriate for the sites in question, our nicely designed image will be included as part of the apps feeds, rather than a blank preview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Years I&#39;ve Spent on Side Projects Have Not Been Wasted</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/04/the-years-ive-spent-on-side-projects-have-not-been-wasted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 10:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/04/the-years-ive-spent-on-side-projects-have-not-been-wasted/</guid>
      <description>In my 18 years online, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent large chunks of time exploring ideas that never came into fruition. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone years building out software I&amp;rsquo;ve never made into saleable products for a multitude of reasons. The standard indie hacker journey would have you believe that this is time wasted, pointless where iterating quickly and shipping products that sell would get you to that magic monthly recurring revenue you so desperately desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cookiecutter Template for Multiple Python Package Managers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/25/building-a-cookiecutter-template-for-multiple-python-package-managers/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I described how you can use Python and Makefiles to quickly get new projects started. In this post I explore how you can use cookiecutters more advanced Jinja templating techniques to make a cookiecutter that can be used for multiple package managers. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;ll be extending the existing template to build another that can be used with either Poetry or Pipenv.
Our New Cookiecutter Template As a reminder, Cookiecutter allows us to template project and directory content and structure using Jinja2 logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping Python Projects with Cookiecutter and Makefiles</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/01/07/bootstrapping-python-projects-with-cookiecutter-and-makefiles/</guid>
      <description>When starting a new project, it’s easy to get caught up in the excitement of starting the `shiny new thing’ and forget about some basics. What starts out as a script slowly evolves into an application and before long you’ll find yourself repeating common steps for every project to get it to match personal preferences. If you happen to be working within on a team, you may have many repositories that should have the same setup and inconsistencies between them can quickly lead to large amounts of lost time to get them aligned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a PEP and why should I care?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/16/what-is-a-pep-and-why-should-i-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 15:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/16/what-is-a-pep-and-why-should-i-care/</guid>
      <description>No doubt if you&amp;rsquo;ve been developing in Python for any length of time, you will have heard the acronym &amp;ldquo;PEP&amp;rdquo; mentioned quite frequently. More often than not you hear it when talking about Python code style, usually followed by the number &amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo;. So what is a PEP and why should you care?
What is a PEP? PEP stands for &amp;ldquo;Python Enhancement Proposal&amp;rdquo;. They are used to describe and summarise the technical design and reasons for enhancements to Python and surrounding processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Features in Python 3.9</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/05/interesting-features-in-python-3.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/05/interesting-features-in-python-3.9/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some features I found interesting in the release of Python 3.9 last month. You can see me talk about each of these in my latest video on youtube.
Full Release Notes
Merging and Updating Dictionaries PEP 584 - Dictionaries now have new union operators to work with them.
Python 3.8:
x = {&amp;#39;key&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;original_value&amp;#39;} y = {&amp;#39;key&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;updated_value&amp;#39;} print({**x, **y}) # Python 3.8 unpacking, kind of confusing Python 3.9:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Black to Format Python and get on with Your Life</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/03/use-black-to-format-python-and-get-on-with-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/03/use-black-to-format-python-and-get-on-with-your-life/</guid>
      <description>When I first started working in software development teams, I can remember heated discussions on pull requests on a few occasions. Typically these were when I or other developers reviewed code that didn&amp;rsquo;t meet formatting rules that were felt best for that piece of work. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether the rules in question were in code, documented in a README or just held in a developers head, the simple fact that something was wrong on the project meant the author needed to make changes, be severely reprimanded and never make the mistake again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy a Django App to the DigitalOcean App Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</guid>
      <description>Digitalocean recently launched their App platform, a platform as a service (PaaS) which can be seen as a competitor to the likes of Heroku. As a Python developer, I wanted to see how easy it was to deploy a django app to App platform. It took me a little while to configure everything correctly so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go through some of the points that tripped me up here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for some time for a relatively simple method for deploying my projects, but I also want to use a pattern where my repo is the primary source of truth for my app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing to PyPI Using Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 10:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>In creating my first package on PyPI, I realised that many of the tasks I&amp;rsquo;d want to do on a subsequent publish would be repetitive. If I wanted to push out a simple fix, I wanted to automate away those tasks so I could focus on my code rather than a sequence of repetitive steps.
Github actions is a simple way to do this and has given me the ability to quickly push out changes without lots of manual work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing a Package to PyPI with Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/20/publishing-a-package-to-pypi-with-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:04:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/20/publishing-a-package-to-pypi-with-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I recently published my first ever package to the Python Package Index (PyPI). The process was particularly novel for me as it meant my first ever use of the Poetry package management tool. If you happen to work in a production studio that uses ftrack and is now working remotely, you might even want to take a look at it as it enables sharing of assets using the Simple Storage Service (S3) from Amazon Web Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/12/06/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/12/06/purpose/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking recently about purpose for Nifty Digits and myself, reviewing the clients I’ve done work for in the past and that work which I’ve felt most fulfilled by.
I’ve straddled a path between web/pipeline developer thus far - so it’s fairly difficult to pin down what I do in a single mission statement. A more enterprising developer may well have done that as part of a business plan when they first started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhealthy Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/21/unhealthy-comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/21/unhealthy-comparisons/</guid>
      <description>As we nearing Christmas, we’re met with the familiar annual trickle of uplifting, heartwarming adverts that show just how wonderful your world will be if only you would buy your gifts from a particular retailer. After several weeks of this I’m already feeling bad for thinking our simple, paired down family Christmas experience might just not compare and wondering how anyone can’t help but feel any different after two months of constant commercial brainwashing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web Development Stack in 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Over my time as a web developer, I’ve jumped between many frameworks and languages, attempting to find ones that work well for me. This seems to be pretty typical for developers who always have a take on the latest trend, either to quickly adopt or criticise it.
I really wanted to be a member of the Ruby crew for a time and ended up buying multiple copies of “Agile Web Development with Rails”, before having the opportunity to really apply it to a project and disposing of them because the material was outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s in a name?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/16/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>I usually get one of two looks when I announce the name of my company as &amp;ldquo;Nifty Digits&amp;rdquo;. Either a “Ah, I like that” or a raised eyebrow. Generally, it’s the person latter in years who might raise an eyebrow.
When I picked the name, I was still a PhD student at University and wanted something that “sounded technical (digits), but also sort of British (nifty)”. I also was heavily influenced number of web design bloggers at the time, particularly Dan Cedarholm’s blog “Simple Bits”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/04/blogging-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/10/04/blogging-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>All my most recent blog posts seem to be about updating my blog tooling (much as Rick commented earlier today). By recent, I obviously mean within the last 5 years.
I back tracked through my blog updates and discovered I&amp;rsquo;ve used 5 different tools over my 15 year history on the web.
 Moveable Type (2003) b2/Cafelog (2003) WordPress (2003) Jekyll (2014) Metalsmith (2015) Hugo (2018)  Something got lost in the process of migrating through all these blogging platforms, using increasingly complex plugins to generate what is simple static html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Generated Forms with WTForms</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2017/04/18/user-generated-forms-with-wtforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2017/04/18/user-generated-forms-with-wtforms/</guid>
      <description>As part of my past work with the Office for National Statistics (ONS), I worked with the survey runner team to add additional features to their Electronic Questionnaire which enabled the business to take regular surveys electronically via the web. During my final months there, I took it upon myself to tackle what was seen to be one of the projects major pieces of technical debt, its use of a custom form renderer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s No Such Thing as a Side Project</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2016/01/20/theres-no-such-thing-as-a-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2016/01/20/theres-no-such-thing-as-a-side-project/</guid>
      <description>As a freelancer who has worked with clients using non disclosure agreements in the past, it&amp;rsquo;s often difficult to showcase or build a portfolio of my work. I&amp;rsquo;m not alone on this, I know. Sarah Parmenter for one has posted about this problem as a designer.
As a developer, I sometimes feel it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to easily show a concise representation of my work in a public arena anyway. How can I convey my role in what will usually be a complex process involving many other parties?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Metalsmith</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2015/06/30/blogging-with-metalsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2015/06/30/blogging-with-metalsmith/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m switching blogging platforms once more. Moving from Wordpress to Jekyll enabled me to no longer deal with the multitude of updates and protected me hacks I could be susceptible to, but Jekyll being written in Ruby (a language I&amp;rsquo;m not overly familiar with) has been a problem. I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to cobble together scripts to deal with the custom parts of my blog build, but it&amp;rsquo;s never felt like home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Camera RAWs with OpenImageIO and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/09/15/processing-camera-raws-with-openimageio-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/09/15/processing-camera-raws-with-openimageio-and-python/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the library OpenImageIO, an awesome tool for reading and writing image files. What makes this of particular interest is the sheer variety of image files supported (BMP, Cineon, JPG, JPG-2000, GIF, DPX, OpenEXR, Targa, TIFF) (as well as variety of camera raw formats) and the fact it can perform image transformations upon them very easily. Given it&amp;rsquo;s designed for use in media and VFX environments it sounds like it will be useful for the type of work I&amp;rsquo;ve previously been involved with in stop motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Shot Thumbnails from a video using FFMPEG</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/31/extracting-shot-thumbnails-from-a-video-using-ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/31/extracting-shot-thumbnails-from-a-video-using-ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Andy Davies asked the following question on twitter: Any ideas on how I can easily convert a video to a filmstrip?
&amp;mdash; Andy Davies (@AndyDavies) July 23, 2014  I found this pretty interesting, especially given I&amp;rsquo;d used various open source tools for assembling storyboards in the past. I knew it was possible to extract images at desired intervals and left it as that.
After a bit of digging last night, I discovered it&amp;rsquo;s actually possible to extract images based on changes in the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splitting a date range in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/01/splitting-a-date-range-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/01/splitting-a-date-range-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Dates are one of those annoying things that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be, but are regularly difficult in web apps. I used the following two methods in a recent page to neatly break a date range into distinct segments as part of a analytics app I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on. Hopefully someone else will find them helpful.
import datetime, calendar # Find the delta between two dates based on a desired number of ranges def datedelta(startdate, enddate, no_of_ranges): start_epoch = calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for being a more Productive Freelancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/16/tips-for-being-a-more-productive-freelancer/</guid>
      <description>Having heard the question raised on @workingoutshow, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take some time to share the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve found have really helped me be productive in my work. These may not work for everyone, but hopefully some points will help for others.
Find a Good Environment The single biggest change I&amp;rsquo;ve found which has had a major impact on my work is changing my environment. We&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to have a small garden at our house and with the arrival of my daughter back in October, I was quick to realise that working in the open plan lounge in our house just wasn&amp;rsquo;t a viable option any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting a Wordpress blog to Jekyll: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/02/porting-a-wordpress-blog-to-jekyll-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/06/02/porting-a-wordpress-blog-to-jekyll-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the second of my posts in porting a wordpress blog over to jekyll, I outline how I&amp;rsquo;ve replicated wordpress&amp;rsquo;s default permalink structure on my own blog.
Creating Category and Tag Pages Jekyll doesn&amp;rsquo;t create category or tag index pages for those categories listed in your _posts source. Instead, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use a plugin to recreate them. I used the tutorial here as the basis for my category/tag generator, with my plugins/generate_cats_and_tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting a Wordpress blog to Jekyll: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/05/20/porting-a-wordpress-blog-to-jekyll-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/05/20/porting-a-wordpress-blog-to-jekyll-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As my last post indicated, I recently made the decision to leave wordpress for jekyll for my blogging software of choice. There were a number of hurdles I had to overcome in order to get to a state I was happy with, emulating my previous blog structure. This first post details a few of the setup problems and how I&amp;rsquo;ve overcome them.
Using Compass for a Jekyll theme The first problem I hit was my use of compass to create parts of the theme I intended to use for my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/05/18/bye-bye-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/05/18/bye-bye-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made the move to jekyll for building this site. It is now hosted on github pages, comments are handled by disqus and my post source is written in markdown. My entire site is visible on github and revision control for post entries is handled there too.
What finally convinced me with the release of jekyll 2 was the introduction of native sass support. Originally, the prose theme I&amp;rsquo;m using for my site was using scss, which I later ported to a wordpress theme in order to blog with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright Law Finally Aligns with Me</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/04/07/copyright-law-finally-aligns-with-me/</guid>
      <description>On June 1st 2014, some much needed changes are being made to exceptions to copyright law which amongst other things, will allow conversion of personal media between file formats.
Finally, we’ll able to make personal conversions of digital media (at least they will be now counted as legal copies). I’ve long made copies of my cd’s to listen to whilst coding (iTunes allows me to do so simply) – but it is not currently legal to move these files to another storage medium, such as an mp3 player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Weeks 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3/</guid>
      <description>So, anybody paying close attention may have noticed I’ve skipped a week on updating my progress on shipping in March. There wasn’t much to report in week 2 aside from I was busily updating my Nifty Digits site. This hasn’t yet gone live, mainly due to some restrictions on current client projects and publishing about my previous work. I hope to be able to publish it before the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Week 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</guid>
      <description>I promised a progress update on how my attempt to get 4 projects shipped this month was going. On my first week, I decided to focus on my time tracking tool, hourglass. I’ve had this in the works for sometime and unfortunately, it’s fallen by the wayside to client work.
I’ve failed on my first week in getting this released to the world, but I’m far happier with how it’s working now and the value it might give to any potential user than previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a Linear Domain to an Ordinal Range with d3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had the opportunity of using d3 quite a lot over the past few months for a number of clients. It offers some amazing flexibility for chart generation and much more.
Anyway, I thought I’d share a quick tip I developed for mapping a linear set of values onto an ordinal scale. For those who’re seasoned pros at d3, this probably seems trivial, but had me stumped for some time today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</guid>
      <description>This month, I’ve decided to take some time out to ship projects.
I have a huge list of projects accumulating I’d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.
Currently I don’t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we’ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up an .is Domain with ISNIC</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/10/27/setting-up-an-.is-domain-with-isnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/10/27/setting-up-an-.is-domain-with-isnic/</guid>
      <description>I’ve purchased a couple of .is straight from the Icelandic Domain Registry (ISNIC) in the past year with a view to using them with my own vps. The process of setting up nameservers isn’t great, given their somewhat confusing management interface. That’s summed up in a recent tweet below. Looks like I just spent 39 euros on a domain I can’t use. Fucksticks.
&amp;mdash; Craig Lockwood (@craiginwales) October 26, 2013  Given the potential savings compared to a ‘normal’ registrar, it’s likely you’ll want to make use of ISNIC themselves – who are much like an Icelandic version of Nominet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decade on the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/08/14/a-decade-on-the-world-wide-web/</guid>
      <description>10 years ago today, I started this blog. That’s just under a 3rd of my life. In other words, that’s quite a long time ago.
I started out using Movable type and very quickly (3 days later) ditched it in favour of the b2 “weblog tool”, which WordPress was later spawned from.
Back then, I blogged frequently about what was going on in my life, which tended to centre around University coursework rather than technical posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Rate Britizens</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/07/06/second-rate-britizens/</guid>
      <description>I decided to attempt a simple app this week, first using GoCardless, then later the beta of Stripe. It requires the payment of funds between two individuals, neither of which might be a business. GoCardless suggests signing up to use their partner programme, which involves registering a user as a merchant. This isn’t entirely suitable given the individual will be asked many queries on the nature of their business (which they don’t have).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Developer Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/06/27/the-developer-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/06/27/the-developer-dream/</guid>
      <description>I suffer from idea overload. It seems that every day I have an idea for something. As a developer, I’m lucky in that to be able to take an idea to inception very quickly. Best of all, I can show it at inception stage to a huge audience (if I had one), garner feedback and quickly iterate on that idea. To date, I’ve mainly created these by myself – a casualty of doing paid work in the main like this too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Full Stack JS Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</guid>
      <description>Whilst node.js heralded an era of being able to use a single language for both server and client side development, nobody mentioned the confusion such an approach could cause. It’s inevitable that there’s going to be similarities in code that constructs data on the server and that which presents it on the client. The fact that the two are written in the same language and the structure of them is so tightly coupled can make it easy to lose track of where you are and what you’re doing when knee deep in code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Run a Fairtrade Business?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/28/so-you-want-to-run-a-fairtrade-business/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief retrospective of what I’ve learned in the 6 years I’ve been running Fair � Bare, a Fairtrade t-shirt company along with my wife.
If you’re a new follower of mine, you heard right – I run a Fairtrade t-shirt company. I’ve not actively been marketing it more recently for a number of reasons, but I still have a strong belief in our original vision. That vision was that Fairtrade shirts at the time weren’t being well received by the world, despite being available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up Relationships with CouchDB</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/01/breaking-up-relationships-with-couchdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/03/01/breaking-up-relationships-with-couchdb/</guid>
      <description>[NB: This is an unpublished post I wrote in 2010 on getting started with CouchDB. Therefore, despite all the code and examples being relevant, it may be considered somewhat &amp;lsquo;belated&amp;rsquo;]
Beware – there’s a bunch of home wreckers out there intent on removing the love of your life and replacing it with a wicked mistress.
For me, my first experiments working with databases were performed with Oracle, the staple of our computer science course at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Business with Developer APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis/</guid>
      <description>Those of your you who follow me on twitter will might be aware of a single day hack I attempted last week, which takes output from Lovefilm’s customer history and formats it so it can easily be imported into the lovely Letterboxd. It’s named Loveletterd and it seemed entirely appropriate to release it on Valentines day.
After hearing that Letterboxd had created a CSV import tool for it’s community to use and as I’m a Lovefilm developer, I felt like it would be a great use of my time to get to work on Loveletterd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introvert Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/07/introvert-interfacing/</guid>
      <description>You pay for your ticket, hotels, travel and then spend the rest of the year excitedly awaiting being able to attend the conference everyone is speaking about. Having travelled halfway across the country, braving weather you’d never ordinarily leave the house for, you arrive in the unrecognisable city. You’ve left your family to be here, which is heart wrenching at the best of times and your lonely hotel room is no comfort (especially given the number of beds it has).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Move Towards Static Websites</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/22/the-move-towards-static-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/22/the-move-towards-static-websites/</guid>
      <description>There’s some discussion on new podcast “The Back to Front Show” on why of late we’re seeing so many static websites cropping up. It seem like now more than ever, we’re seeing both developers and designers jump ship to this way of working, having long been using database backed solutions (such as WordPress/Drupal) to manage their publishing.
When I talk about a static site, I think of it of raw HTML sat on a server and nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Theme</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/21/new-year-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>I’ve long made use of the default theme on WordPress, which I’ve always felt wasn’t entirely “me”. The theme now live is one I’ve been tinkering with for a while now based on the lovely preview design used in the prose.io document editing tool for github. I really like the focus on simplicity and think it suits me well.
I’ve added some different styling for the navigation elements, given they didn’t already exist on prose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Choose Popular Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>I feel compelled to write this post so late in the day after clocking Tyler Renelle’s rant on github about his problems with the popularity of certain JS frameworks (in the main Backbone.js). After having written apps in a variety of JS frameworks (Backbone, Spine and Meteor), I’ve learned that the feature set of a framework is not the only thing I hold dear when making a choice between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/02/2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/02/2012/</guid>
      <description>So here we are in a brand new year. 2012 came and went without even the slightest apocalypse. Reflecting on what has been achieved this past year has found favour with others in the web profession so I thought I might try it. More importantly to me, it also seems like a good way to perhaps spur me on to achieve some firm targets this year.
My circumstances have dramatically changed since January last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Crap, I&#39;m a Frontend Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/23/oh-crap-im-a-frontend-developer/</guid>
      <description>When I was first tiptoeing in the waters of web development (early 2000′s), getting a grips on job descriptions was simple. There were 2 types of people in our industry: designers or developers. You either drew websites, or you built websites – that was it.
As time went on people seemed to invent new titles: “UX Designers” were the first to appear on the scene to me, and we’re still to this day figuring out what this role really entails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Cinema According to Lovefilm</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-according-to-lovefilm/</guid>
      <description>Given there’s a bit of lovefilm bashing going on in Wales at the moment, I thought I’d chime in with the most frustrating thing I found with communications from lovefilm.
Check out the following weekly email I used to receive (I’ve since unsubscribed), along with my annotations.

I really couldn’t care less about who lovefilm are sending into cinema’s to perform reviews and certainly don’t want it to be the first text I see in relation to that image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Images from SD Cards with PhotoRec</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/09/04/recovering-images-from-sd-cards-with-photorec/</guid>
      <description>I had the horrible situation last Sunday following removing a number of pictures using an SD reader from my SD card that when I inserted it in my camera, it registered nothing upon it. My heart sunk, because this card is stuffed full of images of me and my family (along with my 1 year old son growing up) and I was unsure of which ones I’d actually backed up. After perusing the hidden files on the card, all I could discover was the files I’d most recently transferred from the card….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scientist in an Adventure with Pirates</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates/</guid>
      <description>This is a talk I did back in May at unifieddiff about my time working as a web developer at Aardman Features. I talk quite a bit about the production process and what we take from staff in order to help them do their jobs properly. I quite enjoyed giving this talk – more so than those I’ve given in an academic capacity in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You’re Nowhere Near as Good a Hacker as You Think</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/13/youre-nowhere-near-as-good-a-hacker-as-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/13/youre-nowhere-near-as-good-a-hacker-as-you-think/</guid>
      <description>What are you doing? Why would you go down that road? Shouldn’t you be building something else? How long have you been doing this?
Sure you can fool your clients into thinking you’re adding value to their product. I know the truth. But how did you – with all your expertise get to the point in thinking that’s what you’re really doing?
This is your first project? Shouldn’t you be focusing on your clients problems?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does Steam store Indie Game The Movie?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/06/12/where-does-steam-store-indie-game-the-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/06/12/where-does-steam-store-indie-game-the-movie/</guid>
      <description>A quickie – but for all those that have downloaded “Indie Game the Movie” today from steam and are wondering where the video files are stored, you can find them here:
Steam/SteamApps/common/Indie Game The Movie/data/movies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Build It</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/05/03/if-you-build-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/05/03/if-you-build-it/</guid>
      <description>If my years in academia have taught me anything, it’s that insight obvious to you isn’t often obvious to others.
As a result, I’ve pretty much adopted a gung-ho hacker attitude towards getting my own ideas built whereby I’ll just often work to get an iteration of an site out as fast as possible. The only factor here is my own time and I’m in the fortunate position to have some of that available now and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Switch Your VPS in 2 Hours</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/03/01/how-to-switch-your-vps-in-2-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/03/01/how-to-switch-your-vps-in-2-hours/</guid>
      <description>Friday last week I woke up to a barrage of emails coming into my inbox. All of these were coming from notification of spam comments upon this very blog. By the time I’d woken up I’d had something like 75 emails. This was pretty strange given that Akismet was there guarding my blog ever since it’s been available and I’d never had a email about a dodgy comment since I’d set it up (something like 5 years ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where&#39;s my Full Stack Payment Service?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/02/16/wheres-my-full-stack-payment-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/02/16/wheres-my-full-stack-payment-service/</guid>
      <description>Unless you’ve been living under a rock, you’ll realise that there’s an uprising against paypal amongst developers. Most of this stems from the multitude of crazy requirements they put upon sellers and the locks they can put upon your account without notice.
This in part has led to a number of payment alternatives cropping up. Here in the UK for instance, you have Google checkout and checkout by Amazon pitching up against paypal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2012 - Self Help for Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012-self-help-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/23/new-adventures-2012-self-help-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>Last week, like many others working on the web, I took the trip to Nottingham for New Adventures 2012. I’d seen the wonderful praise dished out for it last year and felt like I wanted to see what it was all about first hand.
I’ve learnt from experience that the most important part of any conference is not the talks or speakers involved, but the community around it and therefore I headed up the night before to ensure I didn’t miss a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye 1 &amp; 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/12/goodbye-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/01/12/goodbye-1-1/</guid>
      <description>I just sent the following email to 1 � 1′s billing department. I’ve been with them for coming up to 7 years now and they were, when I first used them, the only registraar I knew about and I was really happy.
As the number of domains I own has grown, their account admin has become really totally useless to manage them all. I recieved a payment request out of the blue today and it tipped me over the edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagination in CouchDB Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/11/02/pagination-in-couchdb-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/11/02/pagination-in-couchdb-apps/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on some fun little node.js / couchdb projects of late. Given the fact I don’t use either as part of my work, I’ve spent some downtime experimenting and slowly iterating my approaches as I learn best practice.
I hit what I consider to be a fairly frustrating hurdle that couchdb threw up that I’ve been blissfully unaware of through all my couchdb dev. When it came to doing pagination it turns out I’ve always been doing it the “bad” way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting an Octopress Blog on Amazon S3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/09/09/hosting-an-octopress-blog-on-amazon-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/09/09/hosting-an-octopress-blog-on-amazon-s3/</guid>
      <description>Octopress is a framework for blogging based on the static site generator jekyll. In short jekyll takes markdown and turns it into blog style html ready to be served straight away with Apache whilst Octopress dresses it up nicely with HTML5, responsive layout goodness and gives you a bunch of options for code formatting and the like. A perfect little blogging setup for hackers for those of us who typically won’t need all the bells and whistles on our blog I’m sure you’ll agree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin v0.2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0.2/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to say I’ve updated the plugin that generates my filmstream pages. It’s become obvious that the Lovefilm API only exposes the last 10 features that you’ve rented in their “at home” list. This isn’t that great if you’ve been renting more than a few months. This is the same as the information you’d see in your account when logged in.
I’ve made a simple modification to use the actual ids that Lovefilm issue for films, rather than a autoincrement value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate, Don’t Preach</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-dont-preach/</guid>
      <description>Last week, tickets went on sale for dConstruct 2011 and sold out within an impressive 7 hours. Having attended in 2010 and 2008 and judging it to be filled with the highest calibre web celebs from across the globe, I coughed up the entrance fee as part of the excited gold-rush. The cost of £150 includes access to the pre and after parties and the conference itself.
These type of events are stuffed to the brim with amazing, intelligent web professionals, many of whom I would consider to be colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining References to Sockets with Express and Socket.io</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/04/maintaining-references-to-sockets-with-express-and-socket.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/04/maintaining-references-to-sockets-with-express-and-socket.io/</guid>
      <description>I hit a frustrating problem when trying to use expressjs alongside socket.io recently. The solution may seem somewhat trivial, but I struggled with it for a while, until finally asking for help on the socket.io irc channel. I’m not sure if a better solution exists for my case, but this is what I have for now.
In the main route of my express app, I needed to iterate across an array, performing a REST call using each element as a parameter and spit the results back for socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating WordPress Automatically over SFTP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/05/07/updating-wordpress-automatically-over-sftp/</guid>
      <description>Heres a quick how to on getting wordpress to update over SFTP. On a default install of php, wordpress only gives the option to update over FTP. I wanted to get it working as it’s more secure and means I don’t have to open up FTP on my virtual server and open another port up in the firewall.
I’m using ubuntu and the sequence of commands I followed were:
You should now find that if you list the modules installed in php and check if ssh2 is now there, you get the result “ssh2″:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of Hype in Web Development Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/03/31/a-survey-of-hype-in-web-development-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/03/31/a-survey-of-hype-in-web-development-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>I listen to quite a few web dev podcasts. Something that irks me about a lot of them, is how much they tend to hype their own shows, products or the like. Sure, they’re allowed to, it is their own podcast after all, often from their own businesses etc. I’m fully aware this all possibly contributes toward the success of shows, but it annoys me nonetheless.
One of these things is the title of the show itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog rolling with CouchDB, Express and Node.js</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/02/07/blog-rolling-with-couchdb-express-and-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/02/07/blog-rolling-with-couchdb-express-and-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Over the last little while, I’ve been doing a lot of playing with Node.js, mostly to run data collection scripts. Last week, I started following Ciaran Jessup’s tutorial on getting started with node.js, Express and mongoDB. Express acts as a framework to node.js, allowing you to work in a familiar mvc format in a not so familar server side language. I hit a few problems along the way in the tutorial, so I thought I’ve list a few of my findings here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin is No More</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/11/28/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin-is-no-more/</guid>
      <description>I think my post title says it all really. I’ve just discovered that amazon has deprecated use of its ListLookup method since October 15th. I had used this in order to retrieve details of my amazon wishlist and display neatly on my blog using my wishlist plugin. Now it seems I’m forced to generate one with their own widget builder. This in turn means my wordpress plugin will no longer work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing gPhoto on Snow Leopard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/09/09/installing-gphoto-on-snow-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/09/09/installing-gphoto-on-snow-leopard/</guid>
      <description>I always seem to choose the difficult route to do things. Having become equipped with a new canon camera, I’m instantly wanting to capture stop motion shorts with it. Unfortunately canons proprietry capture software isn’t really up to the job and FrameByFrame doesn’t work with such high-end cameras.
So, I got to thinking wether there was any other route? I was aware of the gPhoto commandline interface and libgphoto pointed out by a colleague some time ago, so I thought I’d see what I might be able to do with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How not to: Do A Hack Day</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day/</guid>
      <description>It’s been well over a month since I attended science hack day and I’d thought I’d put out some notes on my time there. Rather than do a run down of the event, for which I’m sure there’s far more comprehensive blog posts available already, I thought I’d share my experiences based on attendance of a number of different hack events I’ve been to over the years. I went with the full intention of doing some hardcore hacking, but didn’t entirely meet my own expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MPlayer on Snow Leopard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/06/15/installing-mplayer-on-snow-leopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/06/15/installing-mplayer-on-snow-leopard/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a heads up for anyone installing MPlayer on Snow Leopard. I’ve been playing a fair amount with tools recently and inevitably ending up running round in circles in installing, compiling, setting flags etc. Here’s a quick one liner param for anyone compiling mplayer (and freetype as its dependency) which people on Snow Leopard may find useful.
You’ll first need to download latest versions of freetype and mplayer. Uncompress both. (Check here that the command “file /usr/local/lib/libfreetype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Something I’ve thought I’d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I’ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I’m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I’ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I’ve got the opportunity to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixbooth</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/03/21/mixbooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/03/21/mixbooth/</guid>
      <description>Mixbooth is a dj mix hosting service I created several years ago. At the time there wasn’t a lot around in terms of options for allowing anyone to share them. You either had to exchange it upon a site filled with advertisements, or host it on your own space which might mean you’d breach your server bandwidth for any given month. I decided to use some space I had available at next to nothing to build something that might be of use to myself and any other dj whom saw fit to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair  Bare - January £10 Sale!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair-bare-january-10-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair-bare-january-10-sale/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Plugin v0.2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just updated my amazon associates plugin to take into account the recent signiture changes which amazon have introduced for their webservices api.
This now also means you’ll have to enter your amazon secret access key in the plugin configuration page.
You can download the updated version over here.
It also means my wishlist has finally been brought back to life. Just in time for Christmas…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Google</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently read a post over on the guardians technology site which gave a whistle-stop history of the internet as it turns 40. I thought I’d share here my own experiences of growing up alongside the web, more for my own record than anything.
I remember at school a time at which there was no external connection, nor internal network (which we the pupils used) so the Acorn machines used at our school at the time could communicate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aardman</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/09/26/aardman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/09/26/aardman/</guid>
      <description>In order for me to generate this post I’ve created something quite novel on my blog – a new category which I’ve not had a great deal of experience in previously, “work”. For the last couple of months I’ve been working for Aardman features in Bristol on their forthcoming feature film, “Pirates” – building software, which I’ll be doing at least for the next couple of months too.
I’ve been having an amazing experience over this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Your Own TinyURL Service for WordPress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/16/create-your-own-tinyurl-service-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I don’t particularly like using URL shortening services. I think I first noticed them getting used rather prolificly in the Guardians technology section to include lots of random links to bizarre web content. TinyURL’s own web site wouldn’t particularly inspire me to go ahead and make use of it either. But, because of my own use of services such as twitter, I’m forced to shrink down links to get within those 144 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vicious Circle of Posting Quality Content</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/15/my-vicious-circle-of-posting-quality-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/05/15/my-vicious-circle-of-posting-quality-content/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been looking back at the posts on this site and the commitment that I supposedly made (internally) a couple of months ago about posting regular, interesting content. But it seemed to die a death very promptly.
I think that there may be a bit of a vicious circle here (in my own situation at least). I’d love to post regular interesting stuff, but for that to happen I need to feel that it might be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has web use changed your life?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been pondering this morning how the use of the internet has (or may have) changed my life. As a child/teen during the web’s infancy, I was blissfully unaware that so many lifes/careers/relationships would be enabled or changed as a result of the interactions it might facilitate. I hadn’t even heard of google prior to arriving at university and two years prior to that had never had internet access anywhere locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Fry and the Ascent of &#34;Micro Blogging&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/06/stephen-fry-and-the-ascent-of-micro-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/06/stephen-fry-and-the-ascent-of-micro-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is all over the news at the moment. For the uninitiated, it allows you to list short updates of what you are doing at any time. BBC News seemed to have an all-out assault at the end of January raving about it at every opportunity – the first moments of the Hudson plane landing, an short chat about it by Stephen Fry on Friday Night with Jonathan Ross and this short clip on iPlayer by Stephen Fry again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Music Blogs getting a Raw Deal?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/31/are-music-blogs-getting-a-raw-deal/</guid>
      <description>I can’t help but feel a little sorry for music blogs as of late. I’m sure you may be familiar with The Hype Machine and may use it on a daily basis. For the uninitiated, it is essentially a music blog aggregator, which takes details of tracks and ranks them based on how often they appear and how popular they are. I’ve found it really interesting to browse around and discover new artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I have to contribute?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/29/what-do-i-have-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>It has struck me over the last couple of days and it’s a reflection of my attitude to being interested in geeky things in general. I’m an elitist. When I started my blog back in 2003, I loved the fact that relatively few of them existed. It was a reflection of my day to day life and I felt my voice was being heard (even though I had no analytics tools to back that up and it was not particularly interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale Design Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/01/13/fairy-tale-design-challenge/</guid>
      <description>It seems that all I do these days is talk about what’s going on over at Fair � Bare and if you’re here because you prefer the more geeky side to me I apologise I’ve not been indulging you recently. However, that said, these posts do represent a significant part of me right now and what’s going on in my life so I think it fair I shout about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-Shirts from Fair &amp; Bare</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/20/new-t-shirts-from-fair-bare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair &amp; Bare Snowdodgers Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair-bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/11/03/fair-bare-snowdodgers-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I announced that we’re running our first design challenge in conjunction with team Snowdodgers at Fair � Bare. These are some really amazing fellas who are trying to raise £48,000 for charity by rallying a £200 banger round 4000 miles involving the Arctic circle. We’re asking designers to get in designs relating to the chilly weather and the guys crazy antics!
If you’re interested, you’ve got just a month to get an entry in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweetcron is pretty sweet at Lifestreaming</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/08/31/sweetcron-is-pretty-sweet-at-lifestreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/08/31/sweetcron-is-pretty-sweet-at-lifestreaming/</guid>
      <description>For people like myself who are fairly erratic at posting regular updates to their blogs, you might do well to pass your eyes over to Sweetcron. Sweetcron does very well at pulling your content from other places on the web you may frequent and gathering it altogether in a neat little summary page automatically. This is otherwise known as a lifestream and has gained popularity as people tend toward exposing more of their activities on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare&#39;s first shirt!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/07/22/fair-and-bares-first-shirt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Web Meetup #3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/31/cardiff-web-meetup-#3/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note to remind people that this coming week is the third Cardiff meetup for web types in wales. It’s in 10 Feet Tall on Church St on Wednesday 4th June from 6.30pm. Featured speakers include Matthew Cashmore (Development Producer for BBC Future Media � Technology, Research and Innovation) and Tim Holmes (Course co-ordinator for the Postgraduate Diploma in Magazine Journalism and the MA International Journalism: Magazine Pathway at Cardiff University’s School of Journalism, Media and Cultural Studies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnny Lee&#39;s Innovative Uses of Common Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/30/johnny-lees-innovative-uses-of-common-technology/</guid>
      <description>I’m not sure how many visitors have caught this ted talk before, but I’d thought I’d post it anyway. Johnny Chung Lee is amazing, turning a $40 wii remote into use an interactive whiteboard or a new way to interact with video games via head tracking. He’s been at this sort of thing for ages previously putting out a $14 steadycam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair and Bare - Bringing Design to Fairtrade</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/05/06/fair-and-bare-bringing-design-to-fairtrade/</guid>
      <description>Some of the visitors to this site might be aware that I like my t shirts, each with their bold and awesome illustrations. I’m also quite an avid supporter of fairtrade, being involved with fairdos and purchasing fairtrade options such as tea and chocolate where possible. One of the big bugbears my friends and I have always had in the support of the fairtrade movement is that many of the designs put across upon fairtrade cotton products don’t appeal to us at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that’s bugged me for a while whilst having a website is that at certain times of the year when people might actually like to buy me a gift they’re unable to find my wishlist. This is mainly because they’re simple folk who might not think to check amazon for my name. I’m also signed up with amazon associates, so I decided it could do me well to post my wishlist items along with my referral tag in the links in order to earn a bob or two on my own homepage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Code Igniter for Rapid PHP Application Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/31/book-review-code-igniter-for-rapid-php-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/31/book-review-code-igniter-for-rapid-php-application-development/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location Based Job Boards</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/30/location-based-job-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/30/location-based-job-boards/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find about hearing about possible web development jobs on certain sites is the sheer amount of them which are simply unviable due to my UK location. Previously I decided to post all those jobs I could find to my own webtyrant site and the recent job and profile sites in the django communities has got me thinking about how these two pieces of information on locality could be aggregated together (I don’t have time myself to do this though unfortunately – perhaps someone might like to chat about collaborating).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Learning jQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/09/book-review-learning-jquery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Filezilla Passwords with PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find in managing a number of websites is that I’m always forgetting passwords. The version of Filezilla I’m running however makes it easy to remember them again through its use of weak XOR encryption and a the key being hard coded into the software. I’ve used a program previously called the Filezilla Password Recover, but it turns out that this is also extremely easy to extract them using a simple PHP script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stick to your guns - You&#39;ll be rewarded</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded/</guid>
      <description>I’m a firm believer that by upholding my own principles, I’ll be rewarded. It’s a tag line I adopted for the small hosting company that I’ve been running for a while now. It also has been reflected this year in a nasty situation I was left in with my landlords, the council and a previous housemate (who doesn’t really deserve that title, more just a person whom shared the house). In all these situations things have turned out better for me in the long run, due to myself re-enforcing what I believe should be done – even if it does mean a longer struggle through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Cardiff Geek Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiff geeks will be having its first ever face to face on Wednesday 17th October from 7pm at Cafe Floyd, just opposite the castle. Props to Dan Zambonini for organising the venue.
This is an informal, introduction between us all. If you’re a geek, or interested in chatting with us about what we and you are passionate about, make sure you get over there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undeserved Job Titles</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</guid>
      <description>Today on the return from uni I passed the new Subway that is opening up soon near Queen Street train station. On one of their job adverts, they were advertising for team leaders and sandwich artists. I’ve never really noticed my sandwiches being arranged in a artistic fashion before, maybe it would brighten my day if they were. I feel sorry for the poor art school graduate who ends up filling baguettes for a living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my “business” cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing “beta” on hand hand-made ones or something…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of “The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain”, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Geeks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</guid>
      <description>I’ve long wondered why there doesn’t seem to be much happening in terms of community of the web professionals in wales. There is a vibrant collection of people sporting different skill sets in the area, yet as I can see not a lot of chat amongst everyone in between different groups. On a whim, I decided to create a facebook group “Cardiff Web Geeks” to try and get people to come out of their shells and actually participate in a bit of discussion about tech topics in wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New iPods - 160Gb or Touch Interface?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods-160gb-or-touch-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods-160gb-or-touch-interface/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing too much?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/31/sharing-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/31/sharing-too-much/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neckache</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</guid>
      <description>The other evening I managed to stretch my back awkwardly and I’ve been feeling the repercussions of it ever since. It’s extremely painful to move my head, arm or neck and I’m getting really frustrated by not being able to sit at the computer without being uncomfortable. Wednesday night I was flat out in bed not able to move an inch, and little more of an improvement last night. It’s making me really tired and irritable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Bristol</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stag Do</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</guid>
      <description>Now that the big day has passed, I thought I’d start revealing how some of my days in the lead up to it were spent. For my stag do, firstly we had a fairly quiet night in playing computer games, after doing a shop at Asda and getting the majority of mates locked out of our new pad. Many laughed at my wii fighting skills. Saturday, we travelled over to the Forest of Dean to climb through the tree-course that is Go Ape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where have I been?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</guid>
      <description>Is a question you may have asked yourself once or twice on the absence of any written word on this site. Well, aside from not being here – I’ve been doing many things including moving house from my home of 3 years, playing a small part in organising a wedding and actually getting married (I know!). I’ve also just returned from honeymoon with wife in tow and now we’re trying to figure out where all our stuff should go when it’s never had a home before and we’ve never owned it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want this Coffee Table Please</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/19/i-want-this-coffee-table-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/19/i-want-this-coffee-table-please/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thou Shalt Always Kill</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</guid>
      <description>I am loving this track I just discovered on Adam Fletchers blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re off to see the Hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</guid>
      <description>The wonderful hackers of, er Britain. When I say we, I actually mean me because my wife to be has to head back to Abergavenny before me. Which means that actually I’ll be the only one able to make use of my free invite to see the rumble strips. Oh well.I’m actually a bit nervy about heading over – I have done an extreme lack of preparation in terms of programming and I’m going to be sleeping in a room full of nerds and pcs, or possibly not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s up with Last.fm?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</guid>
      <description>Last.fm seems to be down at the moment for the last couple of minutes. Anyone know what’s going on?[Update:Looks like this was just a blip, ho hum]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Developer Day</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just returned from my stint in the South East after being invited to attend Googles London Developer day on thursday and remaining there to hang out in Haddenham for the weekend. Theres a ton of photo’s over on a picasa web album which has been built up from peoples pics. I even got interviewed regarding using the google web toolkit, but my experience was not exactly extended so I don’t know if it would get used at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay for DevDay!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/24/yay-for-devday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/24/yay-for-devday/</guid>
      <description>Wow! A long time ago I signed up for google’s developer day, to be on their waiting list. I’d completely forgotten but just got an invite asking me if I wanted to come along. Crazy! First yahoo, now google! I’m very, very excited.Obviously I am not more excited about either of these days than my wedding day… </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay for Hackday!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</guid>
      <description>I just heard I’ve got invited to Hackday! That’s totally awesome, I’m really excited! I signed up half expecting to be told to “go jump” and I’d contacted the administrators of the list due to hearing nothing about it and some confusing responses at first – but I just got my proper invite. Woo! – Impressive as I didn’t put much of an explanation of my work on there. I guess it was my sob story about my ongoing PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to acquire Yahoo? - Cost? $50 Billion!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/04/microsoft-to-acquire-yahoo-cost-50-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/04/microsoft-to-acquire-yahoo-cost-50-billion/</guid>
      <description>Mashable is reporting that a Microsoft-Yahoo merger may be on the cards, which is a fairly bizarre prospect.
The price? $50 Billion, is Yahoo only worth 30 odd YouTubes? I for one think not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big it Up for Yeovil!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</guid>
      <description>Browsing across Matt Westcotts site yielded this particular gem. [I&amp;rsquo;m from there don&amp;rsquo;t you know?]. I used to love tracking it up in fasttracker, but haven’t done anything for a very, very long time. Maybe I should start experimenting again….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check the Prices in Your Area</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/17/check-the-prices-in-your-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/17/check-the-prices-in-your-area/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that not only can http://rightmove.co.uk hunt down all the prices of current houses for sale in your area, it will also give you the prices that houses have gone for for the last 7 years? I didn’t, but tonight I enjoyed checking out the fact that someone bought a house in my road for £40k in January (but I think either this is a typo, or the place is a hole!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joost Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/12/joost-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/12/joost-beta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bills are Boring</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</guid>
      <description>Doing household bills is extremely boring. I just spent two hours dividing up the phone bill and working out who owes what. If marriage brings me anything, at least it will bring me less of a headache when it comes to doing the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashup!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threshers Voucher Number 2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/21/threshers-voucher-number-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/21/threshers-voucher-number-2/</guid>
      <description>[via Vecosys]I’ve just read on vecosys’ blog that Stormhoek has just posted Threshers Voucher Number 2. This will most certainly come in handy for all that wine we need to get for the wedding….Go grab it over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threadless launches Threadlesskids.com</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</guid>
      <description>Threadless has launched threadlesskids.com – like threadless, but for kids. I suppose that should come in handy for Jake and Shondis recent announcement. Anyway, it looks wicked – its amazing how the kids stuff costs more than adult though! My friends told me kids are expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wed Designer - I wish I had one!&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer-i-wish-i-had-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer-i-wish-i-had-one/</guid>
      <description>Currently Viv and I are planning our wedding for later in the year, which aside from being the most exciting thing ever, is really, really stressful. Apparently though, there are wed designers about, though I never realised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>If anyone else like me is considering working in the uk “web 2.0″ market, and finds the posts on common job boards clogged up with all the jobs from america, the small job board I have created and posted online might be a help. You’ll find it over at: http://webtyrant.com/jobs. It aggregates some common job boards together like 37Signals and ThinkVitamin, but removes anything but those located in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pMachine changes its name</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</guid>
      <description>pMachine has changed its name to Ellislab, and are sporting a shiny new website for all to see. The reason for the change is the expansion over the last 6 years to encompass products which don’t fall under the same banner now. I’m glad to see that the CodeIgniter website has got a facelift. 31three did the hard graft on the design and they all look awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenID - The end of multiple passwords?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/08/openid-the-end-of-multiple-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/08/openid-the-end-of-multiple-passwords/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hearing some really good stuff about openID recently. For those who don’t know, this is a online identity standard which promises to be the end of having multiple passwords at just about every single website you visit. It’s recently risen to light with the adoption by WordPress.com as a provider and digg as an adopter.Complaints against wordpress.com’s non-allowance of logins with openID’s created anywhere else than wordpress.com seem quite well founded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s my birthday soon</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</guid>
      <description>Did you not know? I’m going to hit the grand old age of 26 soon. Whooah, thats like ancient. If you want some ideas of what you can get me (I obviously expect a gift), why not check my gift list here and here, to save the embarrasment of some really awful gift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes the Fuzz</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/here-comes-the-fuzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/here-comes-the-fuzz/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, Cineworld gave us tickets free to any film of our choice when we were meant to be seeing a preview, due to a cock up at their end. I already knew what it would be without looking at what was out, Hot Fuzz.
I’ve loved Simon Pegg ever since the days of Big Train, when humour was just so completely random it had to be funny. Shaun of the Dead had some great random moments in it, but I left it feeling that it wasn’t the best I’d come to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for Beatbox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</guid>
      <description>This link sent to me by Lewis made me laugh quite a lot. Funnily, it looks a lot like him with a wig on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Star Wars</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/02/silent-star-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/02/silent-star-wars/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered this amusing star wars video coutesy of Jason Cospers blog. Highly amusing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Coloured iPod Shuffle</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/01/new-coloured-ipod-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/01/new-coloured-ipod-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Thought I’d just point out that apple uk are touting the new ipod shuffle today. Basically they have launched a bunch of extra colours, with no change to size or capacity, but they do look rather pretty. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotdealsuk - Indexing the webs best deals</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Web Apps, Future of Web Design</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>If anyone would like to contribute to allow me to attend the Future of Web Apps or the Future of Web Design conferences over the next few months, I’d put together some independent reviews of the events on this site. As the funds of a lowly research student are not all that much cop, you can donate some funds using the donation page.At the moment, registration for Web Apps is £195 + VAT (£595 + VAT including workshops), and Web Design is £59 +VAT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MS Firefox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft and Firefox have joined to bring us MSFirefox. Finally Microsoft have seen the light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today is not a good day to cycle!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Richmond road in Cardiff today is pretty much like a river all the way down today, due to all the horrid weather hitting it, resulting in the following set of footprints (post cycling to work) around my office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t every day be a holiday?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</guid>
      <description>I had a some great times away on holidays recently. The first was at New Year in Rhayader with the usual suspects getting absolutely soaked and vowing never to let anyone else plan a walk ever again. It was good to get outside away from these pesky machines.
As if that wasn’t enough, I went away to France to the slightly more exciting Alps for a skiing holiday for a week too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TechcrunchUK Non-Pantomime Continues</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/21/techcrunchuk-non-pantomime-continues/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, according to the free English dictionary there is a couple of definitions other than the traditional UK understanding of the word pantomime. For those international readers who don’t know, a pantomime is a pretty awful example of B-List celebrities acting ability in the UK in which involves them dressing up in bad costumes and acting out a fairy tale or story. In Cardiff, the big panto is Jack and the Giant Beanstalk – where Jack is played by John Barrowman (or Captain Jack from Torchwood and Dr Who).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg gets Video and Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/digg-gets-video-and-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Digg.com is sporting the ability to be able to now rate online video and podcasts. Postcast searching is in limited beta for registered users only.I just spent a while perusing some items of interest, and found a great segment of play! over on google. This just builds on the fact that Mario has the most awesome music ever.The searching of podcasts is dangerously close to an idea I’ve currently working on myself for a while now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything in Moderation</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/everything-in-moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/19/everything-in-moderation/</guid>
      <description>Apparently coke isn’t that good for you – a few of my friends might like to take heed of that advice. But, you can do some cool things with a lot of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Sethi has Nowhere to Blog?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-has-nowhere-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>It seems, according to Ben Metcalfe, that Sam Sethi has had his typepad account disabled by Six Apart, rendering him unable to post any updates on his recent departure from TechcrunchUK. Loic Le Meur (Executive Vice President of Six Apart and General Manager of Europe, Middle East and Africa) is currently giving no information about the whole scenario upon his own blog.UPDATE: Apparently Sam Sethi’s blog is up and running, though he has to yet confirm this and post his take on the whole scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sam Sethi is sacked from Techcrunch UK</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/14/sam-sethi-is-sacked-from-techcrunch-uk/</guid>
      <description>Techcrunch UK, Techcrunch’s european sister site has recently had a lot of activiity from some notes which the editor at the time, Sam Sethi made about the recent leweb3 event.This invited some comments from Six Apart’s Loic Le Meur in which he called Sam “an asshole”. Sam subsequently posted another blog about the fact that TechcrunchUK would be setting up its own events and workshops in the forthcoming year. It seems this displeased techcrunch’s Mike Arrington enough to give Sam the boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Fools - Learn to Drive!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools-learn-to-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/04/crazy-fools-learn-to-drive/</guid>
      <description>It wasn’t that long ago that I posted about coming off of my bike due to a slippery road, but this time was a bit different. Today somebody properly smacked me off of my bike! They were attempting to cut round a light-enabled junction when the lights had gone green in a different direction. As there is a small window of time only 1 or two generally make this turn, but this car decided that it should go even if it wasn’t its turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Threadless rule or not?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/does-threadless-rule-or-not/</guid>
      <description>Last night I perused a number of articles describing the success of my favourite t-shirt store threadless, the first of which – over at 37Signals reviews in a positive light and the second in a more negative one.Threadless is a t-shirt company with a difference, it’s a 24-7 competition allow you to become the designer. Designs are chosen by the team, and are able to be rated by the community that operates around the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got no hot friends? - Fake Your Space!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/got-no-hot-friends-fake-your-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/12/01/got-no-hot-friends-fake-your-space/</guid>
      <description>I heard about fakeyourspace via mashable today, which offers the ability to purchase your own social networking friends to leave messages and comments on communities such as myspace and facebook (the only two web pages I ever see to be open when supervising university labs). In their own words:*“If you are tired of seeing everyone else with the hottest friends and want some hotties of your own, then this is the place for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Demand Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/19/on-demand-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/19/on-demand-access/</guid>
      <description>I don’t really understand microsoft, over the last few days, their live network has been experiencing problems every time I’ve tried to logon to access my email. Who knows what my 8 emails contain which are hidden within live mail, I certainly don’t. You would think that more people would be in uproar about this – I mean what if these were payment requests, final demands or quick response business proposals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Web Applications - London 07</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/future-of-web-applications-london-07/</guid>
      <description>Registration is open for the Future of Web Apps conference in London 07. I’d love to go, loads of great companies/people talking (good to see Last.fm making an appearance), loads of schmoozing (if thats the appropriate word), but unfortunately absolutely jack to do with my PhD, so no funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zach Braff Makes an Appearance at Threadless</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/zach-braff-makes-an-appearance-at-threadless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/14/zach-braff-makes-an-appearance-at-threadless/</guid>
      <description>The amazing Zach Braff has made an appearance over at threadless to show off the t-shirt which was designed to promote his new film, “The Last Kiss”. Apparently according to the audio interview he gave, he also was going to try to wear it on scrubs at some point, with a cheeky reference to the film. It’s also featuring as part of their current $10 sale in the run up to christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Web Users Want Web Standards?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/13/do-web-users-want-web-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/13/do-web-users-want-web-standards/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking about this earlier and was trying to make an educated answer. What I would note is that it is primarily content which drives users to use sites, we can see that through all manner of feeds and low bandwidth sites across the net. Without content, theres no point in sticking up a website. You can see demonstrations of that assertion here from time to time. It’s also fairly visible through all manner of seedy content on the web as users will be quite happy to sit through the many pop-ups and poorly formatted text to get to that bunch of images which they’re after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carson Systems shows us the money</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/07/carson-systems-shows-us-the-money/</guid>
      <description>Carson Systems is showing the details of how dropsend stacks up in terms of monthly profit. Ryan states that at a conservative estimate by December ’07, it’ll be making $21k/mo. He also seems to be beating off a bit of bad feedback on the advertising which has/hasn’t been done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DropSend is up for sale</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/dropsend-is-up-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>Carson Systems DropSend has recently been put up for sale by Ryan Carson. He states that currently they don’t have enough time to give it the attention it deserves, although the application is profitable with customers accumulating month by month.DropSend allows users to email huge files to one another via uploading them to dropsend and sending an email to the reciever to detail where it can be collected from. It’s quite interesting as the costs involved in its building are quite detailed within Ryans talk at a previous Future of Web Apps conference (also broken down here at 37 signals).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love useful error messages</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/i-love-useful-error-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/06/i-love-useful-error-messages/</guid>
      <description>I love it when I get useful error messages such as those often uttered by hotmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techno Graveyard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/03/techno-graveyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/11/03/techno-graveyard/</guid>
      <description>Our front room is looking a bit of a technology graveyard at the moment. Not only do we have the two archaic computers which have been there since forever, but now we also sport an unused fridge which has been replaced by one of our housemates parents (much larger) hand-me-downs.
This time last year saw the cleaning out of the Cardiff Department of Computer Science’s cupboards, with a large amount of the machines having to be “properly disposed of”, due to their burden of having huge crt monitors from yesteryear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/31/halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/31/halloween/</guid>
      <description>Does anyone else get the distinct impression that halloween is reserved for lamers? I mean, correct me if I’m wrong, it stems from a pagan festival celebrating a time at which spirits can make contact with the physical world. Is that something people really want to be celebrating?
I assume that the majority of the world goes along with the fact its just a bit of fun, a time at which kids get dressed up and collect sweets door-to-door, punishing those who don’t pay up with a bombing of baking compnents and parents play the niave fools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Tells Me Anything</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/29/nobody-tells-me-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/29/nobody-tells-me-anything/</guid>
      <description>Somebody should really remind me the evening before the clocks go back. I got up at 7.30 today and could have done with that extra hours lie-in. Oh well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 2.0 is Out!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/23/firefox-2.0-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/23/firefox-2.0-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Firefox 2.0 is out! Wikked wikked bwaaad bwoy!Get your ass over to mozilla.org while its still hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God is a DJ</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/17/god-is-a-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/17/god-is-a-dj/</guid>
      <description>This short vid is quite clever:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash bash</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</guid>
      <description>I was quite impressed with myself the other day that I’d actually managed to write a bash script within ubuntu which served a purpose. I wanted to be able to monitor the size of files within a particular directory, and report back their size when a change was observed.
I found a program called fileschanged, which fulfilled half the problem, namely reporting back a file had changed, but I needed a greater level of detail than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ow! My arse!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/13/ow-my-arse/</guid>
      <description>For the 3rd time I can remember ever I came off my bike this morning. I took a corner too sharply and ended up sliding across the road. So I am currently sitting here with gravel ridden hands and a really sore arse. I thought to go and check my arse when I finally arrived at uni and decided that it might be an idea to find something to stop the injury oozing all over my underwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flickr</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</guid>
      <description>After just 24 hours on flickr, someone has already added one of my pictures as one of their favourites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been following a number of so called “web 2.0″ companies in the uk recently via techcrunch.co.uk in order to explore what might be available to me when I need to start work this time next year. It’s quite interesting that actually, there is a number of companies cited around the Cardiff/Bristol/Bath areas that I’d never realised were in the UK.In Bath, there’s Carson Systems, which also host a number of web application workshops around the uk, with a Drop Send and Amigo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My final year of being a student?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</guid>
      <description>I thought I’d pose this as a question because I’m unsure if this is indeed my final year. It’s quite strange to think at the end of this thing I’m actually going to have to find some work somewhere another. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated from whomever. I’m looking for £50k/yr involving part time work from home, company car, but then I think the rest of the world is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone want to buy a car?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</guid>
      <description>I’m selling my car, which has been with me for the last 4/5 years and always been very reliable. It’s a very nice Vauxhall Corsa 1.5 TD in red, for more details, check freeads here and drop me an email either through freeads or this website if you’re interested.
I’m pretty sad to see the thing go, but as I now have no need for it due to the acquiring of my own personal chauffeur, it seems a bit uneconomical to hang on to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web is Just to Darn Big</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been suffering at the hands of the sheer size of the web recently. Just starting off at popurls yields many hours spent just browsing randomly across many, many web buzz sites. Although its all very interesting, its not particularly useful to my research, or in fact my own projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XGL, Compiz on Dapper 64 - Too much to ask?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64-too-much-to-ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64-too-much-to-ask/</guid>
      <description>I spent a large amount of time last week, after realising that I could very easy install compiz and XGL on my machine at uni, trying to install it upon my home machine. As its 64 bit, and owing to previous problems I’d experienced installing 64 bit applications (like linux for instance), I spent the best part of 2 days attempting to install both, before caving and completely giving up.I got to the stage where XGL is installed properly and seems to work ok, but the compiz gnome window manager isn’t working properly, meaning I have no borders to any panes I create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, we’ve not spoken in a while. How’s you?It seems I’ve been succumbing to a lifestyle of late that I wish I would never end up at – that of working within a “routine”. I must be getting old. The whole of last week seemed a little bit of a drain, working my ass off trying to get tiny parts of code to work properly in the day and the rest of the time being tired that I was staying up late to give myself alone time in the evenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Igniter</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been experimenting with code igniter tonight, a php mvc framework. I discovered it yesterday, not realising that such things were available for php. As its extremely lightweight and seems to speeding up things no-end already, I reckon I’ll probably be using it on some of my new slimshot projects I’m planning on working on soon. I just need to get another life somewhere so I can actually go about implementing all this stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slug&#39;s Talking Nicely</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a couple of problems getting my slug working nice under ubuntu. Firstly, although it is recognised by default and I can connect and browse via samba, when I actually came to playing my media, everything got screwed up, with Amarok trying to launch kmail…… I could copy files to ubuntu and play them properly from there, but straight off of the slug was a no go.I found the solution was to mount it under ubuntu using the command:sudo mount -t smbfs //NAS/DISK 1 /media/slug -o username=user,password=passWhere user and pass are your username and password for the slug respectively and the backslash indicates a space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to contribute</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been wanting to create a site which attracts lot of attention for ages. Not to create some profit-making venture, just to know that my voice was being listened too elsewhere and hopefully appreciated. I suppose that goes for my PhD too. It’s kind of depressing however that almost everything ever has been done, and every avenue seems blocked in both respects. How do you contribute to a world that is uninsterested in what you have to say?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Slugs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks back I discovered a slug in cash converters. Well, a usb2 external disk to nas drive converter affectionately known as the slug. Seeing as how I’ve been considering purchasing one, I figured shelling out the £25 was worth it for an experiment with installing linux on it for a bit. The D-Link nslu2 features two usb2 connection points for hooking up usb2 drives, but I didn’t really feel like sacrificing my university external box as this usually comes in quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Ubuntu? - ATI 9600 and SBLive</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu-ati-9600-and-sblive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu-ati-9600-and-sblive/</guid>
      <description>Another post about ubuntu? Where will it end?I was fairly excited from thursday evenings antics of getting things working on my machine at home, I thought I’d give it a try with my dev machine at uni. My graphics card, a 9600 (yes ATI, I know!) had been screwed since the day I’d put on Dapper, and to be honest, as I’m not using it that much for GL stuff, I wasn’t really bothered about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I speak too soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</guid>
      <description>It seems I may have spoken too soon about my linux joys with ubuntu. After performing a dist-upgrade on my previous beta version of Dapper, I discovered I’d have to go through the same problems of downloading kernel source and linux header packages for my new kernel version.I also discovered after doing this that actually there were further problems on booting Dapper straight up. Apparently the pointers to drives get screwed up somewhere in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thieves</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</guid>
      <description>You’d think that thieves would be content who’d bent my door back along to try and nick my car, realising actually I have nothing of value. Or that by monitoring my movements over a period of time, the opportune time to get into it would be when I went away to Dublin, Chicago or Singapore for weeks on end. Apparently not, in fact, they think its such a prime example of Vauxhalls lack of security that they would in fact like to come back and try to nick it by bending out the other door right when I’m here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Working</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</guid>
      <description>FInally, after a grand total of 10 months, I have a 64bit version of Ubuntu Linux working upon my home machine.This is great news, not only does it mean that I have a wonderful OS to try out for size, but that I can easily convert my subversion server code and latex source to my machine.As I’ve never mentioned it before, I’ll detail what the problem was here. First up, the graphics card didn’t have drivers which were working which meant that my X800 was pretty pathetic to be quite honest with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Irony</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I got a little annoyed about the fact that it seemed as if play had forgotten all details of my existence and telling me my email address was wrong. After sending a little letter off to them complaining yesterday evening, I realised after their response that actually I’d altered my saved email a little while before. I went ahead and placed my order of Sideways this morning which I’d expected to be fairly good due to the rave reviews I’d heard of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it take to make a good wife?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</guid>
      <description>From “How To Succeed With Women Without Really Trying” c1957
“The first wife, as opposed to the fiancee, must be practicable and serviceable. She is neither a toy, an ornament, nor a playmate. She will be your wife during the early, hard years before you can afford a staff of servants. She will serve as mother, cook, housemaid, chauffeur, nurse, and charwoman. This will allow her, if she is nimble, six or seven hours of sleep a night, ample for a sturdy girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mull</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</guid>
      <description>So my holiday in Mull more than surpassed the expectations I had for it. Beautiful scenery, solitude, our own private beach, lots of sheep and cows etc etc. In fact, you had to be fairly careful negotiating the roads of Mull for fear of taking out the 50 odd sheep that would block our journey to and from the house. That and the rocks (which we experienced through a blowout). We visited the smaller islands of Iona and Staffa, with both being beautiful but Staffa getting my vote (its full of puffins, rather than americans).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays Soon!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/17/holidays-soon/</guid>
      <description>Woohoo, rock on – its almost holiday season for me. Next week I’ll be off to Scotland to the Isle of Mull for a week and a bit of unadulterated relaxing. Ahh…Looking forward to it. Last years summer time in France was one of the best times I’ve had in donkeys and I hope and expect this to be too. So to those who’ll be there with me – you best make it a good’n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing domain names</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/choosing-domain-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/choosing-domain-names/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I’ve been spending many an hour pondering domain name choices for a fair trade t-shirt site I’d like to set-up, but never actually committing to one, due to the rather lacklustre responses of others on hearing my suggestions, or not finding anything suitable which conveys what I am trying to get across (a hip, trendy t-shirt place, ala threadless.com).If anyone can think of anything clever – let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My world has ended</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/my-world-has-ended/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/06/06/my-world-has-ended/</guid>
      <description>Interestingly, two of my most used sites hotmail and ebay, seem to be unavailable at the moment for me to peruse in my daily late night browsing routine. Maybe ntl is doing something stupid at the moment, in fact this is most likely the problem as large amounts of images around the web are unable to be displayed for one reason or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 7 - Sentosa Island (Hopefully!)</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/22/singapore-day-7-sentosa-island-hopefully/</guid>
      <description>So I managed to make it to the zoo yesterday, which was very exciting. More exciting though, was the night safari, where everything is minimally lit with the animals there to give a night time experience (I expect). I was a bit worried about catching buses and the like, but it was fine in the end, everything was really very well laid out, it was a doddle.
Today I’m off to visit the somewhat artificial Sentosa island – there seems to be a bit of controversy about the fact the land is all ‘reclaimed’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/19/singapore-day-3/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just returned from the conference dinner to finalise CCGRID for ’06. Tomorrow will be its last day whereupon everyone will return to their various different countries, or maybe somewhere closer for a short time on holiday. I’ve already heard of others plans to see Malaysia and Vietnam. I’ll be here until Tuesday evening to check out all that Singapore has to offer (at least I hope I will be able to).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/17/singapore-day-2/</guid>
      <description>So, I have arrived safe and sound in Singapore. I got in yesterday and have been doing various CCGrid related things since. Yesterday evening, after a quick shower I headed off to find the conference venue and something to eat. Unfortunately I spent the best part of my time wondering round trying to find the venue! It was rather annoying as a large majority of pedestrian routes had been obstructed due to a huge amount of road works going on around the university premises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to Singapore!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/15/off-to-singapore/</guid>
      <description>So despite having only been back in the UK for less than a week, I’m now off to Singapore, to present another paper of my work at CCGrid06. I’m slightly less nervewracked this time, but not looking forward to the ridiculous flight time (best part of 13 hours) and the time difference when I arrive (+ 7 hours). Viv tells me its a beautiful and amazingly techie place, so it sounds not at all distant from my own bedroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Five - Threadless and Whitesox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-five-threadless-and-whitesox/</guid>
      <description>After the workshop ended in the early hours of the afternoon today, I thought it would be kinda cool to head over and see if I could find threadless in Chicago, to stock up on some more of their awesome t shirts. After a little bit of thinking and umming and ahh-ing about whether or not I could actually find the place, I decided to make a a go of it and try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Six - Last Day in Hard Rock</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/06/chicago-day-six-last-day-in-hard-rock/</guid>
      <description>So today marks the last day I’m put up in the Hard Rock, and my last full day here in the states. I awoke to a bill that had been slipped under my door to announce that I’d been charged for their “intimacy kit”, because I had moved it to have a look at it, and this constitutes a charge. I found this most amusing. I think I’ll make sure that there are no more automated charges made before I leave, seeing as how I’ve actually used nothing….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Four - Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/05/chicago-day-four-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Hello. Today marked the second day in the workshop I’m attending and the presentation of some of my own work and thoughts. I’ve also experienced some very useful thoughts of not only my work, but my PhD as a whole. Today is a good day for that.
Yesterday evening we attended an italian restaurant as part of the evening meals for the conference, which featured such a ridulous amount of food it was stupid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Three - Workshop Start</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/04/chicago-day-three-workshop-start/</guid>
      <description>So today marked the checking in and out of hotels to move down the road in preparation for my workshop I’m attending while I’m here. Here’s some views of my hotel room looking out onto Sears, complete with the only person whom is here with me. I have to head out now, for the conference dinner etc. I shall be sure to post later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day Two - Sears Tower, Hancock Observatory</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/03/chicago-day-two-sears-tower-hancock-observatory/</guid>
      <description>Today, after yesterdays success, and it being fairly sunny, I decided to try and find Sears Tower (The USA’s tallest building) and come home fresh in the knowledge I had ascended it. People were all trying to put me off going as the views from Sears weren’t as good as those from the Hancock observatory, which sits on the Magnificent Mile and gives nice views of the shore of Lake Michigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Day One</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/chicago-day-one/</guid>
      <description>I have an uncanny habit of organising travel on unique dates. Last year my journey to Edinburgh for a conference was held up because it was the day before the G8 summit, when Viv and I went to Dublin, I completely forgot about the fact St Patricks day would fall around that time. My journey to Chicago it would seem is not to be blessed without this feature either. I’ll let you in on what happened in a sec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling to Chicago</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/05/02/travelling-to-chicago/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve arrived safe and sound in Chicago! I’m quite glad about that as it means I’m not dead, murdered or anything like that from what came from my whole journey…
I didn’t realise how much of a strain etc travelling could be, mainly because I’ve never come this far before (actually, I’ve never been outside of Europe). I had to set off at around 8.00am from home, catching a train to get to Gatwick for 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Go!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/05/all-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/05/all-go/</guid>
      <description>Its been a long time without me saying anything much, but lots and lots going on. The first event to note was that I had my car attempted to be broken into over here in Roath, I suppose that eventually that this was bound to happen being in a city centre and all I guess until now I’ve been lucky. They tried to get in through the passenger side door, bending it out and giving up after not getting in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ebay Experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/04/the-ebay-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/04/04/the-ebay-experiment/</guid>
      <description>I’m always coming up with concepts for websites, but I thought this one was worth blogging about. Basically, my idea is that you give yourself a budget of say 99p on ebay and see what kind of profit you can get from that by selling it again….on ebay… and so on until you flop and lose all your profit, or give up and bag the benefits of being able to spell and take photographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>worpdress</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/17/worpdress/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I noticed that worpdress.com, org and net weren’t registered, despite their similarity to the excellent blogging tool wordpress’s domain. I thought it was too good an opportunity to be missed, and registered the lot of them.After a couple of posts on the wordpress forums, and the realisation that there was no way in hell I’d ever have the time to put anything there, I decided to donate them to Matt Mullenweg, so at least they were redirecting the one or two people who might hit them to the correct wordpress site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nth Fest</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/08/nth-fest/</guid>
      <description>Although I didn’t attend it, it sounds like this event held at my church at home in Somerset was an absolute blast – props to crackers for sorting it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digg It</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/06/digg-it/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently, through many searches to do with AJAX, Web 2.0 and the like been perusing digg.com, that fairly new web site for geeks.Basically, it’s a social booking marking site where users “digg” those sites which they find interesting, as more users digg the same pages, they get promoted up through to the main page, or higher up through the rankings within particular categories. Its a really interesting concept, quite similar to del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Pancakes!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/03/02/flipping-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Flipping pancakes eh? They’re crafty beggars they are..
Would you believe that in my 24 years knocking around, I’d never actually flipped a pancake until this tuesday? You could understand why I might be a little excited about that particular prospect, and a little nervous. I spent my evening with a bunch of girls, in all shapes and sizes (some tall, some short, some insanely strong) to celebrate this occasion, but when my time to shine came, it was all good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSI RS480M2-IL Motherboard</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/msi-rs480m2-il-motherboard/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who would like to have a stable SFF machine, lest ye take heed of my advice…do not buy MSI.I bought a mATX MSI RS480M2-IL back in october, with a view to putting it in my new Antec Aria SFF case. It looked deceptively feature packed with its 939 madness and 3 x PCI and PCI-E slots. There it still currently resides sitting quietly all day until I return from work in the evening to perhaps do a little web design or listen to the 70 odd gigs of music I have stashed away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geeks gone out</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/09/the-geeks-gone-out/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started a new blog over at webtyrant.com for all of you who visit my site and need a fix of techie-type jazz. I figured most of you didn’t, hence my placement on a different domain. You might notice a similar theme over there, so that’ll make you feel right at home even if the content doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just been informed that my paper for CCGRID06 has been accepted, which I’m very pleased about. It’s my first paper acceptance in my 14 months of being based as a PhD at Cardiff University so really its about time I got some ideas out in the open to people. It’s also based in Singapore, and I’ve never left Europe – yeah it’s two days, but I’m chuffed nonetheless.
The ironic thing is I was a bit annoyed last year at the fact CCGRID05 was in Cardiff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/whats-the-difference-between/</guid>
      <description>Romantic rose petals and normal ones?
Probably about £6 I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</guid>
      <description>My day was brightened lots yesterday when my my PhD supervisor informed me he had a blog on the subject of grid computing. It was intended for members of our research group to contribute to and discuss things. The most amusing part was, being cutting edge and all, you’d expect it to be a bustling hive of activity. What I actually found was a site with two posts covering the last 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/it-begins/</guid>
      <description>and so it begins….a new website, a new era of web geeking to the max, free from the shackles of mere mortal mens minds.A place to be geeks are creative, explore and communicate…Ladies and Gentlemen, I give you, The Web Tyrant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are 100</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</guid>
      <description>This post is the official 100th post on this site! Wow, how exciting. I know that it’s marked up as #127, but these are of the ones that actually made it public here. The first one made it up back in August 03 and was rather boring. That makes an average blog per month rating of 3.4….Yeah, thats lame too. So, what can I talk about to make it all profound now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live in the Moment</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</guid>
      <description>For Christmas, one of my gifts was an ace calendar providing helpful hints on worst case scenarios for each day of 2006. Todays one made me smile quite a lot – “How to survive psychological torture”. The second part of it however sounds more applicable to everyday life, work, relationships etc rather than actual torture (except for the horrors part).
Here’s the advice:
Do not worry about what comes next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Goes On</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</guid>
      <description>On the dawning of a new year, life continues much the same as it has done previously, I have lots of work to do, lots of pointless things to do and lots of people who want me to fix their computers because they heard I know a little about those sorts of things. On my quest to rid the world of all t-shirts by stocking up on them myself, I’d quite like to pick up this t-shirt to reflect how I sometimes feel about this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</guid>
      <description>I’ve not spoken in a long time on here and it seems I’m getting harassed into doing so, so I thought I’d air some stuff.
It’s the New Year! Woohoo! Christmas brought with it all the usual stuff, like parents moaning about computers and arguing about nothing. This year I only crept back for a very short time in which to see family and catch up. It seems like Yeovil is less and less like my home now, with friends moving away and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out with the Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/16/out-with-the-old/</guid>
      <description>If anyone is interested in puchasing my old computer, I’m getting rid of it.
It features:
 Athlon 2500XP Barton CPU 512Mb 3200 DDR Memory 80Gb 7200RPM Hard Disk Sound Blaster Live Drive 5.1 with Remote Control Sony DVD-ROM LG 52x24x52 CDRW Tyan Tachyon 128Mb G9600Pro (Ati Radeon – fully boxed) 350W Levicom Blue Lit Dual Fan Power Supply (fully boxed) Antec Plusview Case (with side panel)  (fully boxed) 17″ Hansol 710D CRT Flat Monitor Logitech Keyboard/Mouse  Boxes/driver disks included, but supplied without any operating system (unless you want Ubuntu!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouragement</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/05/encouragement/</guid>
      <description>I cleaned out one of the boxes of papers kicking around my room the other evening. In it, I found an old lunch pass from school (featuring a photo sporting a lovely little version of me) and lots of old encouragement sheets we used to pass around our youth group to gets lots of positive comments on ourselves. Most of these are at least 5 years old and some stretch back to 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Long</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/12/04/so-long/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday morning, Maggie, our eldest labrador at home was taken to the vet to be put down. She’d been poorly for sometime and had become unable to walk, for any reason whatsoever. Maggie was a member of our family for the past 13 years, so it’s understandably a bit of a loss to us all. It’s strange to think back to when we first got her, making apologies to numerous teachers for the state the new books I’d been given had gotten into so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It’s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I’d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she’d brave the border as well to make those “all important” first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oblivious</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</guid>
      <description>I think I’m a little less than perceptive of situations in which I’m involved. Recently, I’ve been clued in to a number of things which makes me think I’ve been carrying freeriding on this life while I could of been part of something so much more interesting. This isn’t a direct attack on anyone but myself, so don’t anyone take it to heart. I think this is best shown through the forming of a type of relationship I’ve been starved of for the best part of my life, one with my lovely new girlfriend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alarm Bells</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</guid>
      <description>Some of the thoughts in this post over at Barbara’s really hit home with me today. I don’t often take time to reflect on pointers like these but the majority of them are ringing alarm bells about some aspect of my life at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>From a sample upon the dischandler (DJ Moneyshot):
“No one wants to be a failure, no one wants a life constantly filled with worry, fear and frustration. Therefore you must remember to reap that which you sow. If you sow negative thoughts, your life will be filled with negative things. If you sow positive thoughts, your life will be cheerful, successful and positive.”
Not so sure how this pads out in real life…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMuppets</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</guid>
      <description>So, I’ve had not a lot of response to my situation with ebuyer of late, but this recent email I recieved from them sent me over the edge – I’d sent them 7 emails and phoned 2 times with a 40 min wait prior to recieving this.
———————————————————————————————————-
Microsoft OEM Windows XP Professional x64 Edition – 1Pk
Dear Sir / Madam,
Thank you for informing us of your missing item. When we are believed to have short shipped an</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing the Effects of Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/30/describing-the-effects-of-music/</guid>
      <description>I went round to Living Stones last night for a bit of a lads night with Jon, Dan, Rob and Joe for music and watching Batman Begins. I took a number of Cd’s for Dan and I to listen to, which basically reflected the “base” around which the majority of all my other music stems from. It’s quite odd trying to verbalise how a particular song makes you feel, why you feel uplifted by it, how it captures a particular moment in time, thought, etc etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daft Punk</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/24/daft-punk/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been attending a fair few ‘live’ gigs recently as oppose to the frequenting of clubs in Cardiff. The first was the fantastic Röyksopp, whom I was dubious to see alone, but glad I did. Quite frankly they were as great live as I could possibly hope for and the addition of the huge inflatable tape and scrolling info about each song added to the experience.
More recently, I got to see “Bowling for Soup” at union on Friday, which allowed me to experience the ‘delights’ of teen punk as well as some awful “post-punk laptop (c)rap” from Mc Lars who seemed confused as to where exactly Cardiff featured in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What colour are you?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/08/what-colour-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/08/what-colour-are-you/</guid>
      <description>I found a wicked animation by Maria Claudia Cortes describing what personalities a bunch of colours are often attributed with. I reckon I’m a mixture of red and blue, my wardrobe reflects this as well. What colour are you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fools</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/06/fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/06/fools/</guid>
      <description>Whats the most annoying thing ebuyer could leave out of my order for my building a new PC? That’s it – the OS, so I can build my lovely little machine, but not actually use the thing until they get their act together. Nice one guys, you suck ass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD Greedy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/10/04/cd-greedy/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always bought lots of music. Those of you who’ve had the privilege of viewing my collection will have seen it spans all manner of media, Tape, CD, MD, Vinyl. I’ve recently been doing a lot of random browsing on ebay for CD’s that have previously escaped me and possibly buying a few other items from the same seller to save on postage. My biggest one though has to be my most recent, 12 albums from the same seller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragile</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/26/fragile/</guid>
      <description>I’m feeling rather fragile at the moment, which is really annoying because the majority of the time I’m the picture of health. It started yesterday, but I thought I’d got over it only for headaches and tummy aches to return by the evening. Unfortunately, it meant I wasn’t best of hosts to Hannah who stayed over on Sunday because of a stereophonics gig she was going to. I had to fix her up with Jon to go with as her mate decided to back out on her pretty late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/job-requirements/</guid>
      <description>That last post aside heres a mildly amusing anecdote that happened to me whilst in B�Q a couple of weeks ago featuring a sweet old welsh lady.
Old Lady (Looking at lampshades): “Is that the ACTUAL price of these!?”
Me (Bewildered, wondering past end of aisle): “Well, yeah, it says so on the label”
Old Lady: “£11.99! I saw ‘em for £1 on Newport Road!”
Me (Still bewildered, now in aisle): “Oh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who hid the bloomin&#39; remote?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/18/who-hid-the-bloomin-remote/</guid>
      <description>I was contemplating all the stuff I generally tend to blog about. Most of the time, something rather huge has to happen for me in my week to be bothered to blog about it and then a large majority of that goes unnoticed by you, my readers (both of you), due to concerns about upsetting people, getting upset by people or not reflecting myself in the best of light. Other stuff, I just don’t think is interesting at all, but I’ve been told that while I think it mundane, it proves amusing to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/13/a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may have noticed that I’ve moved. Whats that? You didn’t? Oh well, cheers then, how much of a friend are you? I never read your blog either. For those who didn’t – take a look in the address bar, I’m now at www.ianwootten.co.uk (Highly original I know!).
This week I have been mostly stressing about work, sitting at home alone, watching repeats, finding interesting links through the wonder of del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not quite the iflea, but...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/09/09/its-not-quite-the-iflea-but.../</guid>
      <description>So Apple announces this week that they release their new version of iTunes, the ROKR E1 – a mobile phone featuring iTunes and finally, the iPod nano – a super-small, thinner version of the iPod to replace the iPod mini. Another iPod – how many have there been now? There’s still no move on a larger capacity front, so nowhere to house my 7000 high quality mp3′s just yet – except my portable fat hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Interludes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/31/musical-interludes/</guid>
      <description>These last couple of weeks have been fairly exciting from a musical point of view. I dj’ed for both Sarah Lou and Zoe’s birthday parties, which were both fantabulous, getting to hang with new and making even newer friends. My mixing on each was somewhat dodgy, but to be honest I’m a bit out of practice.
Tim had been preparing for his CD launch for his band “Walking Wounded” all week last week, and their performance upon Thursday at Journeys showed off all their hard work (although unfortunately, I don’t think the same can be said of the random geezer who decided to perform last minute inbetween them and the support).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bizarre Dreams</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/25/bizarre-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/25/bizarre-dreams/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been having some really random dreams this week, the strangest part being I can actually remember them. Here’s a few examples:
Sunday – I had one of those ones where, you’re aware you’re asleep and can control whats going on, but was face down on my bed and completely overcome by something and unable to move any part of my body. When I woke up, with a bit of a start, I’d only been out for a half hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trials Unicycling</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/19/trials-unicycling/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired yesterday by watching a few vids on the internet of crazy kids doing trials unicycling, so decided to go out for a ride in the evening round Roath Park. It’s been a long time since I’ve ridden, but it seems you don’t forget. Nor do the ‘oh I’m original’ taunts cease, such as “oi, mate, you’ve lost a wheel!”, “pull a wheelie!” etc etc. Anyway, it was nice to finally ride mine without fear of the horrid scratching which I usually obtain from my previous saddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Somerset</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/17/sunny-somerset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/17/sunny-somerset/</guid>
      <description>I went back home this weekend for Tim and Becca’s wedding. Although the weather didn’t hold out – it was raining all day, the guys made the most of it and the service was fab. Music was provided by Mr Maynard and a string quartet. By far the most amusing thing was the pastor’s inability to use a radio mike without whispering the whole service. So amusing sentences like “Don’t fall down the steps….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Mercies</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/11/small-mercies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/11/small-mercies/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch Charlie and the Chocolate factory last night – which I thought was great, compared to the original preconceptions I had of it from trailers, reviews and the like. Anyways, I was sat there at the end as all the children were walking out of the factory thinking, “Well, at least I’m not as thin as Mike TV”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwanted Affection?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/10/unwanted-affection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/10/unwanted-affection/</guid>
      <description>So, after renewing my insurance policy today, I get handed the piece of paper with my policy number and the words “Ashley, love”. I’m unsure whether the guy wrote this in awe of myself or indeed it had been written previously on the pad in use. Either way, the words in that order don’t make any sense. Dyslexia perhaps? There’s been a bit of talk and reading recently involving dating with integrity, not settling with second best and the like, but this ranks a few rungs below that upon my ladder unfortunately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal Images</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/03/ideal-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/03/ideal-images/</guid>
      <description>On a lighter note, I went to a ‘focus group’ last night which was fairly surreal. I’d been asked last week to attend, and had agreed not actually knowing the subject matter. On sunday I was informed that it was going to be on ‘mens cosmetics’ (something I’m obviously very familiar with!) so didn’t really know what to expect. After arriving, discovering two of my old coursemates were there (and on the same course as Garima), we sat down for like 45 minutes talking about our opinions about luxuries, cosmetics and as many tangents we could stray off on as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Wrongs don&#39;t Make it Right</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/08/01/millions-of-wrongs-dont-make-it-right/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had quite a lot of talks recently with people about the subject of piracy, be it music, films, software, whatever. You might think that being a Computer Scientist and DJ, that I’d be quite blase attitude toward it, but it’s quite the opposite really.
My take on it, is, whichever way you come at it, it’s theft. That might sound quite harsh, but I might as well to cut to the chase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a difference a year makes....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</guid>
      <description>So, in the absence of students, life continues as normal for the various research teams down here in the Queens buildings. We wake, march to University and sit in our little boxes reading, theorising and tearing our hair out until 5 o’clock when we march back, only to be repeated the next day. I hate routines…
Today marked the graduation of Year 3′s which brought back memories of my graduation last year, which was pretty depressing to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weddings, Unicycles and Money</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/07/weddings-unicycles-and-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/07/weddings-unicycles-and-money/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a good week thus far. Saturday marked a return to Somerset to attend Steve and Hannah’s wedding, which I was a little late for due to having to pick up a number of interesting things I’ve been given by Gran. I felt a little harsh having to dash in, collect and leave, it felt a little like Dad and I were looting the place.
Being late was ok as one of the speakers was following in just after me (apparently a bit of a search was going on for him prior to the service), confirming we were good to creep through the large arched doors as the sound of singing could be heard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Mental</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</guid>
      <description>Today I travelled on 2 planes, 3 buses and 1 car (thats a full house and extra) to make the 800 mile round trip to Edinburgh for part of a BioDiveristyWorld conference. I’m quite surprised I managed to organise and sort out everything since Monday and it go according to plan.
I was actually really overwhelmed at how amazing the place was for the brief time I was there, the sheer scale of the city was something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writers Block</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/28/writers-block/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to write a classic quote I found in ‘Boy’ while I was away so I thought I’d shove it up now. I think it encompasses how I feel about work at the moment. Really enjoyed just lazing about reading in France for ages, finished Pi, although I found it to drag on somewhat, the quirky bit at the end made it fairly clever. Onto some Pratchett now after resisiting for ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normality Check</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/26/normality-check/</guid>
      <description>Our last day in Jard was rather less exciting than we’d hoped, we decided to clean the place* we were staying in, so spent the morning doing that and unfortunately the weather was cack so didn’t make for much of an afternoon either. We apparently caught the back end of a heatwave this week which has been rather fortunate, although pretty uncomfortable in the evenings. (Tim had it worse being in the same room as Mr ‘Exorcist’ Pete, I had to endure that in Germany so it’s his turn this time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastis and Miniatures - 22/06/2005 - 23/06/2005</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures-22/06/2005-23/06/2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/23/pastis-and-miniatures-22/06/2005-23/06/2005/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday not a lot happened, except for much reading and bumming around the house whilst trying out my newly found juggling skills. We also went on our search for pastis, after discovering that it actually tasted much the same as oizo, a wicked aniseed flavour…I think Rach may need to be educated in its use however, due to filling a wine glass neat with the stuff, which I would of been dead if I’d actually consumed undiluted, or at least extremely quiet for the rest of the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/21/beer-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Decided to make a move on to our next beach today, taking with us a picnic and a load of beer. This one is situated right next to a forest, which was ace for our picnic.
Tim, after 3 years of living with one another has finally managed to teach me to juggle and give me the bug for continuing it. It’s actually easier to learn using boule, forcing you to use correct arm movements, though its a little dangerous on the beach if you have a distinct lack of footwear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Marshes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/20/wine-and-marshes/</guid>
      <description>Today we went over to the salt marshes in Olonne, it being slightly more manageable weather and all. Tim basically wanted to do a little birdwatching and Heledd and Dave didn’t fancy such french beauty so went to have coffee in a suitable village somewhere. It was really cool, took lots of photos of the strange green murky waters and had a bunch of exercise too. Saw loads of eels while we were there – horrible things writhing about….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine and Beaches</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/19/wine-and-beaches/</guid>
      <description>Sunday’s morning events weren’t overly exciting – the weather has been so hot that it would be a bit much to go off and try to do anything. Instead has been a morning of reading (Dahl’s ‘Boy’ – bizzarrely featuring Cardiff, La Rochelle and Somerset within) and people trying to juggle. The afternoon became overcast so we decided to make the trip down to the beach, where Tim, Rach and Pete all got rather dirty trying to recreate a eurotunnel experience, which was destroyed as soon as it was completed by Dave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Journeys - 17/06/05 - 18/06/05</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys-17/06/05-18/06/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/18/long-journeys-17/06/05-18/06/05/</guid>
      <description>So, it begins, the holiday season that is and with it my two day trip across England and back down the west coast of France to Jard Su Mer. Todays trip was fairly long, spending two hours bombing down the M4 to meet with the guys in Reading, then a further few to reach the underside of London on the M25, and a bit more to finally bundle over toward the Eurotunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another One Bites the Dust</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/13/another-one-bites-the-dust/</guid>
      <description>You’d be forgiven for thinking that the title might refer to Pop’s funeral this week, but no, I mean the fact that finally after 7 years in courtship Mike and Jo have become hitched. Thats strike 5 from the core Yeovil lad’s posse…
It was a fab day, with schoolfriends from yesteryear I haven’t kept up to date with, and family members I never knew existed. My sister always seems to find it amusing that Jo’s sis, Sarah got hitched before them being a couple of years younger, having her been to school with Sarah and Jo in my form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUMO!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/05/sumo/</guid>
      <description>No, not the monthly breaks event in Clwb Ifor, though you’d be forgiven for thinking that’s what this post would be about due to regular raving about it, no, *actual *Sumo.
So I started my trip off at 9:45am – realising that actually that Tesco’s would be shut if I left earlier and I’d not get fuel.. After faffing getting burgers and the like, I set off about 10:20am to Bournemouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackalicious - Make You Feel That Way</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious-make-you-feel-that-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/blackalicious-make-you-feel-that-way/</guid>
      <description>“Ya know its like ahh like the most greatest feeling you could ever feel, you know, like, just total elation. Sunny day, just got paid….
You know its just like, you know, just the most joyous feeling you could ever comprehend. You know, chilling with your family.
You know just you know just really really feeling, feeling the moment, with the folks. Ya know really really really just chilling.
It’s love…”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Places</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/happy-places/</guid>
      <description>To cheer me up a bit I’ve been trying to go to my happy place (which doesn’t involve dwarfs on tricycles before you ask), merely great places nearby which hold fantastic memories for me – ‘Ham Hill’ and “West Bay” being two notable ones. Ham Hill has all those fantastic bike rides, barbeques, moonlit evenings, Christmas moments and stupid uni friends wondering where we got all the pigs from. West Bay holds a bunch more cycle rides, youth camps (with lots of sheep, golf courses and jogs), barbeques, baptisms (including my own), boating moments and horrible toilets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Rank</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/03/how-rank/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I found most amusing yesterday, which made me laugh lots is that my website is currently ranked #5 in msn for “childrens farting jokes”, Microsoft are obviously doing their jobs well once again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highs and Lows, Peaks and Troughs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/02/highs-and-lows-peaks-and-troughs/</guid>
      <description>It was great to have the bank holiday this monday once again, allowed me to recover from the mad weekend that I had. The Vineyardites met at Living Stones for a great packed lunch (which had been moved from the park due to Cardiff’s dodgy weather), followed by new take on a game of miniature bowls on the snooker table by Jon and Rob. After this I moved on to Roath Park with Lewis and one of his mates from home before meeting up with Vineyardites once again and chucking bread at feathered creatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same Old, Same Old</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/30/same-old-same-old/</guid>
      <description>So, its been a fair while, I’ve been getting jip off of people about not writing, but to be honest, there’s not exactly been a lot happening in my neck of the woods which is all that exciting. I’ve pooled everything I can remember from the last two weeks and bunged them into one post…
Sat 14th – Featured a grandma squashing her child by clipping her foot on a paving slab on albany junction and falling straight onto him whilst carrying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put on a brave face</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/13/put-on-a-brave-face/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been feeling a bit off today – maybe its the fact I had to cook dinner amidst housemates washing up at like 8:30pm yesterday, I had my wall banged on by neighbours last night due to noisy Tim (he has a gig soon so can be forgiven), or couldn’t get to sleep last night again for the same reason, radiators blaring and a noisy neighbour party or maybe its because I had to wait around forever at home today to collect a parcel from the Royal Snail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academia</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/11/academia/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had the fairly bizarre experience this week of attending the CCGrid 05 conference at city hall. This is my first conference and by all means a first introduction to my peers outside of the group involved with the PASOA project I am working upon. I think the most interesting thing is how normal each of them actually are – I was expecting them all to have some sort of superiority complex for some reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Week</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/05/07/matthias-week/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a really great week this week, mainly due to spending a large majority of it with the wonderful Matthias’s and crew. I’m not sure if this was altogether intentional, but it was great however it happened. I enjoy the crazy banter, furious sarcasm and witty jokes which are often made at others expense….
Monday we spent the day at Jon and Cathy’s eating and playing board games due to the unfortunate weather that occurred outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a palava</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</guid>
      <description>I went off to meet up with my Sis and Viv in Swansea on Thursday night, the drive out there and around the bay was fantastic, beautiful scenery in wonderful weather that I don’t often get to see around Cardiff. I think the comparison was made between the bay and Roath Park by Viv, but to be honest, there isn’t much of one. After a full on carvery meal and everyone feeling like veritable fat jabba’s, we drove over to the mumbles to munch on ice-cream (follow the logic there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitch Hikers Guide to the Skittle Alley</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</guid>
      <description>Every time I visit UGC Cardiff it brings back terrible memories of when I went to see ‘Matrix Revolutions’ last year. A bit psyched by the fact that it may of be able to redeem the tragedy which was ‘Matrix Reloaded’, I went to see it with some of the Glamorgan crew on its day of release. All was going as well as could be expected, until when 3/4 way through we were treated to a bit of a fight sequence and aerial acrobatics, which didn’t really seem to fit with what we had been watching, but could of been some sort of trendy ‘dream sequence’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things you might not know about CV&#39;ers..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</guid>
      <description>Here’s some interesting information I found about fellow Cardiff Vineyard’ers*.
 Jon Mathais was the producer of the New Romantics and was cut from the Sony Open in Hawaii on the 2005 PGA Tour. Jonathan Morgan holds both a successful ‘modeling’ career and since 1999 has also been a Conservative Assembly Member. Zoe Morgan once featured in a Dr Who Episode (Season 25, Episode 152 -’ Remembrance of the Daleks’) as ‘Girl’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far have I come?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</guid>
      <description>Having free time in the evenings recently is a wonderful thing, and its given me the chance to think about ‘stuff’ I might not of done otherwise, recently its been my undergrad life. When I came to University, I was all fired up for an amazing walk through Christendom, I tried to throw myself into the Christian Union, and for a while it was great. Unfortunately my work got a grip of me very quickly, and for all the wrong reasons I backed off from CU and any kind of fellowship with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Busy Busy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been running around a bit like a headless chicken recently, not content with spending lots of time at uni working, I’ve been partying pretty hard as well.
Spent Friday going to Kez’s 21st birthday for a meal at Old Orleans, which was rather tasty. Bombed back to hang out with Vineyardites at Marty’z Kitchen, which we were duely moved on from to Cafe aroma, and back to mine (after a few choice insults were uttered by me) for a nice cuppa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebay Bargains</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</guid>
      <description>If I had something interesting to say I would say it, but I don’t really so instead I’ll hit you with a few ebay bargains I’ve picked up of late. Currently I’m holding a rating of 166 positive, I reckon thats pretty good. Anybody else bought anything interesting off the net lately?
 Cut N Paste – Forget It [12&amp;quot; Single] (£1.99). I’ve been after this ever since I heard it on a Fatboy Slim ‘On the Floor at the Boutique’ mix CD donkeys years ago….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signs</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</guid>
      <description>There’s loads of places on the net where you can view silly or stupid signs. Most of the ones I’ve seen aren’t from the UK though, and I can’t imagine them any kind of scenario, which I think would make them all the more funny. This place has loads, so many I can’t afford to look through all of them. I can’t believe I’ve missed it before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/28/birthday/</guid>
      <description>Well, thats another year over and done with, on to the next. Unfortunately, due to the distinct lack of friends available at Cardiff or at home, it kinda all just happened, and is almost over. I went out for an romantic italian with Tim and Mark on Friday, featuring a couple of very grumpy waitresses. I had hopes to move on later on to bsb with people, but Tim was knackered from returning from a week of training and Mark wanted to save his efforts for the Easter Service on Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Blues</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/14/birthday-blues/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to decide what to do for my birthday which falls on Bank holiday monday this year. Currently I’m of the mind to do something on Good Friday like have a meal, then off to town (Chico Fresco and Phantom Beats will be at bsb apparently)….Leaving me free to go back and have easter and my actual birthday with family and friends. I’m going to be 24…24,24?!, no surely thats not right!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Jelly</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/10/lemon-jelly/</guid>
      <description>I was a right little Heathen yesterday and skived off of housegroup to meet up with Mr Bryer in Bristol to see the awesome Lemon Jelly. Whats even better was the fact that Ben Lilford had come along too, unbeknown to me before arriving. They are quite literally the most amusing band ever. Prior to the Jel’s entrance we were treated to Don Partridge (a one man band) whilst trying to play a couple of party games (find 3 stooges hidden in the audience).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oops</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/03/01/oops/</guid>
      <description>Ok, not to totally contradict my last post, I’ve just read a comedy web page all about me that was put up 5 years ago which I never knew existed! You might like to take a look here. It seems my music tastes haven’t changed all that much, as the songs I quote are all still top tunes…I may of gotten all technical for no reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Music</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/27/emotional-music/</guid>
      <description>I’m finding quite a lot at the moment that my music stirs up far more emotion in me than ever before. I don’t overly listen to sad songs, but I tend to find myself welling up at the most random of tracks. Quantic, Amon Tobin anyone? Pretty much most of these are without lyrics either, so I guess it really is “all about the music”. Tim’s once told me that there is no reason for us to really gain pleasure in listening to music, its just a bunch of random soundwaves, how can we possibly gain pleasure through that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Packed Weekends</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/21/fun-packed-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/21/fun-packed-weekends/</guid>
      <description>My weekends are getting more and more full of stuff being a PhD student. It’s nice being able to confine my work to a 9-5 regime (or thereabouts) and do whatever I want outside of that, plus unlike being an undergrad, I get some money.
This weeks been pretty packed, after the fan dabby dosy weekend at Port Eynon with Cardiff Vineyard last week, I stopped by my sis’s in Swansea for a bit to say hi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrumpy Jack gig</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/02/09/scrumpy-jack-gig/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got my first ‘proper’ gig in Cardiff next week, supporting the mighty ‘Eberg’ at Clwb Ifor Bach. If you’re interested, come along, it’d be good to see you…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tsunami Relief Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/24/tsunami-relief-cardiff/</guid>
      <description>I went to the Tsunami Relief concert held here in Cardiff on Saturday. I have to say, it was absolutely fantastic…! Made all the more special by the fact it was my first time in the stadium. Completely crazy to think I was in there for a good 7 hours or the hours I’d work in a day. I think probably best acts include Keane, Feeder (becuase I knew the words!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Photo&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/20/old-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/20/old-photos/</guid>
      <description>I’ve uploaded some old photo’s of me performing at an old Infusion gig back in 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas over, back to work</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/07/christmas-over-back-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/01/07/christmas-over-back-to-work/</guid>
      <description>So, the holiday season is all over and now I suffer the mundane reality that is my own life…boo hoo. Christmas was a little pants to be honest, as my Mum was in hospital the whole time I was at home, although it did make the place a lot quieter! Christmas Day was quite special as well, the fact that it snowed and all. It just so happened that this was when St John’s Church doors were opened after the morning service too, so everyone there was quite exciteable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vineyard reclaiming the web</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/14/vineyard-reclaiming-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Cardiff Vineyard have got to be the biggest bunch of bloggers I’ve ever met, in a non-derogitory sense. Makes a change to Yeovil Community Church. Browsing around their main site and links from it, I’ve found, hmm, lets see:
Cardiff Vineyard
Jon Matthias
Helen Carslaw
Lewis Parfitt
Neil Morgan
Zoë Morgan
Sarah-Louise
Thats crazy….! – We’ve got say 25 ppl max when I’ve gone along, so thats over a 5th turned blogging converts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple PHP Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/13/simple-php-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/13/simple-php-gallery/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got rid of the old phpautogallery that I had and dumped simple php gallery up instead. I’ve also converted shedloads of photos over so that peeps can see what I’ve been up to recently and not so recently. This includes most of the weddings I’ve attended over the last few years of very close friends, plus a few random ones for good measure.
Check them all out here http://users.cs.cf.ac.uk/I.M.Wootten/gallery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas feelings</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/09/christmas-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/12/09/christmas-feelings/</guid>
      <description>Can it be December already? What have I been doing? Wheres the last 3 months gone? I have to say I feel more Christmas-sy this year in Cardiff than I have ever been up here.
There seems to have been a bit of a build up so far.. Watching “Bad Santa” back in Nov (quite possibly the most amount of swearing I’ve ever seen in a film), going to Germany the other week with all the festive fun over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boo hoo....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/11/08/boo-hoo..../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/11/08/boo-hoo..../</guid>
      <description>Thought I’d have a moan about a few bits and bobs…same old, same old
I had a bit of an interesting experience today when my speedo decided to die halfway to Rhwibina. Could have been worse I guess, could of been on the motorway. Anyway, best get that sorted.
Uni seems to be going ok, the works piling up a bit though. It’s a bit of a nightmare to think about teaching and researching within the same day, takes me ages to adjust and concentrate for that matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weddings Galore</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/10/11/weddings-galore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/10/11/weddings-galore/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been to so many of my close mates wedding over the last couple of years… In fact I don’t actually think any of the old school crew are still single! Anyway in celebration of this, and Pauls recent marriage to Lisa, I’ve shoved up a gallery to show off some of the pics I have for them.
The gallery is located here, and for the blog here’s Paul in his new found role:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/16/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/16/update/</guid>
      <description>Seeing as how I haven’t posted anything here properly for far too long, I thought I’d give an update on everything I’ve been doing since we last spoke..
Firstly, I got my degree, with the grades I wanted, although not perhaps in the subjects I expected to get them in, though I guess thats always the way. As a result of that, I’m going to be staying on at Cardiff for a PhD conducting research into the PASOA project over the coming year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/08/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/08/08/security/</guid>
      <description>Blimey, some cheeky blighter signed up and posted on my blog! Well, I suppose it was my fault really seeing as how wordpress was configured to allow it! Anyway, I removed the offending post and reconfigured so we’re now back to normality…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Breasts</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/06/chicken-breasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/06/chicken-breasts/</guid>
      <description>In order to give a little more items of interest here, these are a few of the images which I’ve been creating to assist me with my Image Processing module here at Cardiff…
Basically, an image of a Chicken Breast is taken, and the best approximation to a cardioid found and displayed. This involves taking an image, performing Median filtering upon it to remove noise, edge detecting it with sobel masks, forming an accumulator space from the approximate gradient determined, and finally locating the largest peak within this space….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s been a while</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/03/its-been-a-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/05/03/its-been-a-while/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, haven’t really written much here in a while. Things are going ok, I have my final 4 exams over the next fortnight which I’m currently struggling revising for. Will hopefully pull out the grades I want, but I’m cutting it fine..
I’ve also finished my project, and its up and running on the web at www.understroke.com (requires client side XSL processing, IE 6+ Mozilla 1.4+).
Anyway, thats all I have to say for now, I’m off to watch Kill Bill 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Processing - Connected Component Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/03/05/image-processing-connected-component-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/03/05/image-processing-connected-component-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Ahh, theres a result.
I’ve been working some image processing coursework trying to correctly label an B+W image with a different label for each object in the image…it’s taken ages!….
The basic premise is, go through each pixel in the image. If this pixel has a neighbour which is labelled, label it with that label, if two pixel neighbours labels differ, store the equivalence in a table and resolve it later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arggh</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/26/arggh/</guid>
      <description>I’m realling struggling at the moment to get a visual interface all sorted and loverly so people can literally “point-and-click”. I made the decision to do this after talks with both my supervisor and moderator and have been trying like crazy to get it sorted, its taken over a week so far! Not good.
My moderator also suggested that trying to find example XML schemas for CMS’s which were already out on the market at the moment for would make for good reading also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Year with Moderator</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/16/mid-year-with-moderator/</guid>
      <description>Just had my mid-year meeting follow-up with my moderator. It seems he would like to see a focus on XML standards for this system, rather than just a botch of XML which I decided on. Don’t really know how I decide on that.
On searching for them though I found a CMS XML framework (uh-oh) which basically just outputs everything as XML. Find it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/11/ie/</guid>
      <description>Just realised that my cms doesn’t display properly in IE6. Might explain why it looked so dodgy at my mid-year meeting with my supervisor.
Got a few extra things in my project, permission system is fully functional, priorities for roles, workflow management – all of which still have bugs. Going to get down to the actual “management” part of the CMS tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a waste</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/02/01/what-a-waste/</guid>
      <description>What a waste of a day that was…I hate programming.
I’ve spent most of the day stuck on trivial little tasks like trying to pass back multi-dimensional arrays through scripts, and interpret the results.
On an upside, I’ve managed to get XSL producing XHTML output and generated a working grid for the actions in the system. I also found a bug in XSL which means that it will condense textarea tags to their smallest form, and resulting in incorrect display in most web browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSL</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/30/xml-xsl/</guid>
      <description>After spending most of the day working upon it, I have managed to convert the whole template system in my project over to XML. I also added the beginnings of a permissions system which has no functionality yet.
This does need some time for me to go through the motions of Spec, Design, Implementation write-up for this over the weekend so that I can present it next week during my mid-year progress presentation with my project supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML, XSLT</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/28/xml-xslt/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent a large portion of today converting bits of my project over to using XML with XSLT stylesheets. This solves a few issues that I’d had problems with.
 Generating RSS feeds. The masses of files for each template is now reduced to a single XSLT file, easily modified by anyone knowing what they are doing. Better compliance with web standards (missing “‘s, closing tags all need to be corrected) means that it should be relatively XHTML compliant when tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huzzah</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/23/huzzah/</guid>
      <description>Hurrah, exams over for another few months. I’m glad, and completely exhausted by them all. I was feeling completely overrun by them all. Still now its time to kick back and relax…until er – Monday</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ming</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2004/01/05/ming/</guid>
      <description>I should really write something about whats been going on over the Christmas hols, but I don’t want to waste any time which could be used for revision. What I will say though is that I’ve just discovered a sourceforge project called “Ming” which allows for easy SWF (Flash) output with php.
This could come in really handy in that it could be used to generate templates with animated content, such as recent additions or news feeds in side blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project - again...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project-again.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project-again.../</guid>
      <description>After having been working like theres no tomorrow on other coursework, I’ve finally managed to come back to my project work.
I’ve really not got very much productive work done on it aside from a few class diagrams and workflow routines which I’ve put together. I have been working on a prototype over the last month however in order to have that side of things produced on time. Currently it doesn’t do a lot more than add or delete users and needs to come a lot further before its something impressive which is worthy to be shown to my supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Knackered...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</guid>
      <description>I’ve been totally caning it over the last week or so…. I’ve got this Opengl graphics project due in very soon, and I’ve been working like a bit of a bandit on it. On the other side of the coin, I’ve got a databases piece due in on the same day which I haven’t made a start on yet. Guess I’ll be doing that over the weekend. Those will be in next week and then I’ll have some time to get moving on my project again….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh deary me..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</guid>
      <description>I’ve been trying to make some headway on my cms project today in order to get ahead and not end up in the same situation as I had in the second year. Seeing as I have a distinct lack of all things coursework related at the mo, I thought that would be a diamond idea. Unfortunately my knowledge of what now goes into a project is somewhat sparse, and I’m finding it a right job knowing where to tackle first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And so it begins..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</guid>
      <description>Used today (yesterday, actually) to take a look over the various things that can be done when using XML and XLST together. All in all it seems very impressive, and can hugely alter the way which a document may first be formatted. This may be a valid reason to choose this method over more standard CSS techniques, which generally just alter bog standard settings like color, font-size ….
On a side note, I also managed to get an NT install of CVS sorted and working nicely on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He ain&#39;t Heavy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/he-aint-heavy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/he-aint-heavy/</guid>
      <description>Having just installed the latest version of wordpress over b2 (thus ruining said previous mood plugin) I now have a working image upload abilities! Just to give you an idea of what goes on up in Cardiff, have a look at this pic of me and my long lost brother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moody</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/09/moody/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/09/moody/</guid>
      <description>Just messing about with a new mood plugin I’ve put up here..
Would be cool to let you guys know how I’m feeling right now..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woe is me</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</guid>
      <description>Oh dear, today has not been good…
After missing Church this morning, I proceeded to backup most of my hard disk onto my old ATA100 so that I could revert my main ATA150 partition back to a “simple” partition, so I *might * be able to install Linux.
After spending the best part of the afternoon backing up, I proceeded to download a partition tool to manage my partitions if Linux couldn’t handle it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back with a vengeance</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</guid>
      <description>After having my account removed (presumably because I should’ve theoretically graduated by now), making the move up to Cardiff, having my account reinstated and finally finding out that the web hosting had changed servers, with the mysql databases remaining on the same server (meaning that I had to change the “99% of the time you won’t need to change this” value) I am now able to have b2 back up and running smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Joys</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to pummel my friends workmates at a bit of LAN gaming yesterday, I took the initiative and upgraded my computer this week. Placed an order on Monday, ordering just the CPU fan from a different store – which proved to be a bad idea, it still hasn’t turned up yet! – preventing me from installing the CPU on my new motherboard…..Tut Tut ebuyer..
All well, its nice to have shedloads of space on my machine now, even if I don’t have any real need for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Rummaging</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/19/random-rummaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/19/random-rummaging/</guid>
      <description>Allow me to breathe a sigh of relief…I’ve just spent most of the last hour sorting out what’s rubbish from most of the paper lying about my room, whilst searching for my student support details. I did find them, could of been a messy first few weeks back at Uni if I hadn’t!
I also found a mates wedding invitation and list, reminding me that I actually have to reply to say that I’m attending, and buy them a present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All change</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/all-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/all-change/</guid>
      <description>Due to MT being incompatible with my Uni server from an imaging point of view, and the fact that its all coded in Perl – which I haven’t bothered looking at for a hell of a long time, I’ve ditched it and shifted my blog over to b2. Now I can actually post images! Woohoo! b2 is nice and tiny also, a mere 527Kb compared to MT’s 3Mb.
I’m actually toying with the idea of developing a blogging tool as a final year project, I think that might be very rewarding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just got back from my Churches “family fun” event. They have been doing a whole bunch of different events this week as an opportunity to witness to those who might not normally come to YCC otherwise. Today was the big finale of the week and was basically all the families who had been a part of the week meeting up with the members of the Church.
What that amounts to is lots of barbeques and little kiddies events galore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Install</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/blog-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/blog-install/</guid>
      <description>So, I’ve installed Movable Type on my website. I figured it was about time that I get up to speed on this whole “Blogging” thing, but I could of even missed the bus already.
I’ve spent half of the evening just looking at what can be done with MT, and it seems to integrate well with Invision Board as the MT crew have an example of a forum set up with it on their site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netpbm woes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/netpbm-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/netpbm-woes/</guid>
      <description>Right, Sonic Flux didn’t happen. Went to Martins instead to sort out a new monitor to replace his dying old one.
I’m having a right job trying to get the image side of MT working. I want to post images from my t610 on here, but it seems somethings afoot as when trying to submit thumbnails I get a lovely page of hex! Ah well…Maybe MT wasn’t such a good move…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonic Flux</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/sonic-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/sonic-flux/</guid>
      <description>I’m pondering whether or not it might be a good idea to upgrade Ben’s Sonicflux site to use MT. I don’t think that over the last year much has been done to update his site, (well I know it hasn’t – I’ve been maintaining it, bad idea) and I’m sure he’d make use of it. He sends out regular updates via email to let everyone know whats going on, I’m sure I could get MT to send regular email updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
