<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: popularity</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Why I Choose Popular Frameworks</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/01/04/why-i-choose-popular-frameworks</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I feel compelled to write this post so late in the day after clocking <a href="https://gist.github.com/4454814">Tyler Renelle’s rant</a> on github about his problems with the popularity of certain JS frameworks (in the main <a href="http://backbonejs.org">Backbone.js</a>). After having written apps in a variety of JS frameworks (Backbone, Spine and Meteor), I’ve learned that the feature set of a framework is not the only thing I hold dear when making a choice between them.</p>

<p>Documentation, support, learning curve and most importantly community are what also guide me when building anything. If I need to make an app quickly, I’ll of course develop it in my favourite tool (Backbone), because I’ve been using it for years and therefore doesn’t hold a cost. If I have a problem, I know there’s a ton of hackers who’ve probably already worked on solutions already and mechanisms are in place for them to offer advice. There may be better documented more capable tools, but I can’t foot the expense in the short term that might come with investigating something new and run the risk of hitting problems I can’t solve. In the long term, as a framework grows in popularity and garners these other factors then I may make that jump. </p>

<p>The real reason these frameworks are popular right now is in part because they are already popular.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>