<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: films</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Growing a Business with Developer APIs</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Those of your you who follow me on twitter will might be aware of a <a href="http://loveletterd.com">single day hack I attempted last week</a>, which takes output from Lovefilm’s customer history and formats it so it can easily be imported into the lovely Letterboxd. It’s named <a href="http://loveletterd.com">Loveletterd</a> and it seemed entirely appropriate to release it on Valentines day.</p>

<p>After hearing that Letterboxd had created a CSV import tool for it’s community to use and as I’m a <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">Lovefilm developer</a>, I felt like it would be a great use of my time to get to work on Loveletterd. </p>

<p>Originally, I’d thought I’d use Lovefilm’s OAuth sign-on, grab past rentals for a user and create a CSV from it formatting to Letterboxd’s import structure. I’d completely forgotten about a bug I raised on the developer forums; almost 3 years earlier – highlighting that actually this was impossible due to a bug which didn’t read a supplied argument, subsequently limiting the number of rental titles returned as the history. What’s more infuriating is that no one from Lovefilm had replied, even though the problem was reiterated by others in the same and other threads. There’s many different threads which highlight numerous other issues, all of which receive no or very little response from the Lovefilm developer team.</p>

<p>This is an awful way to treat a community excited about building tools with your company data. If you don’t want to cushion the cost of supporting providing such an API yourself, don’t create one, or charge for access to it. Similar sentiment has been said about twitter recently on changing their API rendering it unusable for apps that have based their business models on it. Such is the feeling of discontent that it’s led to a niche for rivals.</p>

<p>Lovefilm’s API “gallery” of developer apps features the message </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We will be placing details of the latest and greatest applications using our API here. Be sure to check this page regularly as new ideas are developed.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Which is also the same as 3 years ago, shortly after the API’s first release. Good work Lovefilm.</p>

<p>Remembering this, I walked away thinking, “Oh, well”, before going back to my workday. Explaining it to my wife, I realised there was another route to achieve what I wanted, which is what you see on the web now. Ultimately, this is nothing more than a bunch of regular expressions.</p>

<p>Admittedly, I’m aware there’s changes at Lovefilm – they’ve been entirely bought out by Amazon and I can imagine the new owners would want to integrate the company with their brand better. It seems as if they’ve already switched off new developer registrations, so I’d imagine the whole API will be turned off before long.</p>

<p>On the flip, take a look at where I want to take my data to – <a href="http://letterboxd.com">Letterboxd</a>. A site focused on film lovers and it shows. They’ve taken the route of paid pro accounts, which provide access to the <a href="http://letterboxd.com/about/importing-data/">import tools</a> I mentioned earlier. The majority of users won’t make use of this though; they just want to support a site providing a great service which is open and honest. They’re also planning on providing a full API, which I’ll be interested in playing with on release. As a result, I’m sure Letterboxd users will get a bunch of new toys they can use their accounts with that external developers decide to create.</p>

<p>The best thing though? They’re real people who talk to me. After letting them know about my little hack, I got thanks that same day from <a href="http://letterbox.com/about/crew">Matthew</a> of the Letterboxd crew, with a <a href="http://feedback.letterboxd.com/forums/136771-general/suggestions/2360263-add-lovefilm-imports">ticket closure</a> shortly thereafter. That beats 3 years of waiting.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>A Scientist in an Adventure with Pirates</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2012-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/08/29/a-scientist-in-an-adventure-with-pirates</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>This is a talk I did back in May at <a href="http://unifieddiff.co.uk">unifieddiff</a> about my time working as a web developer at Aardman Features. I talk quite a bit about the production process and what we take from staff in order to help them do their jobs properly. I quite enjoyed giving this talk – more so than those I’ve given in an academic capacity in the past.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Something I’ve thought I’d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I’ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I’m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I’ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I’ve got the opportunity to do this.</p>

<p>Our television came with a years subscription to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a>, which means I can now track our past film watching history. At four blu rays a month, that’s quite a lot of films over the course of the year.</p>

<p>Love Film have recently opened up their doors with an api and <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">developer area</a> (which unfortunately is not particularly active at the moment). Anyway – their documentation is pretty thorough and has made the process of creating a wordpress plugin to display my past rentals really simple. You can see some example output of it on my site <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/filmstream">over here</a>.</p>

<p>You can grab the plugin over <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/filmstream.zip">here</a>. It’s authenticated by oauth (for which you’ll require php on your blog host to be compiled with oauth enabled) and so will bounce you over to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a> to ask for access to your account, but after that will update on a daily basis. Just click “Fetch Items” on the filmstream admin page and stick <code>&lt;!--filmstream_content--&gt;</code> in any page to display a table containing all your past rentals. There’s no options to speak of right now, but I’m sure I’ll be extending it in the future.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2007-09-08T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of “The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain”, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill. They gradually take soil to the top of the (then) hill and eventually get it classed as a mountain by the cartographer. Carrying all that soil is no easy feat – it does require roping in all the villagers into getting it up the hill. It was quite amusing to be sitting in our living room watching a film about the mountain which could be seen through the window right next to our television. Anyway I’m really enjoying it out here – its such a sight to wake up every morning and see the Garth covered in cloud at its peak. I hope Viv and I get the chance and enough enthusiasm to walk it together soon. <a href="http://blog.stuartherbert.com/">Stuart Herbert</a> has some <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuartherbert/tags/thegarth/">great pics of the Garth on flickr</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0112966/" rel="attachment wp-att-182" title="The Englishman who went up a hill but came down a mountain"><img src="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/04m.jpg" alt="The Englishman who went up a hill but came down a mountain" /></a></p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>