<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web development on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/web-development/</link><description>Recent content in web development on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Problem with Full Stack JS Applications</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2013/04/03/the-problem-with-full-stack-js-applications/</guid><description>Whilst node.js heralded an era of being able to use a single language for both server and client side development, nobody mentioned the confusion such an approach could cause. It’s inevitable that there’s going to be similarities in code that constructs data on the server and that which presents it on the client. The fact that the two are written in the same language and the structure of them is so tightly coupled can make it easy to lose track of where you are and what you’re doing when knee deep in code.</description></item><item><title>A Survey of Hype in Web Development Podcasts</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/03/31/a-survey-of-hype-in-web-development-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2011/03/31/a-survey-of-hype-in-web-development-podcasts/</guid><description>I listen to quite a few web dev podcasts. Something that irks me about a lot of them, is how much they tend to hype their own shows, products or the like. Sure, they’re allowed to, it is their own podcast after all, often from their own businesses etc. I’m fully aware this all possibly contributes toward the success of shows, but it annoys me nonetheless.
One of these things is the title of the show itself.</description></item></channel></rss>