<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web Development Stack in 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Over my time as a web developer, I’ve jumped between many frameworks and languages, attempting to find ones that work well for me. This seems to be pretty typical for developers who always have a take on the latest trend, either to quickly adopt or criticise it.
I really wanted to be a member of the Ruby crew for a time and ended up buying multiple copies of “Agile Web Development with Rails”, before having the opportunity to really apply it to a project and disposing of them because the material was outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Weeks 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2--3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2--3/</guid>
      <description>So, anybody paying close attention may have noticed I&amp;#8217;ve skipped a week on updating my progress on shipping in March. There wasn&amp;#8217;t much to report in week 2 aside from I was busily updating my Nifty Digits site. This hasn&amp;#8217;t yet gone live, mainly due to some restrictions on current client projects and publishing about my previous work. I hope to be able to publish it before the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Filezilla Passwords with PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find in managing a number of websites is that I&amp;#8217;m always forgetting passwords. The version of Filezilla I&amp;#8217;m running however makes it easy to remember them again through its use of weak XOR encryption and a the key being hard coded into the software. I&amp;#8217;ve used a program previously called the Filezilla Password Recover, but it turns out that this is also extremely easy to extract them using a simple PHP script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash bash</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</guid>
      <description>I was quite impressed with myself the other day that I&amp;#8217;d actually managed to write a bash script within ubuntu which served a purpose. I wanted to be able to monitor the size of files within a particular directory, and report back their size when a change was observed.
I found a program called fileschanged, which fulfilled half the problem, namely reporting back a file had changed, but I needed a greater level of detail than that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>