<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 13:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Features in Python 3.9</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/05/interesting-features-in-python-3.9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 13:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/05/interesting-features-in-python-3.9/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some features I found interesting in the release of Python 3.9 last month. You can see me talk about each of these in my latest video on youtube.
Full Release Notes
Merging and Updating Dictionaries From PEP 584 - Dictionaries now have new union operators to work with them.
Python 3.8:
x = {&amp;#39;key&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;original_value&amp;#39;} y = {&amp;#39;key&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;updated_value&amp;#39;} print({**x, **y}) # Python 3.8 unpacking, kind of confusing Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Black to Format Python and get on with Your Life</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/03/use-black-to-format-python-and-get-on-with-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/11/03/use-black-to-format-python-and-get-on-with-your-life/</guid>
      <description>When I first started working in software development teams, I can remember heated discussions on pull requests on a few occasions. Typically these were when I or other developers reviewed code that didn&amp;rsquo;t meet formatting rules that were felt best for that piece of work. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether the rules in question were in code, documented in a README or just held in a developers head, the simple fact that something was wrong on the project meant the author needed to make changes, be severely reprimanded and never make the mistake again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy a Django App to the DigitalOcean App Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/28/how-to-deploy-a-django-app-to-the-digitalocean-app-platform/</guid>
      <description>Digitalocean recently launched their App platform, a platform as a service (PaaS) which can be seen as a competitor to the likes of Heroku. As a Python developer, I wanted to see how easy it was to deploy a django app to App platform. It took me a little while to configure everything correctly so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go through some of the points that tripped me up here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for some time for a relatively simple method for deploying my projects, but I also want to use a pattern where my repo is the primary source of truth for my app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing to PyPI Using Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 10:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/23/publishing-to-pypi-using-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>In creating my first package on PyPI, I realised that many of the tasks I&amp;rsquo;d want to do on a subsequent publish would be repetitive. If I wanted to push out a simple fix, I wanted to automate away those tasks so I could focus on my code rather than a sequence of repetitive steps.
Github actions is a simple way to do this and has given me the ability to quickly push out changes without lots of manual work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing a Package to PyPI with Poetry</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/20/publishing-a-package-to-pypi-with-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:04:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2020/10/20/publishing-a-package-to-pypi-with-poetry/</guid>
      <description>I recently published my first ever package to the Python Package Index (PyPI). The process was particularly novel for me as it meant my first ever use of the Poetry package management tool. If you happen to work in a production studio that uses ftrack and is now working remotely, you might even want to take a look at it as it enables sharing of assets using the Simple Storage Service (S3) from Amazon Web Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web Development Stack in 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Over my time as a web developer, I’ve jumped between many frameworks and languages, attempting to find ones that work well for me. This seems to be pretty typical for developers who always have a take on the latest trend, either to quickly adopt or criticise it.
I really wanted to be a member of the Ruby crew for a time and ended up buying multiple copies of “Agile Web Development with Rails”, before having the opportunity to really apply it to a project and disposing of them because the material was outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Weeks 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2-3/</guid>
      <description>So, anybody paying close attention may have noticed I’ve skipped a week on updating my progress on shipping in March. There wasn’t much to report in week 2 aside from I was busily updating my Nifty Digits site. This hasn’t yet gone live, mainly due to some restrictions on current client projects and publishing about my previous work. I hope to be able to publish it before the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Filezilla Passwords with PHP</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/01/05/decrypting-filezilla-passwords-with-php/</guid>
      <description>One of the most frustrating things I find in managing a number of websites is that I’m always forgetting passwords. The version of Filezilla I’m running however makes it easy to remember them again through its use of weak XOR encryption and a the key being hard coded into the software. I’ve used a program previously called the Filezilla Password Recover, but it turns out that this is also extremely easy to extract them using a simple PHP script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash bash</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/10/16/bash-bash/</guid>
      <description>I was quite impressed with myself the other day that I’d actually managed to write a bash script within ubuntu which served a purpose. I wanted to be able to monitor the size of files within a particular directory, and report back their size when a change was observed.
I found a program called fileschanged, which fulfilled half the problem, namely reporting back a file had changed, but I needed a greater level of detail than that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
