<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006/08 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006/08 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Igniter</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/23/code-igniter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with code igniter tonight, a php mvc framework. I discovered it yesterday, not realising that such things were available for php. As its extremely lightweight and seems to speeding up things no-end already, I reckon I&amp;#8217;ll probably be using it on some of my new slimshot projects I&amp;#8217;m planning on working on soon. I just need to get another life somewhere so I can actually go about implementing all this stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slug&#39;s Talking Nicely</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/19/slugs-talking-nicely/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had a couple of problems getting my slug working nice under ubuntu. Firstly, although it is recognised by default and I can connect and browse via samba, when I actually came to playing my media, everything got screwed up, with Amarok trying to launch kmail&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230; I could copy files to ubuntu and play them properly from there, but straight off of the slug was a no go.I found the solution was to mount it under ubuntu using the command:sudo mount -t smbfs //NAS/DISK 1 /media/slug -o username=user,password=passWhere user and pass are your username and password for the slug respectively and the backslash indicates a space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to contribute</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/14/i-want-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been wanting to create a site which attracts lot of attention for ages. Not to create some profit-making venture, just to know that my voice was being listened too elsewhere and hopefully appreciated. I suppose that goes for my PhD too. It&amp;#8217;s kind of depressing however that almost everything ever has been done, and every avenue seems blocked in both respects. How do you contribute to a world that is uninsterested in what you have to say?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Slugs</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/13/icy-slugs/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks back I discovered a slug in cash converters. Well, a usb2 external disk to nas drive converter affectionately known as the slug. Seeing as how I&amp;#8217;ve been considering purchasing one, I figured shelling out the £25 was worth it for an experiment with installing linux on it for a bit. The D-Link nslu2 features two usb2 connection points for hooking up usb2 drives, but I didn&amp;#8217;t really feel like sacrificing my university external box as this usually comes in quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Ubuntu? - ATI 9600 and SBLive</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu---ati-9600-and-sblive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/12/more-ubuntu---ati-9600-and-sblive/</guid>
      <description>Another post about ubuntu? Where will it end?I was fairly excited from thursday evenings antics of getting things working on my machine at home, I thought I&amp;#8217;d give it a try with my dev machine at uni. My graphics card, a 9600 (yes ATI, I know!) had been screwed since the day I&amp;#8217;d put on Dapper, and to be honest, as I&amp;#8217;m not using it that much for GL stuff, I wasn&amp;#8217;t really bothered about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I speak too soon?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/10/did-i-speak-too-soon/</guid>
      <description>It seems I may have spoken too soon about my linux joys with ubuntu. After performing a dist-upgrade on my previous beta version of Dapper, I discovered I&amp;#8217;d have to go through the same problems of downloading kernel source and linux header packages for my new kernel version.I also discovered after doing this that actually there were further problems on booting Dapper straight up. Apparently the pointers to drives get screwed up somewhere in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thieves</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/thieves/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#8217;d think that thieves would be content who&amp;#8217;d bent my door back along to try and nick my car, realising actually I have nothing of value. Or that by monitoring my movements over a period of time, the opportune time to get into it would be when I went away to Dublin, Chicago or Singapore for weeks on end. Apparently not, in fact, they think its such a prime example of Vauxhalls lack of security that they would in fact like to come back and try to nick it by bending out the other door right when I&amp;#8217;m here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Working</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/08/07/ubuntu-working/</guid>
      <description>FInally, after a grand total of 10 months, I have a 64bit version of Ubuntu Linux working upon my home machine.This is great news, not only does it mean that I have a wonderful OS to try out for size, but that I can easily convert my subversion server code and latex source to my machine.As I&amp;#8217;ve never mentioned it before, I&amp;#8217;ll detail what the problem was here. First up, the graphics card didn&amp;#8217;t have drivers which were working which meant that my X800 was pretty pathetic to be quite honest with you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>