<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fair  Bare - January £10 Sale!</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2010/01/07/fair--bare---january-10-sale/</guid>
      <description>Fair &amp;#038; Bare &amp;#8211; The little shop I run (with a little help from my wife) is having a January Sale right now in celebration of entering the year 2010. Every shirt we&amp;#8217;ve made to date is just 10 squid! Hurry up people, it only runs until Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Google</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/discovering-google/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve recently read a post over on the guardians technology site which gave a whistle-stop history of the internet as it turns 40. I thought I&amp;#8217;d share here my own experiences of growing up alongside the web, more for my own record than anything.
I remember at school a time at which there was no external connection, nor internal network (which we the pupils used) so the Acorn machines used at our school at the time could communicate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has web use changed your life?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/02/15/how-has-web-use-changed-your-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been pondering this morning how the use of the internet has (or may have) changed my life. As a child/teen during the web&amp;#8217;s infancy, I was blissfully unaware that so many lifes/careers/relationships would be enabled or changed as a result of the interactions it might facilitate. I hadn&amp;#8217;t even heard of google prior to arriving at university and two years prior to that had never had internet access anywhere locally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>