<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phd on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phd on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/02/papers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just been informed that my paper for CCGRID06 has been accepted, which I&amp;#8217;m very pleased about. It&amp;#8217;s my first paper acceptance in my 14 months of being based as a PhD at Cardiff University so really its about time I got some ideas out in the open to people. It&amp;#8217;s also based in Singapore, and I&amp;#8217;ve never left Europe &amp;#8211; yeah it&amp;#8217;s two days, but I&amp;#8217;m chuffed nonetheless.
The ironic thing is I was a bit annoyed last year at the fact CCGRID05 was in Cardiff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/02/01/cutting-edge/</guid>
      <description>My day was brightened lots yesterday when my my PhD supervisor informed me he had a blog on the subject of grid computing. It was intended for members of our research group to contribute to and discuss things. The most amusing part was, being cutting edge and all, you&amp;#8217;d expect it to be a bustling hive of activity. What I actually found was a site with two posts covering the last 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a difference a year makes....</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/07/12/what-a-difference-a-year-makes..../</guid>
      <description>So, in the absence of students, life continues as normal for the various research teams down here in the Queens buildings. We wake, march to University and sit in our little boxes reading, theorising and tearing our hair out until 5 o&amp;#8217;clock when we march back, only to be repeated the next day. I hate routines&amp;#8230;
Today marked the graduation of Year 3&amp;#8242;s which brought back memories of my graduation last year, which was pretty depressing to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Mental</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/06/29/mental-mental/</guid>
      <description>Today I travelled on 2 planes, 3 buses and 1 car (thats a full house and extra) to make the 800 mile round trip to Edinburgh for part of a BioDiveristyWorld conference. I&amp;#8217;m quite surprised I managed to organise and sort out everything since Monday and it go according to plan.
I was actually really overwhelmed at how amazing the place was for the brief time I was there, the sheer scale of the city was something else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>