<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: lovefilm</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>Essential Cinema According to Lovefilm</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-lovefilm</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2012-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2012/11/20/essential-cinema-lovefilm</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Given there’s a bit of lovefilm bashing <a href="http://www.tomalloyd.com/lovefilm-hate-email/">going on in Wales</a> at the moment, I thought I’d chime in with the most frustrating thing I found with communications from lovefilm. </p>

<p>Check out the following weekly email I used to receive (I’ve since unsubscribed), along with my annotations.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lovefilm.com/emailpublic/cmsnewsletter/uk-newsletter/LOVEFiLM-Newsletter/2012/Newsletter-Issue-No-409?cid=lfnl409tlweb&#038;brand=lovefilm"><img src="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Read-Newsletter-Issue-409-5.jpg" alt="" title="Read Newsletter Issue 409 5" width="470" height="906" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-569" /></a></p>

<p>I really couldn’t care less about who lovefilm are sending into cinema’s to perform reviews and certainly don’t want it to be the first text I see in relation to that image. </p>

<p>Also, the first thing I’m drawn to is the image. Why lead me away from the title of that movie and make work to find the text for the heading? Don’t make the title and preview exactly the same size, or divide them up!</p>

<p>End of rant.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin v0.2</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0-2</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2011-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/20/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-v0-2</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Just a quick note to say I’ve updated the plugin that generates my <a href="http://ianwootten.co.uk/filmstream">filmstream pages</a>. It’s become obvious that the <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">Lovefilm API</a> only exposes the last 10 features that you’ve rented in their “at home” list. This isn’t that great if you’ve been renting more than a few months. This is the same as the information you’d see in your account when logged in.</p>

<p>I’ve made a simple modification to use the actual ids that <a href="http://lovefilm.com">Lovefilm</a> issue for films, rather than a autoincrement value. This way, there’s no need to empty what’s currently stored when updating and we capture the users history of rentals…</p>

<p>You can grab it over <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/filmstream.zip">here</a></p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Lovefilm Filmstream Plugin for WordPress</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/04/18/lovefilm-filmstream-plugin-for-wordpress</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Something I’ve thought I’d like to have on my site for a while is a list of movies that I’ve recently seen and some brief opinions on them. I’m not entirely sure how I would go about this for films I see at the cinema, or whether I could muster the stamina to review every single film I’ve watched, but a recent television upgrade has now meant I’ve got the opportunity to do this.</p>

<p>Our television came with a years subscription to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a>, which means I can now track our past film watching history. At four blu rays a month, that’s quite a lot of films over the course of the year.</p>

<p>Love Film have recently opened up their doors with an api and <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">developer area</a> (which unfortunately is not particularly active at the moment). Anyway – their documentation is pretty thorough and has made the process of creating a wordpress plugin to display my past rentals really simple. You can see some example output of it on my site <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/filmstream">over here</a>.</p>

<p>You can grab the plugin over <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/downloads/filmstream.zip">here</a>. It’s authenticated by oauth (for which you’ll require php on your blog host to be compiled with oauth enabled) and so will bounce you over to <a href="http://www.lovefilm.com">lovefilm</a> to ask for access to your account, but after that will update on a daily basis. Just click “Fetch Items” on the filmstream admin page and stick <code>&lt;!--filmstream_content--&gt;</code> in any page to display a table containing all your past rentals. There’s no options to speak of right now, but I’m sure I’ll be extending it in the future.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>