<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2007 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2007 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stick to your guns - You&#39;ll be rewarded</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/12/20/stick-to-your-guns-youll-be-rewarded/</guid>
      <description>I’m a firm believer that by upholding my own principles, I’ll be rewarded. It’s a tag line I adopted for the small hosting company that I’ve been running for a while now. It also has been reflected this year in a nasty situation I was left in with my landlords, the council and a previous housemate (who doesn’t really deserve that title, more just a person whom shared the house). In all these situations things have turned out better for me in the long run, due to myself re-enforcing what I believe should be done – even if it does mean a longer struggle through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Cardiff Geek Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/first-cardiff-geek-meetup/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiff geeks will be having its first ever face to face on Wednesday 17th October from 7pm at Cafe Floyd, just opposite the castle. Props to Dan Zambonini for organising the venue.
This is an informal, introduction between us all. If you’re a geek, or interested in chatting with us about what we and you are passionate about, make sure you get over there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undeserved Job Titles</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/20/undeserved-job-titles/</guid>
      <description>Today on the return from uni I passed the new Subway that is opening up soon near Queen Street train station. On one of their job adverts, they were advertising for team leaders and sandwich artists. I’ve never really noticed my sandwiches being arranged in a artistic fashion before, maybe it would brighten my day if they were. I feel sorry for the poor art school graduate who ends up filling baguettes for a living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Cardiff</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/fowa-roadtrip-cardiff/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which would you rather introduce yourself with?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/11/which-would-you-rather-introduce-yourself-with/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the FOWA Roadtrip in Cardiff, which was great. Unfortunately my “business” cards were a little lacking, due to me making a rather late order from moo and having to put something together by hand for the interim. They instead arrived today, about 14 hours too late. I felt like writing “beta” on hand hand-made ones or something…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Englishman who lived at the bottom of a mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/08/the-englishman-who-lived-at-the-bottom-of-a-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Taffs Well, just outside of Cardiff, Viv and I have enjoyed fantastic views of the Garth. This mountain is the centre for the original true story of “The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down A Mountain”, a book/film which I managed to catch on TV this week. Basically, it goes like this, the villagers of Taffs Well work together to try to prevent an English cartographer from leaving the village and classifying the Garth as a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiff Geeks</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/07/cardiff-geeks/</guid>
      <description>I’ve long wondered why there doesn’t seem to be much happening in terms of community of the web professionals in wales. There is a vibrant collection of people sporting different skill sets in the area, yet as I can see not a lot of chat amongst everyone in between different groups. On a whim, I decided to create a facebook group “Cardiff Web Geeks” to try and get people to come out of their shells and actually participate in a bit of discussion about tech topics in wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New iPods - 160Gb or Touch Interface?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods-160gb-or-touch-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/09/06/new-ipods-160gb-or-touch-interface/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing too much?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/31/sharing-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/31/sharing-too-much/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neckache</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/16/neckache/</guid>
      <description>The other evening I managed to stretch my back awkwardly and I’ve been feeling the repercussions of it ever since. It’s extremely painful to move my head, arm or neck and I’m getting really frustrated by not being able to sit at the computer without being uncomfortable. Wednesday night I was flat out in bed not able to move an inch, and little more of an improvement last night. It’s making me really tired and irritable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOWA Roadtrip Bristol</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/08/08/fowa-roadtrip-bristol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stag Do</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/22/my-stag-do/</guid>
      <description>Now that the big day has passed, I thought I’d start revealing how some of my days in the lead up to it were spent. For my stag do, firstly we had a fairly quiet night in playing computer games, after doing a shop at Asda and getting the majority of mates locked out of our new pad. Many laughed at my wii fighting skills. Saturday, we travelled over to the Forest of Dean to climb through the tree-course that is Go Ape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where have I been?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/07/20/where-have-i-been/</guid>
      <description>Is a question you may have asked yourself once or twice on the absence of any written word on this site. Well, aside from not being here – I’ve been doing many things including moving house from my home of 3 years, playing a small part in organising a wedding and actually getting married (I know!). I’ve also just returned from honeymoon with wife in tow and now we’re trying to figure out where all our stuff should go when it’s never had a home before and we’ve never owned it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want this Coffee Table Please</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/19/i-want-this-coffee-table-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/19/i-want-this-coffee-table-please/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thou Shalt Always Kill</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/18/thou-shalt-always-kill/</guid>
      <description>I am loving this track I just discovered on Adam Fletchers blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re off to see the Hackers</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/were-off-to-see-the-hackers/</guid>
      <description>The wonderful hackers of, er Britain. When I say we, I actually mean me because my wife to be has to head back to Abergavenny before me. Which means that actually I’ll be the only one able to make use of my free invite to see the rumble strips. Oh well.I’m actually a bit nervy about heading over – I have done an extreme lack of preparation in terms of programming and I’m going to be sleeping in a room full of nerds and pcs, or possibly not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s up with Last.fm?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/15/whats-up-with-last.fm/</guid>
      <description>Last.fm seems to be down at the moment for the last couple of minutes. Anyone know what’s going on?[Update:Looks like this was just a blip, ho hum]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Developer Day</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/06/03/google-developer-day/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just returned from my stint in the South East after being invited to attend Googles London Developer day on thursday and remaining there to hang out in Haddenham for the weekend. Theres a ton of photo’s over on a picasa web album which has been built up from peoples pics. I even got interviewed regarding using the google web toolkit, but my experience was not exactly extended so I don’t know if it would get used at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay for DevDay!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/24/yay-for-devday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/24/yay-for-devday/</guid>
      <description>Wow! A long time ago I signed up for google’s developer day, to be on their waiting list. I’d completely forgotten but just got an invite asking me if I wanted to come along. Crazy! First yahoo, now google! I’m very, very excited.Obviously I am not more excited about either of these days than my wedding day… </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay for Hackday!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/18/yay-for-hackday/</guid>
      <description>I just heard I’ve got invited to Hackday! That’s totally awesome, I’m really excited! I signed up half expecting to be told to “go jump” and I’d contacted the administrators of the list due to hearing nothing about it and some confusing responses at first – but I just got my proper invite. Woo! – Impressive as I didn’t put much of an explanation of my work on there. I guess it was my sob story about my ongoing PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to acquire Yahoo? - Cost? $50 Billion!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/04/microsoft-to-acquire-yahoo-cost-50-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/05/04/microsoft-to-acquire-yahoo-cost-50-billion/</guid>
      <description>Mashable is reporting that a Microsoft-Yahoo merger may be on the cards, which is a fairly bizarre prospect.
The price? $50 Billion, is Yahoo only worth 30 odd YouTubes? I for one think not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big it Up for Yeovil!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/25/big-it-up-for-yeovil/</guid>
      <description>Browsing across Matt Westcotts site yielded this particular gem. [I&amp;rsquo;m from there don&amp;rsquo;t you know?]. I used to love tracking it up in fasttracker, but haven’t done anything for a very, very long time. Maybe I should start experimenting again….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check the Prices in Your Area</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/17/check-the-prices-in-your-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/17/check-the-prices-in-your-area/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that not only can http://rightmove.co.uk hunt down all the prices of current houses for sale in your area, it will also give you the prices that houses have gone for for the last 7 years? I didn’t, but tonight I enjoyed checking out the fact that someone bought a house in my road for £40k in January (but I think either this is a typo, or the place is a hole!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joost Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/12/joost-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/12/joost-beta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bills are Boring</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/04/bills-are-boring/</guid>
      <description>Doing household bills is extremely boring. I just spent two hours dividing up the phone bill and working out who owes what. If marriage brings me anything, at least it will bring me less of a headache when it comes to doing the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashup!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/04/03/mashup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threshers Voucher Number 2</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/21/threshers-voucher-number-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/21/threshers-voucher-number-2/</guid>
      <description>[via Vecosys]I’ve just read on vecosys’ blog that Stormhoek has just posted Threshers Voucher Number 2. This will most certainly come in handy for all that wine we need to get for the wedding….Go grab it over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threadless launches Threadlesskids.com</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/threadless-launches-threadlesskids.com/</guid>
      <description>Threadless has launched threadlesskids.com – like threadless, but for kids. I suppose that should come in handy for Jake and Shondis recent announcement. Anyway, it looks wicked – its amazing how the kids stuff costs more than adult though! My friends told me kids are expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wed Designer - I wish I had one!&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer-i-wish-i-had-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/19/wed-designer-i-wish-i-had-one/</guid>
      <description>Currently Viv and I are planning our wedding for later in the year, which aside from being the most exciting thing ever, is really, really stressful. Apparently though, there are wed designers about, though I never realised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/12/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>If anyone else like me is considering working in the uk “web 2.0″ market, and finds the posts on common job boards clogged up with all the jobs from america, the small job board I have created and posted online might be a help. You’ll find it over at: http://webtyrant.com/jobs. It aggregates some common job boards together like 37Signals and ThinkVitamin, but removes anything but those located in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pMachine changes its name</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/09/pmachine-changes-its-name/</guid>
      <description>pMachine has changed its name to Ellislab, and are sporting a shiny new website for all to see. The reason for the change is the expansion over the last 6 years to encompass products which don’t fall under the same banner now. I’m glad to see that the CodeIgniter website has got a facelift. 31three did the hard graft on the design and they all look awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenID - The end of multiple passwords?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/08/openid-the-end-of-multiple-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/08/openid-the-end-of-multiple-passwords/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hearing some really good stuff about openID recently. For those who don’t know, this is a online identity standard which promises to be the end of having multiple passwords at just about every single website you visit. It’s recently risen to light with the adoption by WordPress.com as a provider and digg as an adopter.Complaints against wordpress.com’s non-allowance of logins with openID’s created anywhere else than wordpress.com seem quite well founded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s my birthday soon</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/03/07/its-my-birthday-soon/</guid>
      <description>Did you not know? I’m going to hit the grand old age of 26 soon. Whooah, thats like ancient. If you want some ideas of what you can get me (I obviously expect a gift), why not check my gift list here and here, to save the embarrasment of some really awful gift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes the Fuzz</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/here-comes-the-fuzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/here-comes-the-fuzz/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, Cineworld gave us tickets free to any film of our choice when we were meant to be seeing a preview, due to a cock up at their end. I already knew what it would be without looking at what was out, Hot Fuzz.
I’ve loved Simon Pegg ever since the days of Big Train, when humour was just so completely random it had to be funny. Shaun of the Dead had some great random moments in it, but I left it feeling that it wasn’t the best I’d come to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for Beatbox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/20/recipe-for-beatbox/</guid>
      <description>This link sent to me by Lewis made me laugh quite a lot. Funnily, it looks a lot like him with a wig on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Star Wars</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/02/silent-star-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/02/silent-star-wars/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered this amusing star wars video coutesy of Jason Cospers blog. Highly amusing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Coloured iPod Shuffle</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/01/new-coloured-ipod-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/02/01/new-coloured-ipod-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Thought I’d just point out that apple uk are touting the new ipod shuffle today. Basically they have launched a bunch of extra colours, with no change to size or capacity, but they do look rather pretty. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotdealsuk - Indexing the webs best deals</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/24/hotdealsuk-indexing-the-webs-best-deals/</guid>
      <description>I came across hotdealsukprior to christmas and I think its an absolute must for any techie thats currently residing in the uk. Basically, a sophisticated messageboard, bargains of interest to the community are highlighted and then voted upon. Those more highly voted make it through to the front page.
I absolutely love it and so far have managed to purchase 1 xbox (with 4 games) @ £50 and a 400Gb harddrive @ £83.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Web Apps, Future of Web Design</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/future-of-web-apps-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>If anyone would like to contribute to allow me to attend the Future of Web Apps or the Future of Web Design conferences over the next few months, I’d put together some independent reviews of the events on this site. As the funds of a lowly research student are not all that much cop, you can donate some funds using the donation page.At the moment, registration for Web Apps is £195 + VAT (£595 + VAT including workshops), and Web Design is £59 +VAT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MS Firefox</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/ms-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft and Firefox have joined to bring us MSFirefox. Finally Microsoft have seen the light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today is not a good day to cycle!</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/18/today-is-not-a-good-day-to-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Richmond road in Cardiff today is pretty much like a river all the way down today, due to all the horrid weather hitting it, resulting in the following set of footprints (post cycling to work) around my office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t every day be a holiday?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2007/01/16/why-cant-every-day-be-a-holiday/</guid>
      <description>I had a some great times away on holidays recently. The first was at New Year in Rhayader with the usual suspects getting absolutely soaked and vowing never to let anyone else plan a walk ever again. It was good to get outside away from these pesky machines.
As if that wasn’t enough, I went away to France to the slightly more exciting Alps for a skiing holiday for a week too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
