<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006/09 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006/09 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flickr</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/30/flickr/</guid>
      <description>After just 24 hours on flickr, someone has already added one of my pictures as one of their favourites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Jobs in Web 2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/26/uk-jobs-in-web-2.0/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been following a number of so called &amp;#8220;web 2.0&amp;#8243; companies in the uk recently via techcrunch.co.uk in order to explore what might be available to me when I need to start work this time next year. It&amp;#8217;s quite interesting that actually, there is a number of companies cited around the Cardiff/Bristol/Bath areas that I&amp;#8217;d never realised were in the UK.In Bath, there&amp;#8217;s Carson Systems, which also host a number of web application workshops around the uk, with a Drop Send and Amigo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My final year of being a student?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/24/my-final-year-of-being-a-student/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;#8217;d pose this as a question because I&amp;#8217;m unsure if this is indeed my final year. It&amp;#8217;s quite strange to think at the end of this thing I&amp;#8217;m actually going to have to find some work somewhere another. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated from whomever. I&amp;#8217;m looking for £50k/yr involving part time work from home, company car, but then I think the rest of the world is too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone want to buy a car?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/17/anyone-want-to-buy-a-car/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m selling my car, which has been with me for the last 4&amp;frasl;5 years and always been very reliable. It&amp;#8217;s a very nice Vauxhall Corsa 1.5 TD in red, for more details, check freeads here and drop me an email either through freeads or this website if you&amp;#8217;re interested.
I&amp;#8217;m pretty sad to see the thing go, but as I now have no need for it due to the acquiring of my own personal chauffeur, it seems a bit uneconomical to hang on to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web is Just to Darn Big</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/14/the-web-is-just-to-darn-big/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been suffering at the hands of the sheer size of the web recently. Just starting off at popurls yields many hours spent just browsing randomly across many, many web buzz sites. Although its all very interesting, its not particularly useful to my research, or in fact my own projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XGL, Compiz on Dapper 64 - Too much to ask?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64---too-much-to-ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/06/xgl-compiz-on-dapper-64---too-much-to-ask/</guid>
      <description>I spent a large amount of time last week, after realising that I could very easy install compiz and XGL on my machine at uni, trying to install it upon my home machine. As its 64 bit, and owing to previous problems I&amp;#8217;d experienced installing 64 bit applications (like linux for instance), I spent the best part of 2 days attempting to install both, before caving and completely giving up.I got to the stage where XGL is installed properly and seems to work ok, but the compiz gnome window manager isn&amp;#8217;t working properly, meaning I have no borders to any panes I create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/09/03/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, we&amp;#8217;ve not spoken in a while. How&amp;#8217;s you?It seems I&amp;#8217;ve been succumbing to a lifestyle of late that I wish I would never end up at &amp;#8211; that of working within a &amp;#8220;routine&amp;#8221;. I must be getting old. The whole of last week seemed a little bit of a drain, working my ass off trying to get tiny parts of code to work properly in the day and the rest of the time being tired that I was staying up late to give myself alone time in the evenings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>