<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014/03 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014/03 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Weeks 2 &amp; 3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2--3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/23/shipping-in-march-weeks-2--3/</guid>
      <description>So, anybody paying close attention may have noticed I&amp;#8217;ve skipped a week on updating my progress on shipping in March. There wasn&amp;#8217;t much to report in week 2 aside from I was busily updating my Nifty Digits site. This hasn&amp;#8217;t yet gone live, mainly due to some restrictions on current client projects and publishing about my previous work. I hope to be able to publish it before the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March: Week 1</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/10/shipping-in-march-week-1/</guid>
      <description>I promised a progress update on how my attempt to get 4 projects shipped this month was going. On my first week, I decided to focus on my time tracking tool, hourglass. I&amp;#8217;ve had this in the works for sometime and unfortunately, it&amp;#8217;s fallen by the wayside to client work.
I&amp;#8217;ve failed on my first week in getting this released to the world, but I&amp;#8217;m far happier with how it&amp;#8217;s working now and the value it might give to any potential user than previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a Linear Domain to an Ordinal Range with d3</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/07/scaling-a-linear-domain-to-an-ordinal-range-with-d3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had the opportunity of using d3 quite a lot over the past few months for a number of clients. It offers some amazing flexibility for chart generation and much more.
Anyway, I thought I&amp;#8217;d share a quick tip I developed for mapping a linear set of values onto an ordinal scale. For those who&amp;#8217;re seasoned pros at d3, this probably seems trivial, but had me stumped for some time today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping in March</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/03/03/shipping-in-march/</guid>
      <description>This month, I&amp;#8217;ve decided to take some time out to ship projects.
I have a huge list of projects accumulating I&amp;#8217;d like to push out of the door, but as a father and freelancer I have lack of a certain commodity in able to achieve them. That would be time.
Currently I don&amp;#8217;t have any work booked in for a while, so along with Viv, we&amp;#8217;ve decided I should try and get some of these projects released.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>