<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/04 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/04 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What a palava</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/30/what-a-palava/</guid>
      <description>I went off to meet up with my Sis and Viv in Swansea on Thursday night, the drive out there and around the bay was fantastic, beautiful scenery in wonderful weather that I don&amp;#8217;t often get to see around Cardiff. I think the comparison was made between the bay and Roath Park by Viv, but to be honest, there isn&amp;#8217;t much of one. After a full on carvery meal and everyone feeling like veritable fat jabba&amp;#8217;s, we drove over to the mumbles to munch on ice-cream (follow the logic there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitch Hikers Guide to the Skittle Alley</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/27/hitch-hikers-guide-to-the-skittle-alley/</guid>
      <description>Every time I visit UGC Cardiff it brings back terrible memories of when I went to see &amp;#8216;Matrix Revolutions&amp;#8217; last year. A bit psyched by the fact that it may of be able to redeem the tragedy which was &amp;#8216;Matrix Reloaded&amp;#8217;, I went to see it with some of the Glamorgan crew on its day of release. All was going as well as could be expected, until when 3&amp;frasl;4 way through we were treated to a bit of a fight sequence and aerial acrobatics, which didn&amp;#8217;t really seem to fit with what we had been watching, but could of been some sort of trendy &amp;#8216;dream sequence&amp;#8217;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things you might not know about CV&#39;ers..</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/26/some-things-you-might-not-know-about-cvers../</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s some interesting information I found about fellow Cardiff Vineyard&amp;#8217;ers*.
 Jon Mathais was the producer of the New Romantics and was cut from the Sony Open in Hawaii on the 2005 PGA Tour. Jonathan Morgan holds both a successful &amp;#8216;modeling&amp;#8217; career and since 1999 has also been a Conservative Assembly Member. Zoe Morgan once featured in a Dr Who Episode (Season 25, Episode 152 -&amp;#8217; Remembrance of the Daleks&amp;#8217;) as &amp;#8216;Girl&amp;#8217;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far have I come?</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/22/how-far-have-i-come/</guid>
      <description>Having free time in the evenings recently is a wonderful thing, and its given me the chance to think about &amp;#8216;stuff&amp;#8217; I might not of done otherwise, recently its been my undergrad life. When I came to University, I was all fired up for an amazing walk through Christendom, I tried to throw myself into the Christian Union, and for a while it was great. Unfortunately my work got a grip of me very quickly, and for all the wrong reasons I backed off from CU and any kind of fellowship with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Busy Busy</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/18/busy-busy-busy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been running around a bit like a headless chicken recently, not content with spending lots of time at uni working, I&amp;#8217;ve been partying pretty hard as well.
Spent Friday going to Kez&amp;#8217;s 21st birthday for a meal at Old Orleans, which was rather tasty. Bombed back to hang out with Vineyardites at Marty&amp;#8217;z Kitchen, which we were duely moved on from to Cafe aroma, and back to mine (after a few choice insults were uttered by me) for a nice cuppa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebay Bargains</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/ebay-bargains/</guid>
      <description>If I had something interesting to say I would say it, but I don&amp;#8217;t really so instead I&amp;#8217;ll hit you with a few ebay bargains I&amp;#8217;ve picked up of late. Currently I&amp;#8217;m holding a rating of 166 positive, I reckon thats pretty good. Anybody else bought anything interesting off the net lately?
 Cut N Paste &amp;#8211; Forget It [12&amp;rdquo; Single] (£1.99). I&amp;#8217;ve been after this ever since I heard it on a Fatboy Slim &amp;#8216;On the Floor at the Boutique&amp;#8217; mix CD donkeys years ago&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signs</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/04/05/signs/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s loads of places on the net where you can view silly or stupid signs. Most of the ones I&amp;#8217;ve seen aren&amp;#8217;t from the UK though, and I can&amp;#8217;t imagine them any kind of scenario, which I think would make them all the more funny. This place has loads, so many I can&amp;#8217;t afford to look through all of them. I can&amp;#8217;t believe I&amp;#8217;ve missed it before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>