<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2006/07 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2006/07 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Irony</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/27/the-bitter-irony/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I got a little annoyed about the fact that it seemed as if play had forgotten all details of my existence and telling me my email address was wrong. After sending a little letter off to them complaining yesterday evening, I realised after their response that actually I’d altered my saved email a little while before. I went ahead and placed my order of Sideways this morning which I’d expected to be fairly good due to the rave reviews I’d heard of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it take to make a good wife?</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/23/what-does-it-take-to-make-a-good-wife/</guid>
      <description>From “How To Succeed With Women Without Really Trying” c1957
“The first wife, as opposed to the fiancee, must be practicable and serviceable. She is neither a toy, an ornament, nor a playmate. She will be your wife during the early, hard years before you can afford a staff of servants. She will serve as mother, cook, housemaid, chauffeur, nurse, and charwoman. This will allow her, if she is nimble, six or seven hours of sleep a night, ample for a sturdy girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mull</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/07/08/mull/</guid>
      <description>So my holiday in Mull more than surpassed the expectations I had for it. Beautiful scenery, solitude, our own private beach, lots of sheep and cows etc etc. In fact, you had to be fairly careful negotiating the roads of Mull for fear of taking out the 50 odd sheep that would block our journey to and from the house. That and the rocks (which we experienced through a blowout). We visited the smaller islands of Iona and Staffa, with both being beautiful but Staffa getting my vote (its full of puffins, rather than americans).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
