<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
   
   	<title>ianwootten.co.uk - Tag: hacking</title>
   
   <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk</link>
   <description>I'm a Web Developer  working at <a href="http://niftydigits.com">Nifty Digits</a> in Cardiff, UK. Here, I enjoy talking code - mostly javascript. I'm <a href="http://twitter.com/iwootten">@iwootten</a> on twitter.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>I.M.Wootten</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
	  <item>
        <title>The Developer Dream</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/06/27/the-developer-dream</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-06-27T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/06/27/the-developer-dream</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>I suffer from idea overload. It seems that every day I have an idea for something. As a developer, I’m lucky in that to be able to take an idea to inception very quickly. Best of all, I can show it at inception stage to a huge audience (if I had one), garner feedback and quickly iterate on that idea. To date, I’ve mainly created these by myself – a casualty of doing paid work in the main like this too. </p>

<p>Most of these ideas in the have been simple hacks – <a href="http://loveletterd.com">solutions to things that bug me</a>. <a href="http://fairandbare.com">One of them has been a proper business too</a>. I’m able to do something and make it happen, to potentially tap a huge audience. Get them to that first step. The problem I have is, not a single one of these so much as turns a profit, though they serve as wonderful educational devices for me. I would hazard a guess that some of them have indirectly got me work.</p>

<p>Some of my ideas never get past the domain registration phase before being knocked on the head. A friend many years ago gave me the great quote that ‘My domains are my todo list’. This totally hits the nail on the head for me – if I’ve felt like an idea was good enough to make it to the registration phase, there’s something there worth pursuing. Unfortunately, I have quite a long list to work through.</p>

<p>I heard it said that “The Developer Dream” is that we (developers) “build a product/service which we’re able to earn a living from”. But the majority of developers I know, don’t even begin to pursue the ideas they have. This surprises me. </p>

<p>There seems to be such an abundance of opportunities that I can’t imagine not building my own ideas, however bad they might seem to others. </p>

<p>Why hold back? Time? Yes, we have other commitments – family, work and maybe even a hobby or two. I’m not suggesting we make drastic sacrifices or sell our kids in order to create stuff. I’d would however, like to think that the payoff for building our ideas might make our initial holdups seem insignificant longer term. <a href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2012/05/03/if-you-build-it">I’ve said it before</a> and I can’t speak from as the voice of successful experience, but what do I get out of never trying?</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Growing a Business with Developer APIs</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2013-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2013/02/20/growing-a-business-with-developer-apis</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Those of your you who follow me on twitter will might be aware of a <a href="http://loveletterd.com">single day hack I attempted last week</a>, which takes output from Lovefilm’s customer history and formats it so it can easily be imported into the lovely Letterboxd. It’s named <a href="http://loveletterd.com">Loveletterd</a> and it seemed entirely appropriate to release it on Valentines day.</p>

<p>After hearing that Letterboxd had created a CSV import tool for it’s community to use and as I’m a <a href="http://developer.lovefilm.com">Lovefilm developer</a>, I felt like it would be a great use of my time to get to work on Loveletterd. </p>

<p>Originally, I’d thought I’d use Lovefilm’s OAuth sign-on, grab past rentals for a user and create a CSV from it formatting to Letterboxd’s import structure. I’d completely forgotten about a bug I raised on the developer forums; almost 3 years earlier – highlighting that actually this was impossible due to a bug which didn’t read a supplied argument, subsequently limiting the number of rental titles returned as the history. What’s more infuriating is that no one from Lovefilm had replied, even though the problem was reiterated by others in the same and other threads. There’s many different threads which highlight numerous other issues, all of which receive no or very little response from the Lovefilm developer team.</p>

<p>This is an awful way to treat a community excited about building tools with your company data. If you don’t want to cushion the cost of supporting providing such an API yourself, don’t create one, or charge for access to it. Similar sentiment has been said about twitter recently on changing their API rendering it unusable for apps that have based their business models on it. Such is the feeling of discontent that it’s led to a niche for rivals.</p>

<p>Lovefilm’s API “gallery” of developer apps features the message </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We will be placing details of the latest and greatest applications using our API here. Be sure to check this page regularly as new ideas are developed.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Which is also the same as 3 years ago, shortly after the API’s first release. Good work Lovefilm.</p>

<p>Remembering this, I walked away thinking, “Oh, well”, before going back to my workday. Explaining it to my wife, I realised there was another route to achieve what I wanted, which is what you see on the web now. Ultimately, this is nothing more than a bunch of regular expressions.</p>

<p>Admittedly, I’m aware there’s changes at Lovefilm – they’ve been entirely bought out by Amazon and I can imagine the new owners would want to integrate the company with their brand better. It seems as if they’ve already switched off new developer registrations, so I’d imagine the whole API will be turned off before long.</p>

<p>On the flip, take a look at where I want to take my data to – <a href="http://letterboxd.com">Letterboxd</a>. A site focused on film lovers and it shows. They’ve taken the route of paid pro accounts, which provide access to the <a href="http://letterboxd.com/about/importing-data/">import tools</a> I mentioned earlier. The majority of users won’t make use of this though; they just want to support a site providing a great service which is open and honest. They’re also planning on providing a full API, which I’ll be interested in playing with on release. As a result, I’m sure Letterboxd users will get a bunch of new toys they can use their accounts with that external developers decide to create.</p>

<p>The best thing though? They’re real people who talk to me. After letting them know about my little hack, I got thanks that same day from <a href="http://letterbox.com/about/crew">Matthew</a> of the Letterboxd crew, with a <a href="http://feedback.letterboxd.com/forums/136771-general/suggestions/2360263-add-lovefilm-imports">ticket closure</a> shortly thereafter. That beats 3 years of waiting.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>Participate, Don’t Preach</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-don%e2%80%99t-preach</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2011-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2011/07/14/participate-don%e2%80%99t-preach</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>Last week, tickets went on sale for dConstruct 2011 and sold out within an impressive 7 hours. Having attended in 2010 and 2008 and judging it to be filled with the highest calibre web celebs from across the globe, I coughed up the entrance fee as part of the excited gold-rush. The cost of £150 includes access to the pre and after parties and the conference itself.</p>

<p>These type of events are stuffed to the brim with amazing, intelligent web professionals, many of whom I would consider to be colleagues. I’ve followed their progress, listened to them speak, bought their publications and hacked on code with them at many other previous events.</p>

<p>It’s often quoted within tech circles that the best parts of these events are not the talks themselves, but the networking parties that surround them. I really struggle in these environments, nervously trying to find a crowd I feel comfortable chatting with, introducing myself and trying to strike up some cutting edge debate on the topics of the day. I’m a developer who usually lurks behind a computer screen for 8 hours a day, so why wouldn’t I find it awkward? It feels like uncharted territory every time I find myself there. Although meeting some great, interesting people, I have ultimately never forged any new lasting relations in this way, where the interaction is somewhat forced and artificial. Maybe it’s just me, but given the com mon nature of everyones work, you’d think it might be easier. As a friend once observed – it’s like everyone turns up to sell their product, but there are no buyers.</p>

<p>It’s also great to be able to chat within the inner circle of the celebrities who attend. You’ve heard from them all year round and now have a brief opportunity to chat. I guess really I’d love to bounce questions and thoughts off of these guys all evening, but often I get the feeling I’m being evaluated against the rest of the attendees in the room in terms of worthiness. Until you’re edging<br />
into such circles yourself, I’m not entirely sure what they would get from these conversations either.</p>

<p>In fact, what I have found is that my most fruitful and long lasting relations have been founded at events when in a participatory nature. Most of these have been Hack Days (where you’re invited to quickly hack together software as an exemplar of new apis from a number of vendors) and some of them have been at Bar Camps (where all attendees have to speak on a subject close to their heart). I feel closer to these people than I could ever do with someone I spoke with briefly in a noisy bar. I’ll also remember faces and names of people even if I never had the chance to interact with them.</p>

<p>This year, a new variety of geek meet has arisen, which flip these more traditional events on their heads and instead focus on providing environments that focus on “the best bits”. They allow everyone to participate on level pegging rather than follow a traditional conference structure. Earlier this month there was &lt;a href=“http://geekkart.in”&gt;Geek Karting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=“http://insitestour.com”&gt;The Insites Tour&lt;/a&gt; is kicking off next week and later this year there’s &lt;a href=“http://preparetoactivate.com”&gt;Activate&lt;/a&gt;. I really like the idea of these as a way of sparking interesting relationships and I’m hopefully going to head to Insites next week to see what Elliot and Keir have been able to cook up. I’d hope to see more of these unusual types of event and ultimately participate in more of them.</p>

<p>I still feel that conferences have their place, otherwise I wouldn’t have coughed up the fee for dConstruct. I enjoy hearing what these illustrious speakers have to say. That part of the event is still important for sparking debate and learning from for months and years afterward. However, I just don’t find surrounding parties as valuable to me as I first would have thought.</p>

		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
	  <item>
        <title>How not to: Do A Hack Day</title>
        <link>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day</link>
		<author>I.M.Wootten<</author>
		<pubDate>2010-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
		<guid>http://ianwootten.co.uk/2010/07/24/how-not-to-do-a-hack-day</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
		   <p>It’s been well over a month since I attended <a href="http://sciencehackday.com">science hack day</a> and I’d thought I’d put out some notes on my time there. Rather than do a run down of the event, for which I’m sure there’s far more comprehensive blog posts available already, I thought I’d share my experiences based on attendance of a number of different hack events I’ve been to over the years. I went with the full intention of doing some hardcore hacking, but didn’t entirely meet my own expectations. Here’s my top tips, for now not to do a hack day:</p>

<ul>
  <li>1: Don’t bother coming prepared – You’ve got 24 hours, and you’re bound to be the best coder at the event. You’ll have a unique idea and get that app finished in no time! No, far better to kick back and relax before setting on your way and conduct your research on what’s possible when you arrive.</li>
  <li>2: Arrive fashionably late – 24 hours is ages, and you know all the apis that presentations are going to cover. Nothing says “I’m superior” more than waltzing in a couple of hours late to the event whilst everyone else has been busy sweating it out already.</li>
  <li>3: Keep your distance from other attendees – Your idea is your own and you’ll want to claim all the glory for it after the event. Where’s the glory in letting people know you’re one of 10 people involved? Keep your app under wraps before that all important presentation at the end, the audience will be in total awe of you and flock to your side afterwards.</li>
  <li>4: Be sure to leave the event – You enjoy your sleep right? Why lose it by camping out on some office floor space, when you can head home to your comfy bed or to a hotel and return in the morning? This way, you also get to avoid all that small talk with big name, high profile coders who will belittle you with their outstanding knowledge of their own companies apis.</li>
  <li>5: Have your fill of the free refreshments – Free beer and pizza? Wow, these are a must for any late night software development project. There’s nothing better than feeling stuffed full of dominos and slightly rosy whilst trying to get your brain working at full throttle.</li>
  <li>6: Don’t prepare for your presentation – You’ll need every last second for building your app and the presentation is only a minute long. You might as well just attempt something of the cuff. Don’t worry about connections to your laptop, because those things always work and organisers like <a href="http://adactio.com/">adactio</a> are most amicable about trying to organise it for you along with 30 others at the same time.</li>
</ul>

<p>I attended <a href="http://sciencehackday.com">Science Hack Day</a> and collaborated with a <a href="http://openobjects.blogspot.com">Mia</a>, <a href="http://dharmafly.com">Prem</a>, <a href="http://tommorris.org/blog/">Tom Morris</a>, <a href="http://yaili.com/">Inayaili de León</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/goodonpaper">Andy McMillan</a> and Richard Boulton in order to build an app titled <a href="http://dharmafly.com/scihack">“The Revolutionaries”</a>. Both Inayaili and Andy I never even spoke to and it was only through Prem’s organisation that the app came through in the end. I spent 2 hours of the event commuting to and from the guardian’s offices and 1 more stuck in a stationary tunnel in the dark. I’m glad that a made an effort though as the <a href="http://dharmafly.com/revolutionaries/">net result was a great app</a>, which even won a little prize. I probably won’t be heeding much of the above advice at future events.</p>


		]]></description>
	  </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>