<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2006/01 on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/</link><description>Recent content in 2006/01 on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We are 100</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/30/we-are-100/</guid><description>This post is the official 100th post on this site! Wow, how exciting. I know that it’s marked up as #127, but these are of the ones that actually made it public here. The first one made it up back in August 03 and was rather boring. That makes an average blog per month rating of 3.4….Yeah, thats lame too. So, what can I talk about to make it all profound now?</description></item><item><title>Live in the Moment</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/19/live-in-the-moment/</guid><description>For Christmas, one of my gifts was an ace calendar providing helpful hints on worst case scenarios for each day of 2006. Todays one made me smile quite a lot – “How to survive psychological torture”. The second part of it however sounds more applicable to everyday life, work, relationships etc rather than actual torture (except for the horrors part).
Here’s the advice:
Do not worry about what comes next.</description></item><item><title>Life Goes On</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/14/life-goes-on/</guid><description>On the dawning of a new year, life continues much the same as it has done previously, I have lots of work to do, lots of pointless things to do and lots of people who want me to fix their computers because they heard I know a little about those sorts of things. On my quest to rid the world of all t-shirts by stocking up on them myself, I’d quite like to pick up this t-shirt to reflect how I sometimes feel about this.</description></item><item><title>A New Year</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2006/01/05/a-new-year/</guid><description>I’ve not spoken in a long time on here and it seems I’m getting harassed into doing so, so I thought I’d air some stuff.
It’s the New Year! Woohoo! Christmas brought with it all the usual stuff, like parents moaning about computers and arguing about nothing. This year I only crept back for a very short time in which to see family and catch up. It seems like Yeovil is less and less like my home now, with friends moving away and all.</description></item></channel></rss>