<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>til on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/til/</link><description>Recent content in til on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:13:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Module Extras with Pipenv and Poetry</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:13:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/04/07/installing-module-extras-with-pipenv-and-poetry/</guid><description>I thought it worth documenting how to install &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; dependencies in Pipenv and Poetry after struggling to find the answer myself. Context: I hit a problem with uvicorn where the websockets module hadn&amp;rsquo;t been installed as a result of not including the &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; extras. Rather than return an error, it just failed to connect the websocket which made me think something was wrong with my network configuration.
As an example, take the following pip command:</description></item><item><title>Comparing VAT Solutions for Bootstrapped UK Businesses</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 11:32:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2021/02/23/comparing-vat-solutions-for-bootstrapped-uk-businesses/</guid><description>Laws on when to apply VAT have always been a complex beast - in 2015 the EU made changes that meant that VAT was to be calculated based on a customer location, introducing a VATMOSS system for its collection. Since leaving the EU things have become even more complicated if you happen to be based in the UK. You now are no longer able to make use of the VATMOSS system, meaning you potentially need to register for VAT in every EU country you sell products to (!</description></item></channel></rss>