<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2005/11 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2005/11 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing...</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/29/introducing.../</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend back at home in recognition of my parents 30th wedding anniversary. It&amp;#8217;s quite bizarre looking through their wedding photos (I&amp;#8217;d never seen them before) and picking out all my relatives in mini form. Said previous ladyfriend decided she&amp;#8217;d brave the border as well to make those &amp;#8220;all important&amp;#8221; first introductions. She might of thought better of it if she knew parentals were going to bring their saturday night party back to ours and keep everyone awake until the early hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oblivious</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/17/oblivious/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;#8217;m a little less than perceptive of situations in which I&amp;#8217;m involved. Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve been clued in to a number of things which makes me think I&amp;#8217;ve been carrying freeriding on this life while I could of been part of something so much more interesting. This isn&amp;#8217;t a direct attack on anyone but myself, so don&amp;#8217;t anyone take it to heart. I think this is best shown through the forming of a type of relationship I&amp;#8217;ve been starved of for the best part of my life, one with my lovely new girlfriend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alarm Bells</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/10/alarm-bells/</guid>
      <description>Some of the thoughts in this post over at Barbara&amp;#8217;s really hit home with me today. I don&amp;#8217;t often take time to reflect on pointers like these but the majority of them are ringing alarm bells about some aspect of my life at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/08/positive-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>From a sample upon the dischandler (DJ Moneyshot):
&amp;#8220;No one wants to be a failure, no one wants a life constantly filled with worry, fear and frustration. Therefore you must remember to reap that which you sow. If you sow negative thoughts, your life will be filled with negative things. If you sow positive thoughts, your life will be cheerful, successful and positive.&amp;#8221;
Not so sure how this pads out in real life&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMuppets</title>
      <link>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2005/11/03/emuppets/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;#8217;ve had not a lot of response to my situation with ebuyer of late, but this recent email I recieved from them sent me over the edge &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;d sent them 7 emails and phoned 2 times with a 40 min wait prior to recieving this.
&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-
Microsoft OEM Windows XP Professional x64 Edition &amp;#8211; 1Pk
Dear Sir / Madam,
Thank you for informing us of your missing item. When we are believed to have short shipped an</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>