<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web Development Stack in 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2018/11/07/my-web-development-stack-in-2018/</guid>
      <description>Over my time as a web developer, I’ve jumped between many frameworks and languages, attempting to find ones that work well for me. This seems to be pretty typical for developers who always have a take on the latest trend, either to quickly adopt or criticise it.
I really wanted to be a member of the Ruby crew for a time and ended up buying multiple copies of “Agile Web Development with Rails”, before having the opportunity to really apply it to a project and disposing of them because the material was outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Generated Forms with WTForms</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2017/04/18/user-generated-forms-with-wtforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2017/04/18/user-generated-forms-with-wtforms/</guid>
      <description>As part of my past work with the Office for National Statistics (ONS), I worked with the survey runner team to add additional features to their Electronic Questionnaire which enabled the business to take regular surveys electronically via the web. During my final months there, I took it upon myself to tackle what was seen to be one of the projects major pieces of technical debt, its use of a custom form renderer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Camera RAWs with OpenImageIO and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/09/15/processing-camera-raws-with-openimageio-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/09/15/processing-camera-raws-with-openimageio-and-python/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered the library OpenImageIO, an awesome tool for reading and writing image files. What makes this of particular interest is the sheer variety of image files supported (BMP, Cineon, JPG, JPG-2000, GIF, DPX, OpenEXR, Targa, TIFF) (as well as variety of camera raw formats) and the fact it can perform image transformations upon them very easily. Given it&amp;rsquo;s designed for use in media and VFX environments it sounds like it will be useful for the type of work I&amp;rsquo;ve previously been involved with in stop motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Shot Thumbnails from a video using FFMPEG</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/31/extracting-shot-thumbnails-from-a-video-using-ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2014/07/31/extracting-shot-thumbnails-from-a-video-using-ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Andy Davies asked the following question on twitter:
Any ideas on how I can easily convert a video to a filmstrip?
&amp;mdash; Andy Davies (@AndyDavies) July 23, 2014 
I found this pretty interesting, especially given I&amp;rsquo;d used various open source tools for assembling storyboards in the past. I knew it was possible to extract images at desired intervals and left it as that.
After a bit of digging last night, I discovered it&amp;rsquo;s actually possible to extract images based on changes in the video.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>