<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on Ian Wootten</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on Ian Wootten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:58:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Create AWS Lambda Layers for Python Dependencies</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:58:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/01/27/how-to-create-aws-lambda-layers-for-python-dependencies/</guid><description>Using AWS Lambda for your serverless Python app can give significant cost and management benefits. However, unless your needs are simple you will quickly need to bundle your dependencies along with your functions. Doing so with an AWS Lambda Layer works much like installing dependencies within a local environment. You are able to reduce each functions size, maintain your core code separately and simply tell the function to use the layer when setting it up.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Associates WordPress Plugin v0.2</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2009/10/25/amazon-associates-wordpress-plugin-v0.2/</guid><description>I’ve just updated my amazon associates plugin to take into account the recent signiture changes which amazon have introduced for their webservices api.
This now also means you’ll have to enter your amazon secret access key in the plugin configuration page.
You can download the updated version over here.
It also means my wishlist has finally been brought back to life. Just in time for Christmas…</description></item><item><title>Amazon Associates WordPress Wishlist Plugin</title><link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2008/04/02/amazon-associates-wordpress-wishlist-plugin/</guid><description>One of the things that’s bugged me for a while whilst having a website is that at certain times of the year when people might actually like to buy me a gift they’re unable to find my wishlist. This is mainly because they’re simple folk who might not think to check amazon for my name. I’m also signed up with amazon associates, so I decided it could do me well to post my wishlist items along with my referral tag in the links in order to earn a bob or two on my own homepage.</description></item></channel></rss>