<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003 on Ian Wootten</title>
    <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003 on Ian Wootten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project - again...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project---again.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/12/13/project---again.../</guid>
      <description>After having been working like theres no tomorrow on other coursework, I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to come back to my project work.
I&amp;#8217;ve really not got very much productive work done on it aside from a few class diagrams and workflow routines which I&amp;#8217;ve put together. I have been working on a prototype over the last month however in order to have that side of things produced on time. Currently it doesn&amp;#8217;t do a lot more than add or delete users and needs to come a lot further before its something impressive which is worthy to be shown to my supervisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Knackered...</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/11/28/absolutely-knackered.../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been totally caning it over the last week or so&amp;#8230;. I&amp;#8217;ve got this Opengl graphics project due in very soon, and I&amp;#8217;ve been working like a bit of a bandit on it. On the other side of the coin, I&amp;#8217;ve got a databases piece due in on the same day which I haven&amp;#8217;t made a start on yet. Guess I&amp;#8217;ll be doing that over the weekend. Those will be in next week and then I&amp;#8217;ll have some time to get moving on my project again&amp;#8230;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh deary me..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/28/oh-deary-me../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to make some headway on my cms project today in order to get ahead and not end up in the same situation as I had in the second year. Seeing as I have a distinct lack of all things coursework related at the mo, I thought that would be a diamond idea. Unfortunately my knowledge of what now goes into a project is somewhat sparse, and I&amp;#8217;m finding it a right job knowing where to tackle first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And so it begins..</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/and-so-it-begins../</guid>
      <description>Used today (yesterday, actually) to take a look over the various things that can be done when using XML and XLST together. All in all it seems very impressive, and can hugely alter the way which a document may first be formatted. This may be a valid reason to choose this method over more standard CSS techniques, which generally just alter bog standard settings like color, font-size &amp;#8230;.
On a side note, I also managed to get an NT install of CVS sorted and working nicely on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He ain&#39;t Heavy</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/he-aint-heavy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/22/he-aint-heavy/</guid>
      <description>Having just installed the latest version of wordpress over b2 (thus ruining said previous mood plugin) I now have a working image upload abilities! Just to give you an idea of what goes on up in Cardiff, have a look at this pic of me and my long lost brother.
 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moody</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/09/moody/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/09/moody/</guid>
      <description>Just messing about with a new mood plugin I&amp;#8217;ve put up here..
Would be cool to let you guys know how I&amp;#8217;m feeling right now..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woe is me</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/06/woe-is-me/</guid>
      <description>Oh dear, today has not been good&amp;#8230;
After missing Church this morning, I proceeded to backup most of my hard disk onto my old ATA100 so that I could revert my main ATA150 partition back to a &amp;#8220;simple&amp;#8221; partition, so I *might * be able to install Linux.
After spending the best part of the afternoon backing up, I proceeded to download a partition tool to manage my partitions if Linux couldn&amp;#8217;t handle it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back with a vengeance</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/10/03/back-with-a-vengeance/</guid>
      <description>After having my account removed (presumably because I should&amp;#8217;ve theoretically graduated by now), making the move up to Cardiff, having my account reinstated and finally finding out that the web hosting had changed servers, with the mysql databases remaining on the same server (meaning that I had to change the &amp;#8220;99% of the time you won&amp;#8217;t need to change this&amp;#8221; value) I am now able to have b2 back up and running smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Joys</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/31/upgrade-joys/</guid>
      <description>In a bid to pummel my friends workmates at a bit of LAN gaming yesterday, I took the initiative and upgraded my computer this week. Placed an order on Monday, ordering just the CPU fan from a different store &amp;#8211; which proved to be a bad idea, it still hasn&amp;#8217;t turned up yet! &amp;#8211; preventing me from installing the CPU on my new motherboard&amp;#8230;..Tut Tut ebuyer..
All well, its nice to have shedloads of space on my machine now, even if I don&amp;#8217;t have any real need for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Rummaging</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/19/random-rummaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/19/random-rummaging/</guid>
      <description>Allow me to breathe a sigh of relief&amp;#8230;I&amp;#8217;ve just spent most of the last hour sorting out what&amp;#8217;s rubbish from most of the paper lying about my room, whilst searching for my student support details. I did find them, could of been a messy first few weeks back at Uni if I hadn&amp;#8217;t!
I also found a mates wedding invitation and list, reminding me that I actually have to reply to say that I&amp;#8217;m attending, and buy them a present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All change</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/all-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/all-change/</guid>
      <description>Due to MT being incompatible with my Uni server from an imaging point of view, and the fact that its all coded in Perl &amp;#8211; which I haven&amp;#8217;t bothered looking at for a hell of a long time, I&amp;#8217;ve ditched it and shifted my blog over to b2. Now I can actually post images! Woohoo! b2 is nice and tiny also, a mere 527Kb compared to MT&amp;#8217;s 3Mb.
I&amp;#8217;m actually toying with the idea of developing a blogging tool as a final year project, I think that might be very rewarding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Fun</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/17/family-fun/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve just got back from my Churches &amp;#8220;family fun&amp;#8221; event. They have been doing a whole bunch of different events this week as an opportunity to witness to those who might not normally come to YCC otherwise. Today was the big finale of the week and was basically all the families who had been a part of the week meeting up with the members of the Church.
What that amounts to is lots of barbeques and little kiddies events galore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Install</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/blog-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/blog-install/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;#8217;ve installed Movable Type on my website. I figured it was about time that I get up to speed on this whole &amp;#8220;Blogging&amp;#8221; thing, but I could of even missed the bus already.
I&amp;#8217;ve spent half of the evening just looking at what can be done with MT, and it seems to integrate well with Invision Board as the MT crew have an example of a forum set up with it on their site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonic Flux</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/sonic-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/sonic-flux/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m pondering whether or not it might be a good idea to upgrade Ben&amp;#8217;s Sonicflux site to use MT. I don&amp;#8217;t think that over the last year much has been done to update his site, (well I know it hasn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8211; I&amp;#8217;ve been maintaining it, bad idea) and I&amp;#8217;m sure he&amp;#8217;d make use of it. He sends out regular updates via email to let everyone know whats going on, I&amp;#8217;m sure I could get MT to send regular email updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>netpbm woes</title>
      <link>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/netpbm-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2003/08/14/netpbm-woes/</guid>
      <description>Right, Sonic Flux didn&amp;#8217;t happen. Went to Martins instead to sort out a new monitor to replace his dying old one.
I&amp;#8217;m having a right job trying to get the image side of MT working. I want to post images from my t610 on here, but it seems somethings afoot as when trying to submit thumbnails I get a lovely page of hex! Ah well&amp;#8230;Maybe MT wasn&amp;#8217;t such a good move&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>